So earlier this year,
Lori and I and my parents
had this awesome trip to Cuba.
Oh, that Cuban trip,
I wanna go back so bad.
Yeah. We just got back, and she
already wants to go back.
But anyhow, we ate
at these awesome restaurants.
We had fantastic dishes.
But there's one place
that she didn't get to go
where they made an old-school
dish she's gotta try.
I know she'll love it.
So I figured,
let's do it on "Big Bite,"
starting off
with my chicken Kiev.
We've got crispy, fried ground
chicken filled with a dill
and smoked paprika
compound butter.
It's crispy
on the outside, juicy
and literally
flavor-packed inside.
To cut through
all that richness,
how about a zucchini
and fennel noodle salad
tossed in a bright lemon
vinaigrette with pecorino cheese
and crispy prosciutto.
And to wash it all down,
I'm shakin' up
a Blackberry Mule with vodka,
lime and ginger beer
that might just go down
a little too easy.
Let's talk about, uh, making
the stuffing for the Kiev.
Now, uh, Kiev is
actually a French dish.
Sounds very, uh,
sounds Russian to me.
For some reason,
I always thought it was Russian.
I think the French stole it.
And then the Russians
took it back.
Is that what it is?
Well, we tried it
at a Soviet restaurant in Cuba.
And I'm not kiddin' you.
This place was legit.
And I've never seen
Kiev done this way.
I always thought it was
the chicken breast stuffed...
-Pounded.
-Pounded out a little bit,
then breaded, then fried.
Well, this right here,
we're gonna be grinding
our own chicken.
We're in for a blast.
Trust me.
Um, you're good with that.
Can I get about
a quarter cup of, uh,
the Pepper Jack cheese?
Okay, so we'll start with
some butter, a lotta butter.
We're gonna take this butter,
mix it with these ingredients.
We got dill.
Yeah. Right in there.
Throw a little bit
of smashed garlic.
There we go.
So the Pepper Jack cheese,
the butter,
little bit of garlic.
That's a lotta garlic.
That's not a lotta garlic.
It's just a little bit.
Who ever comments about
too much garlic in their --
-Yes, it is.
-Huh?
Who doesn't like garlic?
You didn't just say that.
All right.
Little cream cheese.
But you listen.
So we go to Cuba.
And it was really
just at the beginning
when people were having
the opportunity to go to Cuba.
Lori and my mom
and dad flew in ahead of me.
I was coming in from Texas.
And they get there.
They had a real tough time,
well, not a real tough time.
But they had an interesting time
coming through customs.
Me, I just breezed
right through.
But, boy, was it a blast
or what?
Oh, yeah.
But your father, I thought
they were gonna lock him up.
Well, they probably
should lock him up.
Anyways, uh,
so some cream cheese.
-Don't help.
-Oh, okay.
Just stand over
there and watch me.
-Want a back scratch?
-No. Mom, come on.
Would you chop up
a little bit of parsley?
I gotta kinda pulse this
a little bit, get this started.
Okay. So this is
gonna be the stuffing.
Now, believe it or not,
we're gonna take this stuffing
and freeze it before
we put it into the, uh,
before we put it
into the chicken.
This always happens when
I put cream cheese in there.
Okay. So wad that down in.
So yeah.
We go -- we get there.
We were there for about 5 days.
We did it all.
We toured all
throughout Havana.
Then, we went
outside of Havana,
went to a Cuban cigar factory.
That was outrageous.
Just really nice people,
really cool cars.
I didn't believe that the car
thing was true, did you?
No.
That they were actually gonna be
drivin' those cars around?
And if you saw a car that wasn't
an old car, you stared at it.
But the old cars
were everywhere.
So after a while,
it was no big deal.
Yeah. It wasn't.
Go ahead and drop it in, Mom.
Okay. Little smoked paprika.
There we go.
Little salt and pepper.
And I'm just fighting to
get this to start to work.
If you can let the cream cheese
sit out a bit or the butter,
go ahead and, uh, and do it.
It won't make it so tough
to get this to mix up.
All right.
Give it one more try.
-I've done this before.
-I know.
I know it's not appearing --
Nothing worse than have your mom
watching over your shoulder.
"Uh, real good.
Great job on the show, Guy."
Okay. Here we go.
The compound butter --
Well, we should call it
compound butter plus.
Had the butter.
Had cream cheese.
It had, uh, uh,
the Pepper Jack cheese,
little smoked paprika,
had some garlic,
little parsley,
a little salt and pepper.
And to round it out,
which this place was known for,
Okay. So what we'll do,
take a little bit
of this compound butter.
Lay it right here in the center.
We're gonna freeze this, Mom.
We're gonna freeze it
real tight. Okay?
We're gonna freeze it so,
when we drop it inside,
we're gonna get some ground
chicken here in just a second.
But we'll freeze this so tight
that, when we drop it in there,
it's almost gonna be like
a butter-cream cheese Popsicle.
Okay?
Lay that down.
Want me to wrap that?
No. I got it.
Why? Just 'cause I couldn't
use my own mixer,
you think that, now, that's
the way everything's gonna be?
Roll that over.
Here we go.
Give it a little spin.
There we go. Okay.
And the key to this is, drop --
gotta drop it in the freezer.
Okay?
Right down here in the freezer.
Out comes the chicken.
So what I did here, Mom,
you got breasts and thighs.
Cubed them up,
threw 'em in the freezer
and just put a little bit
of a freeze on 'em.
You know like when you're trying
to slice something really thin?
-If it's a tiny bit frozen...
-Right.
...it just works
a little bit easier.
Would you grab me that other
carafe right there
for the food processor?
Right there.
So you could get
ground chicken.
But if by chance you can't,
and you wanna make this dish,
this is the way to do it.
You put a little bit extra --
you put a little bit
extra time into it.
Cut it up.
Freeze it a little bit.
And we'll be able
to process it through here.
So --
Is this better
than buying ground?
Well, here's the thing
you know is you know exactly
what your ratio's gonna be.
Uh-huh.
So here we've got equal parts
of breast and thigh
or maybe two-thirds,
one-third.
Don't overload it.
Pop it like that.
Sometimes, it's
a little too frozen.
So if you have
to let it sit out
in a little room temperature,
just kinda pulse it.
Let's take a look at that.
So you see what you get?
Uh-huh.
Nice little --
nice, ground up.
You know, how much
fat you have in there,
how much breast,
how much thigh.
Yeah. It looks good.
Fantastic. Okay.
So we take that out.
We knock it over.
And we continue the process.
You ready?
Yep.
Okay, good, 'cause I gotta go
check some e-mail.
- Okay.
-No?
-Yeah, sure.
-I'll take care of it.
All right.
So this gets dropped in. Okay.
Well, let's do this.
We'll put this together.
When you come back,
we're making chicken Kiev.
Got a fantastic cocktail.
And one of my mom's
favorite vegetables,
the zucchini,
will be coming into play.
We'll see you in a little bit.
Welcome back.
"Guy's Big Bite."
Uh, cooking here in the, uh,
at the ranch kitchen
with my mom.
What are you looking for?
Don't worry about it.
Go ahead.
"Don't worry about it."
You see how we've got
the stations swapped
'cause I'm over here
workin' with the mandoline.
But this is gonna be some, uh,
dynamite zucchini strips
for this salad.
It's gonna get a little
prosciutto into it.
My mom is, uh, setting up
the dredging station over there.
How are we doing, Penelope?
Doing great.
Let me just get this.
-These our eggs?
-Uh, yeah.
Our eggs.
We have, uh, organic chickens.
So our garden,
what happens is, you know,
sometimes, you don't
get out there.
And the tomato was fine
yesterday. Then you come out.
Now, it's laying out
on the ground
and it's a little bit mushy.
Well, we take those,
throw 'em over the, uh,
throw 'em over the fence
to the chickens.
And the chickens get to eat 'em.
And I wanna talk --
you wanna talk about
beautiful organic eggs.
I've talked about it before.
I don't know if you know
the story about Ryder.
So one time,
we didn't have chick--
we didn't have eggs.
We came back from a trip.
And none of the eggs
were waiting for us.
And, uh, so we got some
organic eggs at the store
and made 'em for Ryder.
And, uh, Ryder looks
at 'em and says,
"I'm not eatin' those.
Something's wrong with 'em."
'Cause they were just
a beautiful yellow.
They weren't that
big golden...
-Right.
-That orange.
Uh, it was crazy. Okay.
Um, so my mom's
workin' that.
Whisk that together, please.
And we really wanna have
that super eggy
'cause this is gonna be
a really tight batter
that's gonna go around
this ground chicken.
We did the ground
chicken ourselves.
We have our whisk. Okay.
We did the, uh, we did the, uh,
ground chicken ourselves.
You can't always find
ground chicken in the store.
But if you get
equal parts of breast
and thigh or your mixture
that you like,
and you take that,
I'll tell you something.
Just freeze it up
a little bit.
Throw it into
a food processor.
And you're good to go.
Hi, Roxy.
Wanna help?
All right.
So a little fennel,
a little zucchini.
Okay, Mom.
Let me ask you a question
while I'm doing this,
while I'm -- while
I'm daring my fingers.
Okay.
Uh, favorite thing
about Cuba, what --
besides the fact
that I took you?
Oh. Oh, I'd say it's the night
that you went to bed at 9:00,
and I went out till 3:00.
I can't believe you just
told everybody that.
That is so ridiculous.
I did not go to bed at 9:00.
It was 9:30.
I went to Cuba for the music.
It was -- it was 9:30, Mom.
So, yeah. So I, you know,
listen, I'm working.
I got things going on.
We're over there shooting
a, uh, a special
for "Triple D"
and for, uh,
the Travel Channel.
So I'm doing
my responsible part.
She's goin' out.
They don't start the music
in Cuba till what time?
It started at midnight,
but it was really 1:00
because the time changed.
You all set up? Okay.
I'm all ready.
Little salt on this is gonna
bring out some of the moisture.
We're gonna be making a salad
outta this in a little bit.
I'll set this aside.
Let me get a pan hot here.
I've got a little prosciutto
that I'm just gonna crisp up.
This is gonna be kinda the, uh,
the garnish or the little bit
of the crouton
for this fantastic salad
with the fennel
and the zucchini.
Mom, you ready
to do this over there?
Let me just fold this over.
I love prosciutto
when it's crispy.
There's just a salty
nuttiness about it.
And it's always worth it,
getting really good prosciutto.
Okay. We'll drop this --
Actually, Mom, do me a favor.
-Uh-huh?
-Little olive oil right there,
the first one in front of you,
that bottle,
just so it
doesn't stick too much.
How do you know if it's
really good prosciutto?
There you go.
All right. I'm sorry?
How do you know if it's
really good prosciutto?
The price or...
Well, sadly enough, by price.
But really, uh,
you're looking for,
uh, imported
prosciutto from Italy.
You're also looking at the,
uh, how long it was aged.
They age prosciutto.
Okay.
Let this go.
Let's get into this.
This is where things
are gonna get dicey.
Uh, outta the freezer,
pulling out
our log of butter.
Now this is the one
that we took and mixed
with the cream cheese,
the butter, the dill.
The dill is what really
makes the dish come together.
-Did it freeze?
-Yeah.
-Oh, wow.
-Oh, yeah. It's frozen hard.
And the reason it is, Mom,
you'll see this here
in a second,
is I want it frozen so
when we start to cook it,
it doesn't start to leak out
all this great flavor
right off the bat.
-Right.
-Okay?
About that size.
And you're gonna have
to follow along here
'cause this gets real --
-Okay.
Real quick real fast.
Okay?
So ground chicken,
thighs and breast,
cut it in half.
Just so I don't use
too much of one...
Right.
I found this method. I do this
a lot when I'm doing burgers.
Okay. So then I got four
equal portions.
Okay.
Okay?
Yep.
So now, pick it up
with my hand.
Gonna kinda compact it
together a little bit.
Make a little bit
of a canoe.
-Okay? Nice and firm.
-Okay.
Drop that inside.
Okay? Wrap it around.
I'm gonna steal
a little bit of this.
You're gonna end up
with three.
Well, it might be three.
But listen.
As big and as bodacious
and delicious as these are --
And I've also got
some more frozen chicken.
So I can knock that out.
But the idea
is just to make sure
that it's evenly coated.
Okay? So we got --
-Like pigs in a blanket.
-It's -- yeah.
Just weird --
just with raw --
You wanna stir that for me?
Okay.
Okay. Now, the wet chicken
is gonna pick up
a little bit of
the seasoned flour.
Uh-huh.
Actually, that's probably
gone enough, Mom.
You can just
pull it off the heat.
So a little bit of
the seasoned flour sticks
to the wet chicken.
You're doing the rest of these.
You better be paying attention.
I am.
Okay?
Then we go into
the egg wash,
egg wash into
the Italian bread crumb.
And this is
a really thick batter
that we're putting together.
So we'll go from the Italian
bread crumb back into this,
back into the egg wash again.
Why do you do two bread crumbs?
So it really creates
a coating on it
so when it starts to cook --
'Cause we're gonna pan-fry it,
then finish it in the oven.
And this will keep it from --
this will really
create a barrier
so the cheese doesn't explode.
But why two kinds
of bread crumbs?
Those are a little bit
thinner.
These are a little
bit crunchier.
We're explaining it all. See?
We're learning at home.
We're spreading
attention together.
See you in a little bit.
She's gonna get started
on these right now.
I've done one. And I'm done.
Go ahead, Mom.
Jump in. Grab it.
Welcome back. Special day.
My mom's on "Big Bite."
So you know that, uh,
not a lot is getting done.
And there's more laughing --
Oh, hey.
How'd I do?
Uh, you did --
I'm actually really impressed.
How was your e-mails?
My e-mails were good.
While I was doin' all the work.
Thank you.
I have important things
I'm dealing with.
I don't know what those
important things were.
Okay. Fantastic.
So what we did here
is we made this
ground chicken ourselves.
And my mom, very diligently,
by the way, uh,
took this compound butter
that's got a little,
uh, cream cheese
and Pepper Jack
and, uh, paprika,
mixed it all together,
put it inside frozen,
wrapped the chicken around
it and then dredged it.
And we're talkin'
heavy dredge, okay?
-We're talkin', uh, flour.
-Flour.
Then went to the egg,
then went to
the Italian bread crumb,
then went back to the egg,
then went to the panko.
So oil is right
about 350, Mom.
-Okay.
-Go ahead.
Here's a spoon.
Lay that on the spoon.
And just gently
drop those in.
-Okay.
-And you're good to go.
On the -- While she's
workin' on that,
I've got some, uh, zucchini
and some fennel
that I, uh,
salted in the back.
I'm gonna rinse that off
in a bit to make
this really nice salad
that's gonna go along with it.
You see, when you
put it in there,
how it just comes up
about halfway?
Yeah. Yeah.
We'll fry both of these.
There you go.
Don't put it too close to it.
Okay.
Okay? The idea is not
to really mess with them
because you're starting
to set up the crust now.
It's kind of in
a very tender moment.
Um, once it starts
to build its crust,
tse in the oven.
It's kind of in
a very tender moment.
Okay.
Um, you can go ahead
and pluck some of those
fronds for me.
-Okay.
-I just need some of the fronds.
This is gonna go for
the dressing for the salad.
Typically, the Kiev
is served with noodles.
So this is my California version
of serving it with noodles.
You know,
when you take zucchini,
and you slice it thin
on the mandoline,
add a little fennel to it,
made a little dressing,
olive oil,
some garlic, some salt,
some pepper
and the fennel fronds
and a little bit of lemon zest
and lemon juice.
Took some prosciutto,
sliced it thin,
threw it in a pan
and crisped that up.
Combine it all together
and then top it off
with a little shaved pecorino,
nice and salty.
Ah, a raw salad like this
with such flavor and texture,
perfect for the Kiev.
Okay. Dressing's done.
There we go.
Now, want a cocktail,
Mother?
I know I don't need
to ask you that.
-Of course.
-Okay.
-Of course --
-Let's talk about --
Have you ever had a Moscow Mule?
Yep.
Okay. So this isn't the idea
of the Moscow Mule.
But we're gonna use,
in this Moscow Mule --
Let me grab this here.
-Grab all my goodies.
-Lazy man's load.
-You need some help?
-No.
This is not
a lazy man's load.
- Except I forgot one thing.
-Good.
All right.
So the Moscow Mule,
there's a lotta theories
about this.
One -- The real, true theory
is it didn't come from Moscow.
Two -- Moscow Mules
have that kick.
They say the kick comes
from that ginger beer.
So what I'm gonna do is drop
in some beautiful blackberries.
These are too big.
They didn't come from our ranch.
Our berry bushes are tiny.
And the deer eat 'em
all the time.
So these we got
from the market.
Um, we'll get, uh...
That has garlic on it.
-That'll taste good.
-Little garlic and some lime.
That's how they got the coffee
in the -- in the lobster.
Yeah, it was,
the coffee in lobster.
So we go to this place
called El Figaro.
And, uh, it's in a place
called Barbershops Alley.
-And they made a lobster...
-Yeah.
...that was done with
with an espresso sauce,
outrageous.
Am I gonna put these on here?
Yeah. Go ahead and swap
those out, Mom.
Perfect. All right.
So let me get in here
and muddle this,
few ice cubes
just to help build.
There we go.
So the Moscow Mule,
they say that it --
they call it the Mule because
it's got the ginger beer kick.
So you're talkin' about
vodka and ginger beer
and a little bit of lime.
So what we're doin' here
is adding in the blackberries.
Still got the lime.
And we are gonna hit it
with a little ginger beer.
But look at that,
nice little muddle there.
-You work quick.
-Oh.
I gotta stay on --
I gotta stay on my toes.
-Keep goin'.
-Oh. So these...
You got it. Yeah.
-All right.
-Okay.
The drinks in Cuba,
that was interesting.
I went and made the,
uh, had the daiquiris
at, uh, Hemingway's
place where he --
where his -- his, uh, haunt.
Did you guys
make it by there?
We went to one bar he went,
but not that one.
Well, you could've gone
to any bar in Havana.
I think he might've gone to.
That's true.
Okay. Little bit --
The one we went to,
the only picture I saw of Castro
in the whole place in Havana,
the whole city,
was with, uh, Hemingway
and Castro in this bar.
-And, uh...
-Really?
Yeah. It was a great place.
We went to the place
that makes the daiquiris.
And I'm telling you,
the daiquiris were outrageous.
I mean, I didn't think,
you know,
what could be so special
about the daiq--
- Whoa.
-Huh?
See? I caught it.
Okay, Mom.
Right in the fridge right there,
if you wouldn't mind grabbing,
top drawer, should be
a couple ginger beers.
Okay.
So pour that
right over the top.
Get some of the muddled
berries in there.
I just probably need one.
Is this beer real --
really beer?
Yeah.
Okay. Ale, yeah.
Okay. Gonna do that.
What? Lucky you
didn't hit your --
Part of the --
It's part of the trick, Mom.
I'm just tryin' to do
a little show for ya.
Okay? So we pour the ginger beer
right over the top of it.
There we go. So...
Nice.
I'm wearing half the meal,
hangin' out with my mom,
talking about Cuba,
having a cocktail,
cooking outdoors at the ranch.
It doesn't get any better,
well, until we start
eating all this.
See you in a little bit.
Cheers.
Welcome back.
Chicken Kiev, chicken Kiev
like you probably
haven't seen it before.
This is a little tribute
to my, uh, trip
that I took to Cuba
with Lori and my parents
and making chicken Kiev
with ground chicken.
We made this compound butter
with a little cheese,
stuffed it in there, outrageous.
And a salad.
So you're working
on the pecorino.
Yep.
Would you mind,
uh, just dicing up
a little bit of the chive?
-So...
-Okay.
What we've got here --
What we've got here is
a little fennel, some zucchini.
And my mom is drinking
the Moscow Mule.
Mom, you're quiet.
Did you get tied up
in Moscow Mule, or...
I'm concentrating on my job.
You're doing
a very nice job.
So we made a Moscow Mule,
but we put blackberries into it.
So you take the traditional Mule
that everybody loves
with the ginger beer.
Well, we did that, uh,
a little bit of the lime
and the vodka,
topped off with the ginger beer.
It's fantastic.
Where's yours, by the way?
Is this yours or mine?
Yeah. That's mine.
This is yours.
All right.
Oh, I should know that's yours.
There's more missing.
Mm.
Those aren't blackberries
from the ranch.
But I would like to take
all the credit in the world.
-They're fantastic.
-Mm.
Made a little vinaigrette
right here from, uh,
the fronds of the fennel,
some garlic, some lemon juice,
salt and pepper,
a little olive oil.
Stack that up.
Hit it with a little salt.
Do you know
that about the throwing
the salt on the veggies,
how it kinda makes 'em
a little bit --
pulls out some of
the moisture...
Uh-huh.
...and kinda gives them
a little bit --
makes them a little
more toothsome.
Okay. So, you know,
typically, on a Kiev,
which is actually
a French dish,
but the Kiev typically has,
like, a butter noodle with it.
Well, we changed it up a bit.
Chives go in here, or there?
Yeah. Right on the top of that.
And then, also, I've got
a little prosciutto that
Chives go in here, or there?
l just throw
Yon top of this,he top of that.
nice little salty crunch.
Wow.
And then hit some of that --
Is that gorgeous or what?
It's so --
And then take some
of the pecorino
and drop that over the top.
Okay.
All right.
Eenie, meenie, miney, mo.
Here's one.
Wow.
There's mine.
Why is my mouth
watering already?
Oh, it's fantastic,
beautiful dish.
-Is that good?
-Okay.
Little bit of the zucchini
and the fennel.
Come on over, Mom.
Grab one of these.
Yum.
The whole inspiration
for this dish...
Nice.
...was that this is what she
missed when we were in Cuba.
We were out there
shooting "Triple D,"
doing all types
of adventures.
She and my dad
were gone one day.
They didn't make it
to this restaurant.
We had this chicken Kiev.
I thought it was outrageous.
So I said, "Why not make it?"
So let's dig in.
Thank you.
There you go.
All right.
I hope I did it right.
I'm gonna cut it in the middle,
see what happens.
Oh, my God.
There you go.
Look at that juice.
So what you get is you get
that Pepper Jack cheese...
Wow.
...the butter...
Look at this.
Or the Pepper Jack cheese,
the dill and the parsley
all coming out.
It's amazing.
We double-battered it,
so it really locked
in all of the, uh...
Oh.
Is that awesome?
That's fantastic.
It really locked
in all that flavor.
So as it was cooking, normally,
you'd see cheese kind of
coming out a little bit.
The veggie noodles, huh?
Zucchini can play
well with others.
And the fennel,
thin real --
sliced really thin,
hit with that acid.
Oh, that's good.
But that Kiev,
tell me that
doesn't make the list.
It's awesome.
Good job.
That's my mom. Huh?
Doesn't get any better
than this,
hangin' out in the backyard
at the ranch, cookin' it up,
drinkin' a little
Blackberry Mule with this girl.
See you next week, "Big Bite."
Good job, Mom.
-Thank you.
-You did great. Look at these.
-They stayed together.
-It was fun. Yeah.