Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Poof!
...we're digging
into mega meats...
I like it juicy.
...and some sweet treats...
Today,
the cinnamon roll anaconda.
...like Holy Moly Stromboli
in Washington...
You've got to
be kidding me.
...an Asian-Mexican mash-up
in Atlanta...
That's a jam band
right there, dude.
...and prime-time pastrami
in Austin.
Ho-ho!
Plus, along the way,
pastries that will
boggle your mind.
I have always said,
"If it's funky, I'll find it."
You might be getting
the freaky-funky award.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Yeah!
So, we're here on the southwest
side of Austin, Texas.
Now, a "Triple D" statement
that we always make is,
"Don't judge a book
by its cover."
But what happens when
you're going to a place
and the name, it says pizza,
but they're known
for awesome pastries,
amazing bread,
and killer pastrami?
Well, we're about to find out,
'cause this is Pieous.
House on Fire
and a margherita.
You would think
it's a pizza place
or maybe a bakery,
but it's so much more.
One pastrami chili,
fixings on the side.
I just feel like
it's a gem.
Megan is a producer for us
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
One of my favorite chefs, you
really know a ton about food.
I think what's going on here
is high-end, chef-driven food.
From two people who didn't
actually start out as chefs.
We worked in the music business,
but we didn't like what we did.
Did you become lawyers
and accountants?
Yes.      Yes.
Okay.
We talked about doing
a restaurant forever.
Finally, Josh
and Paige Kaner went for it
and started serving up
the food they love.
You make the pizza.
You're baking bread.
You're doing pastrami.
Juicy pastrami sandwich,
table 20.
Their pastrami is
in a world of their own.
The sourdough bread is awesome.
It's art in itself.
The pastrami that I hear
is to die for,
give me the rundown,
brother.
We have to cure it for 20 days
before we smoke it.
Most people are happy
with seven.
So...
We're gonna
build our brine --
kosher salt, curing salts,
a little bit of hot water.
We're gonna dump
a bunch of water.
To cool it down.
Cover this.
Pureed garlic.
That much garlic.
Onion.
For one brisket?
Yeah.
Black peppercorn.
Put it in the deep cooler.
20 days later,
we're gonna make our rub.
Got it.
Black pepper, paprika,
garlic, coriander.
This is gonna get
rubbed on here liberally.
Let it sit
for about a half-hour
for the juices to kind of
come out and grab the seasoning.
How long on the smoker?
10 to 13 hours,
depending on the size.
Depending on the size?
You do the feel?
Yep.
We're gonna make
sourdough bread dough.
So you just set this thing
right here and hit start,
and that is gonna deliver me
the exact amount of water
every single time
so my sourdough bread
is as consistent as possible.
Nice to meet you.
I'm leaving.
This is ridiculous.
Isn't that cool?
This is
our sourdough starter.
Gorgeous.
This is 20 years old.
It just wafts the air.
And we're gonna add
high-gluten, organic flour.
You know
what's really terrible
is that a dude
from the music business
is chefing this
to the ninth degree.
Give it a good mix, salt it,
proof this for like six hours,
put it in the cooler
for another 24 hours...
Okay, to really let
that flavor build?
...before we take it --
Yes.
And then start
to make the bread?
Yes, sir.
I love it.
We're gonna make
a pastrami sandwich.
I like it juicy.
Make it a-nice.
Ho-ho!
Look at the bark on that.
Sourdough,
whole-grain mustard.
Oh, so you're going full-on
Katz's Deli with this.
Let you be the judge.
Couple kosher pickles,
house-pickled onions.
That onion's
nice little kiss.
Delicious bark.
It's got the right pepper,
got a touch of coriander.
Not over-salty,
which is always the curse.
You got this thin bread,
and it's not coming apart
as you shove it
in your facehole.
The pièce de résistance is,
without question,
the pickled onion,
which cleanses the palate.
That's a badge of honor
right there, buddy.
I'll take three of those
to go.
The pastrami will
knock your socks off.
Reminds me of New York, where
there's more meat than bread.
Homemade sourdough bread
is just another level.
And the mustard just adds
enough of that tang.
When my friends come in
from out of town, I tell them,
"Hey, I'm gonna take you to get
some life-changing pastrami
and some good pizza."
I got the Fat Queen going in.
They got this incredible oven
they imported from Italy.
I got a margherita.
Everything is scratch-made.
It's just the level of detail
in every layer of every dish.
And when it comes
to their desserts,
they take those layers
literally.
We're gonna laminate this thing
how many times?
81 layers.
81 layers?
Now that's how you do
a caramel roll!
Caramel roll's going to table 4.
Even if we're not even hungry
for dessert anymore,
we can't leave here
without ordering this.
And that's when we come back.
Shut the front door, back door,
side door.
Shut all the doors.
Go, hut!
Get it!
There ya go!
All right, I got to go to work.
Welcome back.
Hanging out in Austin, Texas,
at Pieous.
You see the name and you think
they make a bunch of pie.
They do.
Neapolitan pizza -- fantastic.
But the story goes
even deeper than that.
You don't just come
for the pizza.
Sometimes we come
just for the desserts,
because the desserts
are amazing.
Caramel roll going to 10.
The caramel roll's delicious.
That croissant-like crisp
outside, gooey inside.
It's like genius-level pastry.
Did you ever see the show
when Hunter and I
went through Europe
and we were in France
and we made the croissant?
Stretch it here,
and you roll it.
But if you didn't watch
that episode, tune in now.
We're now making
croissant dough.
81 layers.
81 layers?
Start with the sourdough
starter, high-gluten flour.
Sugar, milk.
Diastatic malt powder.
Got it.
This is gonna give it
a good flavor and good color.
Okay.
Butter and water.
My mouth
just started to water.
Let it relax.
Add the salt.
And we're gonna run it
for about five minutes.
Okay, where we at?
Caramel sauce.
We're gonna start with butter,
the brown sugar, little water,
little bit of corn syrup,
heavy cream,
pinch of salt,
vanilla bean paste.
Okay, so we're gonna
let this cook down.
Now let's start
the lamination.
This is
our croissant dough.
Cold and hard
like butter.
Speaking of butter.
Oh, no, that's not
gonna happen right now.
We have some butter,
right in the middle.
Fold it over.
Now we're gonna put it
through the sheeter.
You want to try it?
'Course I do.
Okay, good.
Now drop it down to 16.
Okay.
You think I can count.
Ah, this is so my job.
Until you don't pay attention
and it goes off the edge
and falls on the floor.
Whoa!
It's like Lucy and Ethel.
So now we got to make this
look pretty.
I did a-nice.
Right in    the middle of the fold?
Yep.
Three more times
of this again?
Same way.
Back in the...cooler
Cooler. For at least an hour.
-Two more runs.
-Yep.
Then roll it up
on the pin.
I mean, this is like
"Caramel Rolls Gone Wild."
We're gonna start with cinnamon,
brown sugar, Texas pecans.
Roll this into a log.
Were you this good
of an accountant?
No.
So, I want this edge
to stick to this edge.
Got it.
So I'm gonna kind of dock it
a little bit,
kind of bring out that butter,
and then it will attach.
You're licking the envelope
right there, buddy.
Welcome to
the Flavortown Zoo.
Today, the cinnamon roll
anaconda.
Then we've got to mark it
so we know where to cut it.
Next up,
we have the caramel.
Oh, great caramel.
Add some more pecans
to the bottom.
-And stick them in.
-Okay.
This exceeds what
I've seen before.
This is not even close
to being done.
Of course.
We have to
proof this now.
He's not for real,
ladies and gentlemen.
I'm being punked.
So, now they're out
of the oven.
-Got it.
-Do a flip.
You want to get
a good release.
That's sugar napalm.
It's gonna hurt.
Unh, ow!
Wow!
Delicious.
Nice little bit of salt.
Great vanilla.
Sugar-to-cinnamon balance,
fantastic.
Flakiness of the dough --
I mean, just like all the levels
of righteousness.
One of the most unique,
delicate pastries that I've had.
That right there is what
every cinnamon roll wants to be.
That's crazy.
Here's the caramel roll.
I dig right
to the middle.
You got to have that crunchy
part of it, and it's so good.
It's so sweet.
The nuts on the top
just really set it off.
Pastrami chili.
I never leave here with food
because we wind up
eating it all.
That's how good it is.
I'm really impressed.
You took that discipline
and responsibility
of being an accountant,
and you can taste it.
Everything that I'm seeing
you do is of the next level.
Well done, Chef.
It's delicious.
Thank you, Guy.
Wrap up my cinnamon rolls
and get me my pastrami,
'cause I'm out of here.
Up next, a joint in
Atlanta taking Korean flavor...
I'll have more of that
every day.
...mixing in Mexican...
Hold on.
...and tossing in
an American touch.
I mean,
this is powerhouse, bro.
So I'm here in the
West Midtown area of Atlanta
to, well, not check out
a joint for soul food.
No, I'm here to check out
a joint that's doing tacos.
Well, and they're not
really even tacos.
They're doing Korean food.
Well, it's not even Korean.
It's more like Korean tacos.
I know this is a mouthful,
but you got to check it out.
This is Hankook Taqueria.
Tongdak taco, shrimp taco.
It's hard to believe
that I've found a restaurant
that I can't go a week
without eating at.
The food is that good.
-Bulgogi kimchi fries?
-Yeah.
It's Mexican-Korean fusion,
and I've never heard of that
before I came here
the first time.
And that mash-up
comes from husband-and-wife team
Tomas and Mackenzie Lee.
"Hankook" actually means
"Korean" in Korean.
So, what we're doing is
taking authentic Korean food
and using the vessels
of Mexican food.
You're just funkifying
the flavors.
-Absolutely.
-Got it.
Tongdak taco.
The tongdak's the best.
The fried chicken's delicious.
Lightly breaded with a good
sauce on there, bunch of flavor.
All right, so what are we
going to make today?
Tongdak fried chicken tacos.
"Tongdak" means
Korean fried chicken.
-Speak Korean?
-No, I don't speak Korean.
-Does your wife speak Korean?
-She does.
She has a Southern
Korean accent.
South Georgia
Accent.
Awesome!
We're gonna make our vinaigrette
to start with.
Soy sauce,
white vinegar, sugar,
Korean chili flakes,
pure sesame oil.
I'll have more of that
every day.
This is the salad
that goes on the taco?
Yes, sir, and then we also
add onions and then cilantro.
That's delicious.
Next step, we're gonna
make the marinade
for the chicken tenders.
The tenders tend to...
Be more tender?
We'll add our buttermilk,
salt/pepper mix.
So, let these marinate
overnight,
then what are we gonna
batter them in?
All-purpose flour,
rice flour.
-For the crunchification?
-Right.
Cornstarch, garlic powder,
onion powder, salt/pepper mix.
Let's fry some chicken.
All right.
Here's our warm tortillas,
tongdak fried chicken,
chipotle aioli.
Soy sesame salad on top,
Jack cheese.
Not Mexican or Korean.
We're American, because we just
put cheese on the taco.
That's what
the people want.
I'm in such a weird paradox
right now.
Coming to the South,
having fried chicken, got it.
Having a taco in Atlanta,
not quite sure.
But then when you throw in
this Korean thing
and then spin it all around
and throw some cheese on top
of it, it's delicious.
Great crunch from the chicken,
super-tender chicken.
You get a really nice, good hit
from the chipotle,
but the finishing note
of that salad.
You're really picking up
this sesame oil.
The only thing really Mexican
going on here
is the chipotle
and the tortilla.
After that, Elvis has
left the building.
That's right.
But when it comes
to flavor,
I mean, that's a jam band
right there, dude.
Fried-chicken taco?
I love the mash-up --
the Southern chicken,
and I love the cheese
on top.
These ladies are
some friends of mine
from northern California,
and they raised a bunch of money
to help out some seniors
displaced from
the terrible fires that we had.
What do you think of this combo
of Korean and Mexican?
-Hella good.
Kimchi fries.
Tomas is a great guy
and a fabulous chef.
But it's easy to see
that his wife, Mackenzie,
is the one
really running the show.
How's he doing?
We don't know why he doesn't
speak more Korean.
My dad asked him the same
question when he first met him.
He was very firm about how
things go in this relationship.
And he said, "I wear the pants
in the family."
That's right, but I get to
pick it out in the morning.
And?
Those are not the ones
that I chose.
Can you explain to me how you
would say the bulgogi dish
in -- in full Korean?
Like "prr-gogi."
How do you say "fries"?
Fries.
There's no "prr"
in the front of it?
Almost French.
And together,
they make a killer combo.
The bulgogi kimchi fries are
almost like a Korean poutine.
The Mexican queso cheese
and the kimchi
just gives it a nice kick.
You say kimchi,
my mouth waters.
It's like Pavlov
and the dog.
We'll take Napa cabbage,
natural sea salt.
Pull all the moisture
out of it.
That's gonna go for 24 hours
like this?
Absolutely.
We have our
rice flour slurry,
Korean chili flakes,
chopped garlic, salted shrimp.
And that's what
gives it the funk.
Right.
Then our ginger juice.
Grated ginger that you
squeeze out the --
Yeah.
Toasted sesame seeds,
carrots, green onions.
Then this will go
for another 24 hours?
Correct.
Rub-a-dub-dub,
we got kimchi in the tub.
We're gonna marinate
the sliced rib eye.
Soy sauce.
I like to use pineapple juice.
It helps to break down
the proteins.
Okay.
Sugar, sesame oil,
garlic, onions.
Then we'll take
our sliced rib eye.
Marinates 24 hours, then
we'll put the fries together.
Absolutely.
We're gonna season them first
with sesame oil.
In a squirt bottle.
I've never seen that in my life,
by the way.
And then we have
our seasoned salt.
Which is salt and a little bit
of Korean chili flake.
Korean chili flakes.
Absolutely.
Okay.
Now that our meats
are marinated,
add a little bit
more sesame oil
and then
fresh kimchi inside.
-And this all comes together?
-Right.
Queso sauce.
Hold on.
The kimchi and the fries
is enough,
and now we're putting
cheese sauce on top of it?
Queso, that's it.
Which is just American cheese,
heavy cream and?
Half-and-half.
Drizzle gochujang, scallions,
and there you go.
My friend, you've got
a lot of issues.
I know.
That's what my wife says.
Mmm.
It's legit.
Fries are
the perfect medium.
Crunchy,
take sauce on well.
But then
you bring mega flavor.
Oh.
There is nothing more potent
than kimchi, gochujang on top,
and a little bulgogi
to go side by side with it.
Thank goodness
the queso is there,
'cause it kind of
balances it out.
I mean,
this is powerhouse, bro.
Thank you.
Pick up kimchi fries,
please.
A little bit sweet,
a little bit spicy.
The bulgogi's
real bulgogi.
No "foolgogi."
This thing's like 20 pounds.
I only eat it when
I'm really hungry.
Have you been to this place
here in Atlanta?
No, but I'll come back.
-Without question?
-Wonderful.
He's better than a good cook.
I'd say he's the real deal.
Chef, when it comes
to making delicious food
and putting
cultures together
and keeping it right on the line
of interesting and unique,
you've crushed it.
Congratulations.
Thank you. Appreciate it.
Coming up
in Richland, Washington...
It's fun.
...a cannoli/stromboli spot...
What goes on in here
is a flavor bomb.
...where the food's...
You ever seen "Twilight Zone,"
the pizza edition?
...almost as crazy as the chef.
Good or bad, I will never,
ever let you forget me.
I guarantee it.
All right son,
we're in Richland, Washington.
And you are gonna love
this place.
Where are we going?
Okay, husband and wife
are married for four years,
divorced for 23,
got back together,
and they got a restaurant
where they're not interested
in making a profit.
They're just
really interested
in giving the guests
a positive experience.
-What do you mean?
-I don't know, Hunter.
We'll have to find out
for ourselves.
This is
The Folded Pizza Pie.
Behind you,
Holy Moly's in the oven.
We eat here at least
three times a week.
The food is amazing.
It's fresh.
Legacy calzone in the window.
It's the greatest calzone
you can ever get.
And it's one of the stars
of Dale and Taryn Leikam's
second act,
'cause their retirement plan
meant going all in
at this joint.
-Why do two normal people --
-We're not normal.
I apologize.
I didn't mean to offend anybody
with that one.
Get into
the restaurant business
after they've got
these great careers going?
We're not in it
to make any money.
Our focus
is on the people.
You ever seen "Twilight Zone,"
the pizza edition?
There you go!
It's a world where
nothing's flat, only folded.
The Folded Pie, it's a pizza
that he just rolls up
into a calzone shape
or a stromboli shape.
Holy Moly for Carrie.
The Holy Moly Stromboli,
they pack it
full of seven different meats,
and it's absolutely delicious.
We're making this gigantic
Holy Moly Stromboli?
We're gonna start
with out dough --
4 cups of water,
salt, sugar, olive oil.
Parmesan cheese.
Italian seasonings.
I've never seen pizza dough
made like this.
That's what makes our calzones,
strombolis stand out.
Flour, bloomed yeast.
Get a nice big old blob.
-That's the culinary term?
-That's our term, yeah.
-Blob?
-The Folded Pizza Pie blob.
-What are we up to now, Captain?
-Chicken meatballs.
So we start with 60/40
dark meat/white meat mix.
Whoa, you get after it
with the Italian seasoning.
Garlic powder, onion powder,
salt and pepper,
minced garlic, Cajun seasoning,
and then our bread crumbs.
-Got it.
-Roll them out.
Roast in the oven,
what temp?
625 degrees.
Really?
That hot?
When you get that chicken fat
coming out of there,
it's time to pull them.
Okay, we're gonna do our
oven-roasted chicken.
All right, boss.
Add some balsamic vinegar,
dried minced garlic,
onion powder, garlic powder,
nutmeg, cinnamon,
Italian seasoning.
Italian seasoning?
No?
-Yeah!
-You?
Salt and pepper.
Marinate it for 24 hours.
Yep.
Throw it in the oven.
What temp?
625 degrees.
625 degrees again?
That's how we roll.
We know it's done when you
start smelling the cinnamon.
We don't time it.
We just wait till
we smell the cinnamon.
So now we're going to make
the Holy Moly Stromboli.
So this super-herb-laden,
Parmesan cheese dough.
Yep.
Italian-seasoned dough.
You really don't care
that a lot of your methods
and styles are unorthodox.
It's my place.
Genoa salami.
Don't you know-a.
Spicy sausage.
You want to try some?
Oh, no. Who, us?
Bacon, the meatballs
we just made,
the oven-roasted chicken,
pepperoni.
And Canadian bacon.
You've got to
be kidding me.
We have mozzarella, Fontina,
Asiago, Parmesan,
Romano, cheddar, and Gouda.
Now we roll it up,
brush it with olive oil,
dust it with Parmesan cheese,
and throw it in the oven.
-At 625.
-625.
Holy Moly Stromboli.
Would you
look at that?
Put a little sauce
on there.
Dip it, pour it on,
whatever you like.
I'll tell you what
it's not lacking.
-Flavor.
What goes on in here
is a flavor bomb.
Lots of herbs.
The texture of the bread
and the flavor of the bread
is fantastic.
You get
this cracker crunch.
It's dense,
and it's rich.
I mean, it is not in any way,
shape, or form
what most people expect.
But it's really good.
Thanks.
Holy Moly Stromboli.
It's huge.
It's got a really good
seasoning.
What makes it is the crust.
It's the reason people come.
Well, Dale helps
with that, too.
Driving by,
he's standing outside.
He's like, "Come eat."
He was
flagging you down?
You just can't keep up with him.
Number-one rule's you get to eat
with your elbows on the table.
He's always making you feel more
comfortable, like you're family.
And family dinner here
includes a little dessert.
Apple Doughboy.
The Apple Doughboy
is really good.
It's got the fresh apples
with the cinnamon.
The special sauce on the top,
it's delicious.
Apple Doughboys.
This was my wife's invention.
Granny Smith apples from
the great state of Washington.
-I have never seen that.
-Seriously?
-You've never seen one of these?
-Nope.
-You want one in your stocking?
-I do.
-Yeah, please.
-Slinky, Slinky.
So, some roux
and some butter.
Put these apples in.
Cinnamon and the nutmeg.
-No measuring?
-No.
-Brown sugar.
-Where is this going?
We make dessert dough.
It's just your basic
dough recipe
with no cheese,
no seasoning.
We didn't let it proof.
We just threw it right
in the oven so it poofs.
How's it do it?
Poofs.
How do you
spell "poof"?
P-o-o-f-f-f...
-Nice. Poof!
-Poof!
This is the apple filling
that we made earlier.
Little bit of butter,
the cinnamon-sugar mix.
Ooh!
625 for -- Hunter, guess.
10 minutes.
12 minutes.
-Yes.
-12 minutes!
What does this
get served with?
We make our own
cinnamon drizzle.
We use hard cinnamon candy
in a hot pot.
Soda water.
Now, the longer you cook it,
the more it reduces.
You want me to hang
my clothes up there?
No,
keep your clothes on.
Oh!
It's fun.
Apple Doughboys.
Locally made
vanilla bean ice cream.
So, then we're gonna pour
this cinnamon syrup
candy stuff on it?
Yep.
Bon appétit.
I have always said it
on "Triple D."
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
This is funky.
You might be getting
the freaky-funky award.
The Doughboy is good.
That is delicious.
The glaze is awesome.
Bro, you are on a whole
different planet.
Thank you.
Apple Doughboy up!
Fresh apples, the cinnamon --
incredible.
Very flaky texture to it.
And that secret sauce
just takes it over the top.
Cinnamon glaze on my ice cream.
Folded Pizza Pie's
like a second home for us.
Dale's just a mad scientist
back there.
In closing, this is what
I tell my guests.
You're wrapping
the show up?
Good or bad, I will never,
ever let you forget me.
That is a fact.
I guarantee it.
-Thank you.
-And good night.
Poof!
Pbht!
Oh, interception!
So that's it for this trip
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
but don't you worry.
These young chefs
will be taking over.
I'll see you next week
on "Triple D."
Just like-a your mama.
Where's your papa, hey?
Do not listen
to the crazy person.
You can listen to me.
I'm only around for
another 10 or 15 minutes.