♪♪
Welcome to "Big Bite."
You know, here in this backyard,
in this kitchen, I have hosted
some of the probably most
outrageous game day feasts.
I mean, I've done it all.
I've done the nachos.
I've done the tacos.
I've done the burgers.
About anything in the world
that you could ever
imagine to barbecue,
I have done right here.
But one of the number-one
requests, you know what it is?
Chili.
And not any regular chili.
We're talking Texas-style.
No tomatoes, no beans,
real deal Texas-style chili,
and that's what I'm gonna
give you today.
My Texas-style chili is packed
with ground beef, cubed beef,
dried chilies, fresh chilies,
onions, garlic, cumin and more.
And it's served with, get this,
a beer cheddar cheese sauce.
Oh, yeah. This is the one
that's guaranteed to score
some major points.
Get it?
Game day points.
All right.
On the side, how about
some elevated potato skins?
I'm upping the game
on this game day classic
with leeks, mushrooms,
brie cheese and prosciutto.
And you can bet those are gonna
fly off the plate.
In fact, you might want
to make a double batch.
All right.
Let's get started.
Dutch oven going hot.
Onions busted down.
A little bit of garlic
into my peppers.
So listen.
You're gonna
find your favorite peppers
that you like to work with.
This chili
is not outrageously hot.
So it doesn't mean that you
have to go with the big heat.
But we're gonna
use some Anaheims right here.
Okay.
And we got a bunch
a bunch of dry chilies that
we're gonna bust into as well.
Now, I'm gonna cut 'em
down into a pretty usable size.
Actually, let me go ahead and
drop some of these now 'cause
it's gonna take some time
to sweat 'em.
So a little bit of olive oil.
We'll get down
with the onions right now.
And this is, just like I said,
no beans, no tomatoes.
And that's what's funny.
Because when you give people
chili like this,
they're like, "Hey, I think
you're missing something.
This kind of looks
like a meat sauce."
Well, you got to remember --
chili con carne.
Meat and pepper.
Okay.
Drop those down.
A great way
to break this chili down --
split 'em,
take the seeds, not a lot
of membrane inside of here.
That...just the key
is just to make sure
we got some uniform sizes.
There we go.
Some red bell.
Okay.
Drop those in.
Look at that.
Just sweating up nice.
This Fresno chili here,
I'm not too worried
about the heat on it.
Pretty mild.
So I'll just give it
a couple slices down the front.
And I won't add that garlic yet
because I don't want it to burn.
And I got a lot of heat
going in this right now.
So far, so good, huh?
Okay.
Let this continue to sweat down.
Add a little bit of salt to it.
Let's get into dry chilies.
Now, this is really
the foundation of this chili.
So what we're first starting off
is with some Chile de arbol,
which is nice and spicy.
The ancho and Guajillo chile,
which, to me,
is my favorite dry chili.
And so the ancho's deep
and rich.
The Guajillo's got
a nice little spice and kick.
And, of course,
the Chile de arbol
has definitely got the heat.
So taking those,
charring 'em is the beginning
of this dish.
And, believe it or not, the red
color that's gonna come out
is gonna be outrageous.
So these will sit here
and toast.
Get a little more heat on that.
There we go.
Let me get this stuff
in the compost.
And let's talk about potatoes.
So a lot of people
show up for game day feast.
And they're expecting the --
the regular old fare.
We're gonna
do some potato skins.
Oh, but we're gonna fill 'em
with brie and prosciutto.
Just got to knock it--
you just can't let 'em know
what's coming.
Got to give 'em a little
surprise.
So here is some beautiful
baked Russet potatoes.
So what I'm gonna do.
There's a key
of where I want to slice these.
Okay.
If I slice 'em like this,
then I'm gonna
get these really flat boats.
What I want to do
is slice 'em on the flat.
Okay.
Like so.
Take 'em on the flat like this,
carve into them,
leaving about a 1/4 inch --
leaving about a 1/4 inch
of the flesh around there
so they don't become too thin.
Because what's gonna happen is,
after I take all this flesh
out of them,
let them cool down a bit.
Then I'm gonna deep fry 'em.
What do you think of that?
♪♪
All right.
And the last one.
Now, these potatoes
are still a little bit warm,
so I'm gonna
let 'em cool down here a bit.
And you got to save
those potato innards.
I mean,
you're talking potato pancakes.
You got all kinds
of options there.
All right.
So let me do this first.
Um, the Guaji...
The -- the peppers over here
have really toasted up nice.
I don't want 'em to burn.
So now, I'm gonna reconstitute
'em with just a little bit
of hot water.
Okay.
I'm gonna
do it right there in that pan.
That is a hot pan.
Little more water.
And we'll just let those kind
of hang out for a second.
And those are gonna go directly
into the chili in just a minute.
Speaking of the chili,
I need to get those peppers
and onions out of there
because now I have got
some top round
that I want to brown off.
And we're talking about --
I don't want it
to be interrupted.
I really want to build
some crust,
kind of like we're searing
a short rib.
So what I want to do
is get all these out
'cause you leave just a little
bit of this in there,
there's a lot of moisture.
It will keep it from --
It'll keep the meat
from really browning up.
It's just chasing these around
inside of here.
There we go.
Okay.
Over here.
Let that continue to stay hot.
We'll go over here.
There's ground beef.
But right now, the roast.
Now, this is a great thing.
We're talking about stew meat
right here.
We're talk-- Look at that.
Look how beautiful.
Huh?
So we'll just hit it
with a little --
a little touch of some salt.
And we'll just drop it --
Crank that pan back up.
Right back in.
There we go.
Nice little sear gonna
happen to that.
Now, I also
have some ground beef
that I'll put in
in a little bit.
I like to have
two of the textures.
This is gonna
be really nice and chewy.
It's got some real,
great steak-feel to it.
But it will be super tender.
And then, that ground beef.
Well, that just kind of works
its way around all the peppers
and all that sauce
that's gonna be happening.
Okay.
We'll let that brown up.
Now, the skins.
What's gonna happen with these?
Well, what I'm gonna do is I got
a little bit of the texture,
little bit of potato
left on the inside.
Drop 'em in at about 350.
And here's the beauty
with these.
We're gonna stuff 'em.
Oh, yeah.
So, I want you to think about
a gigantic hollow french fry
that we're gonna jam
some prosciutto in,
some brie, some mushrooms.
I mean, the list goes on and on.
So let me put these down.
You guys come back.
We'll continue
to work on the chili.
We got so many
big flavors going on.
And this is
all for that big game day feast.
See you in a bit.
So it's game day feast
here at the Fieri house,
in the backyard.
And yes, game day
and leeks do go hand-in-hand.
I've got some leeks
that I'm gonna be sautéing,
here in a second,
with some cremini mushrooms.
But, uh, I'll show you
this little leek technique.
Remember when the leek grows,
it's growing up like this.
So the opportunity for sand
and dirt and everything
to fall down into those crevices
is really,
uh, is really, uh, happening.
So what we want to do
is I cut mine.
Makes it a little
bit easier to clean.
And then, I'll just give 'em
a quick little chop,
drop 'em into the water.
I can swirl 'em around
with my hand
and just kind of wash
'em like that,
or rinse 'em, I should say.
Some people leave the rounds
together, but what I find is
that if they -- the rounds don't
get completely broken apart,
you have a chance
of getting yourself some sand
and some dirt into it.
So this is all gonna come
together.
Well, I'll just do it
with my hand.
This is all gonna come together
for a fantastic
stuffed potato skin.
And, actually, I've got to drop
some of the potato skins.
So let me let this settle
down here for a second.
Some baked potatoes just left
with about a 1/4 inch, uh,
interior right there.
Salted them
before I roasted 'em.
And we'll drop 'em
in 350-degree oil.
And yes,
I want these to almost get
like a hollowed-out french fry.
Okay.
Almost potato chip-like
because we're gonna be throwing
in some brie cheese, prosciutto,
and some mushrooms and all that.
And speaking of which,
I need to get
my leeks going here in a second.
So couple tablespoons of butter.
And I'm just gonna
shake the leeks off.
Drop 'em in the butter.
And I have some ground beef
going over here
with some 1-inch cubes of chuck.
And I cooked those in the oil
that I had just sweated
some peppers and onions in.
And in we'll go with the leeks.
And then, over there, also,
I have some steeped peppers
that I kind of toasted off a bit
to get nice and,
uh, well, nice and rustic
because we're making
Texas-style chili.
No beans and no --
and no tomatoes.
Okay.
Drop these in.
Set this aside.
Creminis, my favorite.
I'm telling you,
one of my favorite mushrooms.
I can't say
it's absolutely my favorite,
but it definitely is one
of the best.
Really nice and meaty.
Lots of really defined
mushroom flavor.
And we're gonna cook
these down with these leeks.
It'll work out perfectly.
♪♪
All right.
That's enough.
Okay.
Bring it right over.
Drop these in.
And you know
what this needs here?
Is just a little touch of thyme.
I got some fresh thyme
standing by.
That's all gonna cook
down together.
Throw a little more heat on it.
And all the thyme
comes out together.
And just the leaves
of the thyme.
Okay.
I know this seems
a little bit more refined than
you're thinking game day food.
But, you know,
when you say potato skin
and then you say, "But I'm
stuffing it with mushrooms,
and brie and prosciutto," you
can get away with it.
All right.
Now, back over here.
Let's take a look at this.
The meat looks great, getting
a nice little brown to it.
That's what I was trying
to achieve with that is
just get a little crust on it.
Okay.
What does it need?
Well, it needs a little bit
of this garlic.
I held out on the garlic
till the last moment
because I didn't want
it to burn.
And I got to get
these peppers in.
Let's get over to these peppers.
Ow, hot handle.
And I want that liquid and all.
So I have these reconstituted
Guajillos,
Chile de arbol and anchos.
Okay.
Hit that.
Little bit of power.
Puree it.
There we go.
We'll dump this right in here
on with the meat,
in with that garlic
that I just added.
That's where your real
flavor's coming from.
So you look at this and you
go, "Well, it's red like chili,
but there's no tomato in it?"
Nope.
No tomato.
There we go.
Let me drop this in.
Sweated peppers and onions
that we had from earlier.
And that all gets mixed
together.
Look at that.
Look -- Just --
I mean, take a look inside this.
Now...
Now it's time to go build
another layer of seasoning.
So I've done some salt
and pepper.
Got the peppers and the garlic.
Now we'll do a touch
of Cayenne.
A little oregano.
A little bit of cumin.
Got to have a little kiss
of cinnamon.
Not too much of it.
Just a touch.
Now, this all gets mixed
together
and really gonna
build a big base flavor.
But I've got to get some liquid
in here
to help cook down that meat.
So we'll get in here.
2 quarts of beef stock.
We're gonna let this go in here.
It's gonna cook down, believe it
or not, for two hours.
So I've got my creminis
and my leeks getting ready to go
for my stuffed potato skins.
And my potato skins
are just finishing up now.
Here's chili.
Cheese sauce coming up.
It's game day feast.
And this is exactly
how I like to do it.
See you in a little bit.
Welcome back to "Big Bite."
Oh, man, I'm telling you,
it's all coming together,
finally.
Yes, I'm browning the butter.
That's what you expect to find
on a game day feast
at the Fieri house.
Now, I'm actually making
some roux because I'm gonna
make some beer cheddar
cheese sauce for my chili.
So, just a little bit of flour
to go with that butter.
Make a quick little roux.
Basically, equal parts.
Let's see where that gets us.
There we go.
Toast it off.
There you are.
What do you have back here
in this cauldron of fun?
Well, you've got
some Texas-style chili.
All that beautiful red color,
not coming from tomatoes.
Nope.
We've got a bunch of,
uh, Guajillo peppers, ancho,
little Chile de arbol.
We got some poblanos.
We got some onions, some garlic
and, then, some stew beef,
some ground beef, uh,
all coming together.
It is gonna be quite fantastic.
And then, right here, well,
some mushrooms and leeks
to go in our stuffed potatoes.
So these are actually
potato skins.
Took some baked potatoes,
scooped 'em out, fried 'em.
Nice and crunchy.
Look at that.
Almost like a, uh, cross
between a hollow french fry
and a potato chip.
Gonna go in there.
I'll get to that in a second.
But in the meantime,
we need to get a little beer.
Beer cheddar cheese sauce.
I mean, I like a cheese sauce
like anybody does,
but when you're gonna make it
and it's standing up
against big flavors like, uh,
a Texas-style chili, you can't
just go out of the can
with this one.
So start with a roux,
simple 50-50 of fat and flour --
butter and flour,
a little half-and-half.
Not too much half-and-half
'cause we're adding in
a full beer.
Nice amber beer so you're gonna
get that deep, rich beer flavor.
Dropping in some sharp cheddar,
grated, slowly,
little bit at a time
so it doesn't seize up
and get into that cheese ball.
A little touch of Cayenne.
And then,
this is where the flavors
get a little bit funky.
Dry mustard.
Got to have that little tang
in there from the dry mustard.
A little bit of Worcestershire.
A little touch of paprika.
There we are.
Stir in a little bit more
of this,
and I got one more cheese
to add to this to make
it really nice and velvety.
And that will be...
Exactly. Cream cheese.
Okay.
I'll let that go.
Get some cream cheese.
I said, "Game day food."
I did not say,
"This is the health show."
Okay.
So we've got cream cheese.
We got beer.
We've got chili.
We'll lay that right
in like that.
Let it cook down.
Don't let it burn.
And that can compete
and stand up to that big, uh,
that big Texas chili.
Okay.
Let me get a little
"S" and "P" into this.
And we'll just let
this go low-and-slow
until it breaks up
that cream cheese.
There we go.
Okay.
Let me talk
about this chili real quick.
The chili, I mean, this has got
a super, important role in this
because we can stuff the chili
into these, uh, potato skins.
There's a lot that could happen.
But what I want to do right now
is pour myself an ice cold beer.
I want to get a little bit
of beer,
and I want to get a little bit
of masa, masa harina.
This is what you'd make,
uh, tamales or tortillas with.
If you don't have masa,
don't worry about running out
to go grab it.
All you're gonna need to do
is use some regular flour.
But I'm just gonna
cut it a little bit into this
so it doesn't clump up on me
when I drop it in there.
So maybe...
that's 2 big tablespoons.
Okay.
And I also
want to add just a touch.
Whoa.
Did I get that on me?
A little bit of paprika.
There we go.
Excellent.
Okay.
So we're gonna mix this up.
It's kind of dissolved there,
kind of like you're making
a slurry.
You get the idea.
I'm gonna turn that heat
down a little bit.
That thing's rolling hard.
Takes about two hours
for that really to reduce.
We have 2 quarts of beef stock
that went into it.
So we'll just slowly
incorporate this in.
And this is gonna work
as an awesome thickener.
It kind of plays
right into the theme of Texas,
and chili and Tex-Mex.
Some nice beer flavor into that.
And, again, no tomatoes,
no beans.
All right. There we go.
Okay.
So this is starting
to melt down nice.
You'll see a nice little cheese
sauce coming out of that.
So while that is melting,
let's get over here
and talk about these skins.
Now, the skins, like I said,
"You have leftover potatoes.
What are you gonna do
with them?"
Well, we're gonna take...
Put a little bit of mushroom
mixture in there with the leeks.
Okay.
We'll peel off...
There you go.
This is...
When you think "Game Day"
at my house, you think,
"Of course,
there's gonna be a little brie."
So we'll crumble a little brie
in there.
And then, what would be
the next thought --
"Okay, yeah. Prosciutto."
There's gonna be
some Italian cold-cuts for sure.
So look at this.
There you go.
Some nice prosciutto,
thinly sliced.
We'll just tear off
a few pieces.
Lay it right up on top.
That'll get nice and crusty,
kind of like bacon.
So I'll knock these out.
Fill 'em up.
Pop 'em in the oven.
Let 'em melt one more time.
Cheese sauce will be done.
The chili's thickening up.
When you come back,
it's game day.
I don't know who's playing,
but it doesn't matter
because this is gonna
be a feast.
See you in a little bit.
Whoa.
Coming over hot.
Look at those bad boys.
Huh?
That's potato skins
like you've never seen before.
Cooked these potatoes.
Scooped 'em out.
Deep fried 'em.
Filled 'em with some cremini
mushrooms, some...
And some, uh, leeks.
Then a little brie, of course.
Isn't it tailgate time?
No?
And a little prosciutto.
That's exactly how we do it
at the Fieri house.
Some cheese sauce
made with some beer
and some cheddar
and a little cream cheese.
And then the star of the show --
Let me turn down some heat.
The start of the show --
this true Texas-style chili.
You see that beautiful red hue.
There's no tomatoes in that.
There's no beans.
But there is a mess
of hot peppers, fresh peppers.
We got a little bit of garlic.
We got beer.
We got a little masa harina
to tighten it up.
And you take a look at that,
ladies and gentlemen.
Tell me that is not gorgeous.
Fantastic.
Grab one of these bad boys.
Drop it down.
Got myself a cold beer.
I'm just tasting,
just doing a little pre-party.
Don't -- don't worry about this.
Okay.
Now, get a little dollop
of some sour cream.
Personally, I'm into, uh,
some red onions.
Oh, you know
what I need back here?
Let me get some chives.
Okay.
Sprinkle those over the top.
And a little scallion.
Not showing off, just hungry.
Okay.
Right on top there.
Excellent.
I get myself a couple crackers.
Drop 'em right on.
This is coming together.
Now, look at that.
All that beautiful red color.
Mm. It's totally missing
something --
cheddar cheese sauce.
What am I thinking?
This is the whole...
This is how I got
the whole party started.
Look at that.
There we go.
So sour cream, the scallions,
the onions, the crackers
and this beautiful red chili
that has no tomato or beans.
Mm.
Deep, rich flavor.
Tighten it up just a little bit
with that masa,
that tortilla flour,
right in there.
Mm.
And the cheese sauce,
man, I'm telling you,
you make that roux.
Get a little bit
of that half-and-half,
but then stopped it and hit
the rest of it with that beer,
with that nice little
amber beer,
you're really getting
that cheese to come through.
Mm.
And then, this right here.
I mean, I think
you say potato skin,
people are expecting
that I fill it with the chili
and hit it
with the cheese sauce,
which isn't a bad idea.
But look at this.
Mushrooms, brie, prosciutto.
A little kiss of the leeks
in there, chives on top.
Game day?
It looks like wedding food.
Isn't it?
Well, it depends on the wedding.
Listen.
You want to get this recipe?
'Cause I know you do.
You know the deal --
foodnetwork.com/guysbigbite.
Hanging out in the backyard,
and I'll see you next week.