Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ta-da!
...we're gearing up
for some global greatness.
That rocks the house.
Like a legendary
Los Angeles spot...
It's exactly
what I wanted it to be.
...definitely doing
Italian their way.
I have done some weird
lasagna making before,
but this is taking
the cake.
...and a money
Minneapolis joint...
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
...making mouthwatering
Middle Eastern.
I've had a lot of good hummus
in my life
but I haven't had very much
hummus this fantastic.
And in Hawaii...
Feel free to put as much
on there as you want.
All of it baby.
...sushi so fresh
it practically swims.
I'm gonna hold the plate,
you put the rest
of it in my mouth.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪
So I'm here in
the San Fernando Valley,
just a few minutes
away from Studio City,
to check out a joint.
And you'll love the story.
I'm in this area shooting
"Minute To Win It," years ago.
And I'm looking for
some great Italian food.
And I get this recommendation.
So I drive around,
I drive around,
and I can't find the place.
Uh, that's because
there was a little bit
of a mix-up on the name.
It's not "Varone's"
it's "Barone's" --
famous Italian restaurant.
All right, guys --
Margherita Pizza ready to go!
Unbelievable.
Just off-the-charts good.
Here is your Tres Cannellonis,
sir. Enjoy, eh?
The aura is
so old-school it's real.
That's 'cause it's been
in business since 1945.
Starting with owner
Tom Monteleone's uncles,
then his dad.
When my father passed,
he says to me "You're gonna
carry on the legacy, here."
Fieri: No problem there.
They did move from
the original location,
to this old German
hofbrau house.
But the classic Italian flavors
remain the same.
And Tom's daughter Laura is
working to take it over.
10 more minutes
on the house combo.
First time I came in,
I had the pizza, I flipped out.
It's definitely different
from any other pizza
I've ever had.
I really like the crust.
So, my favorite thing
is the pizza crust.
[ Sighs ]
Just take a moment.
[ Chuckles ]
Let's make it.
All right. White flour.
Developed yeast?
Yep.
That's a lot of olive oil.
More flavor, right?
No, that's key.
Warm water.
Oh, this works.
We'll proof it
for 24 hours.
That's where that big,
yeasty flavor is developing.
Now we're making our
house combination pizza.
We're gonna brush the pan
with olive oil,
grab a portion
of the dough --
So it gets sheeted out.
Flatten the dough
around the edges.
And we're gonna roll it
with a rolling pin.
So we don't get
the big air bubbles.
Right. And then, one full scoop
of our house marinara sauce.
And then, we actually just
take it like this, here.
That's how we move it
around?
Yeah.
No rubber spatula
or nothin'?
Swish it around. Nope.
"Swish it"?
Yep.
I never say that.
Then we add our toppings.
Homemade sausage.
Pork or beef?
There's a mixture of both.
Now pepperoni?
Yes.
That is thick.
Well, we're actually
pretty well known
for our pepperoni.
Bell peppers.
Thinly sliced.
Finally our Monterey Jack.
You guys melt the cheese
on top of everything?
-Yep.
-I dig it.
All into the oven at 650?
15-20 minutes.
It's gonna be crispy.
Oh, you're gonna love this --
when you come here.
Mm. It's the yeast
in the dough,
right off the bat,
that you get.
You can just smell it.
Look at that fat from
the pepperoni float to the top.
Mmm.
My other favorite part
about this
is the green bell pepper.
You guys slice it really thin,
it's all hot in that cheese,
and then it kinda melts.
Mm-hmm.
But the key is is that
you haven't changed this.
I've been eatin' this pizza
for nine or ten years
and it's still
the exact same way
that I had it the first time.
It's dynamite.
And see ya later.
House combo up in a minute!
This pizza is amazing!
This is my team from, uh,
"Guy's Grocery Games."
They have seen some
incredible food.
So, give me the rundown.
Best pizza I've had
in a long time in L.A.
Fieri: But it took the stuff of
Hollywood legend to get it here.
We didn't make pizza
in '45.
Barone's didn't have
pizza in '45?
No. No. I don't know
if you recall the Bowery Boys?
They were a group of New York
film stars in the '40s and '50s
who came in for Italian when
they were shootin' in Hollywood.
Well, they said, uh, "How come
you don't have pizza here?"
My uncle said,
"What's that?"
They said, "Well,
it's big in New York."
Wow. Pizza hadn't made it
to the west coast yet?
So, they gave it
a try with one hitch.
All they had was
a sheet pan.
And the rectangle pie was born.
But, that's not the only twist
you'll find here.
The lasagna?
Well, it has a style of its own.
Here's our famous
cheese lasagna.
Enjoy, eh?
Very cheesy,
very delicious.
So this is a straight ricotta
and pasta lasagna?
Yep.
Fire me up.
All right.
So, we're doin' noodles.
Outside of it?
Yep. We lay it
just like that.
I have done some weird
lasagna makin' before
but this is taking the cake.
Now we're gonna do eight across,
the opposite way.
[ Laughter ]
Now I feel like
we're having a race.
-I'll do it I'll --
-I got it!
[ Laughter ]
Have you ever made lasagna
with a 4-year-old?
Now we go for our ricotta
cheese, Parmesan cheese.
Eggs.
Black pepper.
Parsley.
Mix it all together.
We put a pretty thick amount.
You think?
This is like ricotta pie.
And there you've got
your first layer.
There's another layer
coming?
I've made a lot
of lasagnas.
I've never seen this technique
in a million years.
I love it.
Now we tuck them
over underneath.
Of course we are.
Well, this thing
ain't gonna fall apart.
It'll probably re-enter
the Earth's atmosphere
the way this is bound up.
Now, what temperature
are we gonna bake this at?
500 degrees
for 1 1/2 hours.
Then we'd serve it with...?
Homemade sauce
and meatballs
and melted
Monterey Jack cheese on top.
Look at this iceberg
of lasagna.
I have never seen a lasagna
stand up that high.
You built it like
a fortress, girl.
It's exactly what
I wanted it to be.
Old-school
American-Italian.
Extra hot and cheesy.
Mm-hmm.
As much ricotta
as there is in there,
it's still really light.
The meatball stands
on its own.
The sauce is nice.
It balances it well.
The cheese is crazy.
I thought it was gonna
be big and monstrous --
you didn't disappoint.
Thank you.
Nice job.
Lasagna Meatball Parmesan.
This is one of the best
lasagnas I have ever had.
Nice melting of cheese
over it.
And this really
rich marinara sauce.
Spaghetti carbonara --
ready to go.
If you're anywhere near
Hollywood, come to Barone's.
It's really, well,
just yum.
Man: You bring your kids,
your nieces, your grandma,
you uncle, your neighbors --
everyone.
This is what
I hoped it was.
And this is what people
want to know.
There's still some
of these old-school joints.
And the pizza's legendary.
This is great.
Fieri: Coming up,
a legit Maui sushi spot...
I'm just trying this
for personal reasons.
...rollin' out what they're
personally reelin' in.
I'd eat that out
of a dirty shoe.
I just want a set
of these chairs
to roll around at home in.
Of course.
Hi, welcome to "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Lounges."
[ Laughter ]
♪
So here I am in beautiful Kihei
in the island of Maui.
About a quarter mile
from the beach,
right in the center
of all the hotels --
at a strip mall.
Yeah, I know what you'd like.
You'd like me to take you
to a -- to a sushi restaurant
where the owner
catches his own fish,
and maybe, grows
his own vegetables.
Well, you know what?
That's where we are.
This is Miso Phat Sushi.
Everything that I've tried here
has been phenomenal.
TNT and Gyro.
The best sushi
on the planet.
Rainbow roll.
This is as special
as you can get.
That's 'cause lifelong
restaurant man
owner Shawn Steadman
is reeling in the fish himself.
Your special today.
The owner brings the fish
right through the front door
and takes pictures
with the people.
-What's the name of the boat?
-The Shiso Phat.
-So Miso Phat...
-Is the restaurant.
-Shiso Phat...
-Right.
And my dog is
the Hiso Phat.
[ Laughter ]
Fieri: And while Shawn keeps
the customers laughing,
veteran sushi chef
and Hawaiian native Ahren Uyeda
is keeping things fresh
in the kitchen.
You watch them cut
the fresh filets
and put together
a masterpiece.
Like this ridiculous
tower of tuna,
snow crab, and shrimp tempura.
It just melts in my mouth.
And I just love
everything about it.
All right, we're gonna
make the TNT roll?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
This is our Ahi
for the Ahi poke.
Yeah, this is
gonna go on top?
On top of the sushi roll,
yes.
Got it.
Oh, my mouth just...
I mean, I didn't
even have breakfast
and I'm gonna jump
into this raw fish.
Dig it.
Next we put
our light soy sauce.
Sesame oil.
Got it.
And this is our Hawaiian
chili-pepper water.
Hawaiian chili-pepper water?
Yes.
I like that.
There's a nice little tang,
little -- little
sting to that.
Actually the owner
of the restaurant,
Shawn, makes this.
Shawn makes that?
Correct. We'll just mix it up
just a little bit.
Add some thinly sliced
cucumbers.
Some avocados.
Mix that up.
All right.
I'm just gonna --
I'm just trying this
for personal reasons.
Good?
The light soy
and the freshness
that you're getting
from the cucumber...
Mm-hmm.
And the lean tuna
with the fattiness
of the avocado...
Mm-hmm.
...all wants to get
into my mouth.
I'd eat that out
of a dirty shoe.
I've eaten half of it.
[ Laughs ]
All right, we're gonna
make the tempura shrimp?
Correct.
Give me the breakdown
on the flours we're using.
All-purpose flour.
Cornstarch. Potato starch.
And a little salt?
A little salt.
Some ice.
Ice cubes?
Ice cubes.
Not ice water?
Nope.
Huh, okay.
This melts down,
makes your batter.
Mm-hmm. Next,
we have to clean our shrimp.
Lay it flat.
So what he did here is he
made these little cuts.
So if you ever want
to cook your shrimp
and cook it on a skewer
and have it stay
nice and straight --
that little technique there.
Okay.
Dredge it in the same mix
then wet and fry it.
Next up, a sheet of nori.
Grab my rice.
We got our snow crab meat.
Any binder in that?
A little mayo.
-A little mayo?
-A little mayo.
Grab our tempura.
Roll it and shape it.
So fresh it's almost
jumping into my mouth.
And then Ahi poke.
Be heavy-handed.
Feel free to put
as much on there as you want,
all of it maybe.
That'll be fine.
Kabayaki sauce.
What's Kabayaki sauce?
Uh, like a unagi sauce.
Okay.
And then agave honey
and sesame seeds.
You see this little dance?
[ Laughs ]
I'm getting the crunch
of the tempura.
I'm getting the creaminess
of the crab.
But then I just get
this nice,
phenomenal flavor
of the sashimi on top.
The tuna is so fresh,
as soon as it hits your mouth
it just kind of starts
to dissolve.
It's really
an over-the-top roll.
I'm gonna hold the plate,
you push the rest
of it in my mouth.
[ Laughs ]
Woman: TNT roll.
You got the crunch,
you got the fresh.
It's unique, I've never seen it
anywhere in my life.
I just love
every bit of it.
You want to make
another roll?
Mnh-mnh. Ice cream.
Liliko'i ice cream.
-Seriously?
-Seriously.
All right. What kind of
ice cream are we gonna make?
Uh, liliko'i.
Liliko'i ice cream is the best
ice cream in the world.
You feel like you're eating
a little bit of Hawaii.
-Liliko'i?
-Liliko'i.
He's messing with me now.
I'll see you in a minute.
♪
Welcome back.
Here we are in Maui,
having fantastic sushi
at a funky joint, Miso Phat.
Now we're gonna make
ice cream.
[ Chuckles ]
I don't know.
Liliko'i.
I'm as tripped out
on it as you.
It's called liliko'i.
Liliko'i ice cream.
Oh, my gosh. I think it's like
the best kept secret, here.
The liliko'i just brings out
the freshness of the islands.
This is the liliko'i fruit.
-This is it?
-That's it.
What is it?
Is it an apple?
No, passion fruit.
-Passion fruit?
-Passion fruit.
Now,
let me get this straight,
there's the guy that owns
this place, Shawn.
-Yes.
-Right?
Has a fishing boat,
he catches as much as he can.
Yes.
He also grows a bunch of the
vegetables for his restaurant.
Mm-hmm. Even that.
Is that normal?
Not really.
I've seen farm to table
in a lot of aspects
but I don't think I've ever
seen it in a sushi restaurant.
Probably not.
So, we're gonna take this
and make ice cream with it?
Yep.
We do just one of these
or are we gonna do
a whole case?
Just one,
because a whole case
would take us about
six hours.
As you can see there's
not much juice in it.
And what we do is just scrape
the seeds and the membrane out.
And now you're gonna see why
it takes so long to make this.
So the seeds and everything
don't go in it?
We're just gonna get
the liquid out of it?
Just the juice.
And this is only one fruit.
And how many does it take
to make ice cream?
About a case. The taste
is a million times better
with a fresh liliko'i
than like a concentrate
or, you know,
the frozen juice.
All right, let's do it.
Okay.
Sugar. Milk.
Heavy whipping cream.
Our juice.
Vanilla extract.
And half and half.
Mix it all up.
Dump it in here.
You're gonna tell me that
this little munchkin
ice cream maker
is going to make
the ice cream?
Yep.
And just turn it on.
That's it.
Pbbt!
[ Laughs ]
How long is it gonna go here
in this little ice cream maker?
20 minutes.
All right, so you whip it,
then you take it and freeze it,
now it's frozen hard.
Yep.
Now we're gonna serve it.
There you go.
Mmm.
That's outstanding.
Thank you.
This is like a cross between
an ice cream and a sorbet.
And the tangy-ness
of the liliko'i is fantastic.
Yeah.
Mmm.
This is a really nice
palate cleanser.
Outstanding. I mean, and I don't
really like ice cream that much.
That rocks the house.
Thank you.
Here we go, we got some
liliko'i ice cream for you.
It's like you're eating a fresh
liliko'i, like, off of the tree.
A great way
to end off the meal.
Woman: If you're here on Maui
and you're in Kihei,
you've definitely got
to check out Miso Phat.
You better tell the boss,
he's gonna need like
three more boats...
Mm-hmm, pretty much.
...two plantations.
When people get a load
of this -- dead.
Well done.
Fieri: Up next...
a market/restaurant/factory
bakery....
How about we just say what
things we didn't put in here?
...bringing Middle Eastern
to Minneapolis for decades.
I couldn't imagine
that it would be this good.
[ Laughter ]
[ Muffled ] Welcome back.
I'm Guy Fieri.
♪
So I'm here on the northeast
side of Minneapolis,
you know, the North East,
to check out a type of food
you probably wouldn't expect --
Middle Eastern.
But the story's much
bigger than that.
I mean we're talking about
a falafel and hummus empire.
And a family
that's helped revitalize
an entire neighborhood.
You're gonna love it.
This is Holy Land.
Woman:
I have a gyro sandwich.
Watching the meat cook
makes my mouth water.
Tandoori chicken
and crab cakes ready!
It's actually hard
to choose what to order.
You have to come back.
Arabic beef and chicken
shawirma plate.
The Holy Land
is a little piece
of the Middle East
in the Midwest.
Fieri:
Thanks to the Wadi family,
who came to Minneapolis by
the way of Jordan and Kuwait.
Hummus plate appetizer
is coming up, guys.
Majdi's running the operation
his brother Wajdi
started back in 1987,
servin' up a menu full
of Mama Fatima's recipes.
She's still coming
here every day.
-Every day?
-Drive us crazy, you know?
[ Chuckling ]
Drive us crazy.
And what started out as a
700-square-foot market and deli
now fills a full city block.
With more groceries,
a full restaurant,
and, get this --
a hummus factory.
Woman:
Falafel and hummus appetizer.
The hummus is just
fresh as can be.
So, how do you
make great hummus?
-Cooked chickpeas.
-Cooked chickpeas?
Fresh squeezed lemon juice.
Sea salt.
Citric acid.
Imported extra virgin olive oil
for the holy land.
[ Whirring loudly ]
So quiet!
[ Whirring stops ]
Now we want to add ice.
And the main ingredient --
Tahini.
It's sesame based.
Sesame based.
All right, fire it up boss.
[ Whirs loudly ]
[ Whistles ]
All right, so, now we're
gonna make the falafel.
Falafel, yes. First, we soak
the chickpeas overnight.
Not cooked?
No, not cooked.
Got it.
And then a ton of parsley.
And cilantro.
Yes.
It's like we're
feeding horses.
While this one is mixing,
we can do the spice mix
that we're gonna add.
Let's go.
Ground green cardamom.
Cardamom.
Ginger. Cumin.
Turmeric.
Caraway seeds.
Caraway seed
and this coriander.
Okay.
Sea salt.
The baking soda.
The baking soda, okay.
And then skin-on garlic.
Skin-on garlic?
Yes.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
How can you have
the skin on garlic?
I asked my mom. Her answer
was very specific --
"Shut up and do it
this way."
Crazy. Okay.
All the garlic.
And then the spice.
Now mix it five times.
The fifth mix, we add
some water in.
Make it very smooth.
That's the falafel
that I know.
It's nice and it's light
and it's fluffy
and you can smell
the herbaceousness
of the parsley
and the cilantro.
Fry it up.
Okay, falafels are done.
Now we're gonna make hummus.
Add some cooked chickpeas.
Black olive for garnishing.
Paprika.
Extra virgin olive oil.
And some parsley
for garnishing.
And that's how you do it.
Where do you get the pita from?
We have our bakery.
Of course you do, of course.
I'm sorry, I apologize
that I even asked.
Fresh daily.
♪
I've had a lot of good hummus
in my life.
But, I haven't had very much
hummus that's this fantastic.
Thank you.
Fantastic.
Try it with the falafel.
Seasoning's perfect,
just look at the color.
The warm falafel
that's just buttery inside.
That olive oil
is ridiculous.
Oh.
Fantastic, my friend.
Falafel and hummus
appetizer up!
I've been a big fan of their
hummus for quite a while.
North East Minneapolis
wouldn't be the same
without Holy Land.
Man: Even when the store
was small,
Majdi has been great supporter
for our community.
Fieri: Which is why the city
even made August 12th
Holy Land Day in Minneapolis.
This is the glue that holds
everything together
for this street.
And it doesn't hurt that they're
cooking up dishes like this.
Woman:
Arabic chicken shawirma wrap.
Man: I've never eaten
such a thing anywhere else.
It's just awesome.
Majdi: Now we're
making the marinade
for the Arabic chicken
shawirma.
Fieri: Fire it up.
Apple vinegar.
Yogurt. Onion.
A lot of it.
Lemon. Olive oil.
Freshly squeezed orange juice.
Sea salt.
"Washersister."
"Wash your sister"?
Yes. Worcestershire.
I cannot --
"Wash your sister" sauce?
Yes, "Wash your sister" sauce.
[ Laughter ]
Now --
tahini.
Tahini.
Ground cinnamon.
Cloves.
Okay.
Chili flakes. Nutmeg.
Cardamom. Turmeric.
Garlic-ginger paste.
Citric acid.
Citric acid again.
Paprika. Ground saffron.
How about we just
say what things
we didn't put in here?
Yeah, that's good.
Laundry soap.
[ Laughs ]
Curry.
And then oregano.
Now we get the chicken.
Yes.
Natural, free range.
100% vegetarian fed.
Halal slaughtered.
Now we're adding
chicken shawirma spices.
Doctor.
We mix this up,
we let it marinade.
In the cooler for 24 hours.
Just stack it up.
Stack it up.
Ta-da!
It's breast, thigh,
breast, thigh.
Yes.
To the top.
Then we load it up,
cut it thin?
Cut it thin.
I dig it.
Now we're bringing it up
to the flat-top.
First, garlic butter.
Then, the chicken.
Then, Lianne sauce.
What is it called?
Lianne sauce.
Lianne is my daughter, yes.
Lianne sauce?
You named it after Lianne?
Yes. Salt and pepper.
Garlic mayo.
Cook it for 60 seconds.
leave it set.
Chicken.
Some cucumber pickles.
Some pickles.
Garlic mayo.
We roll it, toast it.
Look at this, huh?
Wrap it. And then --
Tear it?
That's how it goes.
What is the bread?
Lebanese bread.
Lebanese bread?
Baked freshly daily, here.
Of course.
Yeah.
A little bit of acid
from the pickles.
Nice and creamy
with that mayo in there.
You cook it low,
you cook it slow.
All the spices
get into that chicken.
Fantastic.
Lianne, Arabic
crab chicken sandwich.
It's just too good.
This is a good friend of mine
Christina, what do you think?
I have not had anything
like it before.
A lot of big, authentic,
bold flavors.
It's just a fun place
to come and eat.
My crew told me it was
gonna be a great visit.
I couldn't imagine
that it would be this good.
Majdi: Thank you.
So that wraps this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to get
some of the recipes
from today's show,
go to FoodNetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Where are we going?
[ Laughter ]
Man: Did you drop it?
You gotta really stay
serious on this show.
It's important.