HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
- THIS TRIP...
- LOOK AT THAT!
REAL-DEAL BARBECUE...
IT DON'T GET
NO BETTER THAN THAT.
FROM EVERYWHERE...
THAT IS TASTY.
THIS SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
JOINT...
IT'S A SHACK IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE STREET.
WHERE IT ALL TASTES
LIKE MEMPHIS...
THE SAUCE DOESN'T GO ON IT
UNTIL IT COMES OUT.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT.
'CAUSE SHE'S MAKIN' SURE.
MOVE OVER.
LET ME SHOW YA.
OKAY.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CHICAGO
FOR TEXAS BRISKET...
THE BRISKET IS TO DIE FOR.
ST. LOUIS RIBS,
CAROLINA SAUCE...
LIKE A FINE WINE.
AND BAKED BEANS
FROM ANOTHER UNIVERSE.
THAT'S MORE THAN A SIDE.
THAT'S LIKE A MEAL.
YEAH.
WE'RE CHECKIN' OUT
A SHACK IN KANSAS
WHERE THEY'LL BARBECUE ANYTHING
FROM WHOLE HOG...
LOOK AT THAT!
TO CHICKEN WINGS...
THEY'RE THE BEST
CHICKEN WINGS AROUND.
AND THE HEAT DOESN'T JUST
COME FROM THE FIRE.
BROTHER, THAT'S WICKED.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
Closed Captions provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC.
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
WHEN YOU'RE THINKIN' BARBECUE,
YOU'RE PROBABLY THINKIN' TEXAS,
MEMPHIS, NORTH CAROLINA,
BUT, YOU KNOW, BARBECUE
HAS NO BOUNDARIES.
IT HAS NO CITY LIMITS,
NO ZIP CODE.
I'M HERE IN GARDENA, CALIFORNIA,
AT A BARBECUE HAVEN
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE ROAD.
I'VE BEEN ROLLIN' TO THIS PLACE
FOR OVER 15 YEARS.
WELCOME TO JAY BEE'S BAR-B-Q.
WHAT TYPE OF SAUCE
YOU PREFER?
MILD SAUCE.
NUMBER 35.
YOU AT MY PLAYGROUND NOW.
WHAT ABOUT THEM GREENS?
THERE'S NO MESSIN'
WITH BEVERLY NEELY...
DON'T CHEAT 'EM.
PUT SOME MORE IN THERE. THERE
YOU GO. THAT'S WHAT I LIKE.
'CAUSE WHAT SHE'S DOIN' HERE...
IT'S A SHACK IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE STREET.
IS THE REAL DEAL.
- SO WHICH ONE, BEEF OR PORK?
-        PORK.
WE HAVE BEEF RIBS, PORK RIBS
AND A PORK SANDWICH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND THIS PROBABLY
WAS MY REAL INTRODUCTION
- TO SOUTHERN-STYLE BARBECUE.
- REALLY?
IT WAS PULLED PORK.
I REMEMBER EATIN' IT GOIN',
"OH. THIS IS THE BEST
THING I'VE EVER HAD."
OH, THIS IS THE BEST
IN THE WEST.
HOW'S IT GOIN'?
HOW YOU DOIN'?
OKAY.
I GOT YA. I GOT YA.
IT FEELS LIKE FAMILY.
IF I SEE SOMETHIN' THAT'S NOT
RIGHT, I'M GONNA FUSS ABOUT IT.
THERE YOU GO. THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE.
YOU GOT THEM GREENS WORKIN'?
I WANT EVERY--EVERY
FOOD THAT I SERVE--
I WANT IT TO GO OUT THE WAY I
WOULD WANT TO BUY IT AND EAT IT.
IT DON'T GET
NO BETTER THAN THAT.
ALONG WITH HER SON CURTIS,
BEVERLY'S KEEPIN' UP
A PROUD FAMILY TRADITION.
MY BROTHER THAT OWNS BARBECUE
PLACES IN MEMPHIS--INTERSTATE.
YOUR BROTHER OWNS
INTERSTATE BAR-B-QUE?
YEAH, JAMES--JIM NEELY.
GET OUT!
THAT'S HOW--
YOU ARE NOT SERIOUS!
INTERSTATE BAR-B-QUE
IS RENOWNED.
YES.
ARE THESE THE RECIPES
FROM HIM?
SAME RECIPES.
SAME HICKORY SMOKIN',
SAME SPARE RIBS...
NOW HIT IT
WITH THE DRY RUB?
SAME DRY RUB
WITH CHILI POWDER,
SEASONED SALT AND PAPRIKA.
OUT IN CALIFORNIA,
WE TEND TO SEE A LOT
MORE BABY BACK RIBS,
BUT I REALLY THINK--
MY PERSONAL PREFERENCE
IS THAT THE ST. LOUIS--
THE SPARE RIB--
HAS MORE MEAT
AND MORE FLAVOR.
MOISTER, YOU KNOW,
IT'S A LITTLE MORE JUICIER.
AND THESE ARE GONNA GO ON
AT 225 FOR 4 HOURS?
YES, SIR.
WOW.
AND HERE YOU KNOW--
YOU TELL YOUR RIBS ARE DONE--
YOU HOLD 'EM
FROM THE BACK HERE.
IF THEY BREAK APART,
THAT'S HOW TENDER IT IS.
YOU DON'T WANT 'EM
TOTALLY FALLIN' APART,
BUT YOU WANT 'EM
TO HAVE A GOOD...
OH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH.
I'M SORRY YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GET TO EAT TODAY, CURTIS.
YEAH, I'M GONNA EAT TODAY.
SO THE SAUCE DOESN'T GO ON IT
UNTIL IT COMES OUT.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT.
RIGHT.
MMM. TENDER.
GREAT SMOKE FLAVOR.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
I CAN'T EVEN TELL YOU.
HERE YOU GO.
SAUCE--A LITTLE SWEET
WITH SOME TANG.
SO HOW MANY TIMES
DO YOU MAKE SAUCE A WEEK?
MAKE IT THREE TIMES
A DAY, BROTHER.
I LIKE IT FRESH.
KETCHUP AND PASTE.
AND PASTE.
CORN SYRUP.
VINEGAR--NOW THAT'S WHAT'S
GIVIN' IT THAT TANG,
THAT WANG THAT YOU GET.
THIS IS THE SECRET.
MUSTARD. YOU GOT THE ONION
POWDER, THE GARLIC POWDER.
IT LOOKS LIKE SOME CAYENNE,
SOME PAPRIKA,
BROWN SUGAR,
REGULAR SUGAR.
PRETTY MUCH.
THAT CLOSE ENOUGH?
SALT, PEPPER.
CLOSE ENOUGH.
YOU WANT ME
TO STIR THIS UP?
NO, NOT YET. SO WE'LL
STIR EVERY 15 MINUTES.
EVERY 15 MINUTES, YOU MAKE
SURE THAT SOMEONE STIRS IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I FEEL BAD WIPIN' SAUCE
OFF MY LIPS.
THAT'S JUST--THAT'S WRONG.
I SHOULD JUST LICK IT OFF.
AND YOU CAN GET IT
WITH EVERYTHING HERE...
MAY I HELP YOU,
PLEASE, MA'AM?
YES, A SMALL ORDER
OF PORK SHOULDER MEAT.
FROM THE BRISKET
THAT'S BEEN SMOKIN'
FOR AT LEAST TEN HOURS...
SHE'S ROLLIN'.
WOW.
MM-HMM.
TO THE BARBECUE CHICKEN...
THERE YOU GO. VOILà.
OH!
IT'S ALL RIGHT?
DUDE, I'VE BEEN STRICKEN
BY CHICKEN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S THE BEST.
NEVER HAD ANYTHING LIKE IT.
I COME ALL THE WAY
DOWN HERE FROM ONTARIO
JUST TO HAVE THEIR RIBS.
IT'S OUR ROMANTIC SATURDAY
NIGHT DINNER.
AND STILL JUST AS REAL-DEAL
AS 15 YEARS AGO
WHEN THEY GOT ME WITH
THEIR PULLED-PORK SANDWICH.
IT'S A SLOPPY ONE TO EAT,
AND, YOU KNOW, IT HAS GREAT
FLAVOR, BUT GOOD STUFF.
SO BONE-IN PORK SHOULDER.
YEAH, I GOT BONE-IN.
THAT'S IMPORTANT.
FOR ME, IT'S IMPORTANT.
THAT'S WHERE
THE FLAVOR IS.
AND THEN HIT IT
WITH THE DRY RUB AGAIN.
DO LIKE WE DID.
GET UP INSIDE ANY
OF THOSE CREVICES.
ANY OF THOSE CREVICES YOU GOT,
YOU WANT TO HIT 'EM.
YEAH, AND NOW WE'RE READY.
WAKE UP. WAKE UP. WAKE UP.
ALL RIGHT, SHE'S IN.
BOOM, AND THAT'S GONNA
BE FAT UP, OF COURSE,
AND, UH, JUST GONNA
LET HER COOK FOR 12 HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH.
THAT'S HOT.
SAME DEMON.
ALL RIGHT, COOL. GET THE--
GRAB THE REST OF IT.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, GRAB SOME
OF THAT IN THERE.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO FORGET YOUR PART.
OKAY, THAT'S IT.
PULL IT APART. SEE,
NOW YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO--
I DON'T HAVE TO PUT
NO PRESSURE ON IT.
IT JUST PULLS APART.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
MOVE OVER. LET ME SHOW YA.
LET ME SHOW YA.
OKAY.
NO. NO, NO, NO, NO.
A PULLED PORK SANDWICH
IS YOU PULL IT.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALL IT
A PULLED PORK.
NOT PULL IT LIKE THAT.
YOU HAVE TO PULL IT
LIKE THIS, SEE?
AND YOU PUT IT
ON THE BUN LIKE THIS.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS SAYIN'
THE WHOLE TIME, BEV.
YEAH, BUT THIS IS PULLED.
CURTIS--
HE'S A TENDERFOOT
BECAUSE IT'S HOT,
BUT, SEE, MAMA'S USED
TO SOME HEAT.
MAMA'S USED TO--
OOH!
MAMA USED TO HEAT.
I HATE WHEN I GET
IN TROUBLE.
TAKE A LITTLE OF--
NOW WHEN DO I PUT
THE SAUCE ON, NOW?
NOPE.
NO?
YOU DUMP IT
ON TOP LIKE THAT.
NOW WE POUR SOME SAUCE.
THE SECRET IS TO POUR
A LITTLE SAUCE LIKE THIS.
STOP.
PRESS IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
LET IT SOAK IN.
COME BACK.
WE WANT TO DROWN IT
WITH SAUCE.
NOW THAT'S WHAT YOU CALL
A GOOD PORK--
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
DO YOU THINK I SHOULD JUST
GO WITHOUT THE HANDS
AND GO IN LIKE A TROUGH?
OH, JUST GO AHEAD ON.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE AT HOME WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
JUST PICK IT UP.
YOU'RE AT HOME
WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
OH, WE NEED YOU A NAPKIN.
THAT'S WHAT YOU CALL
A PULLED--
THAT'S SOME GOOD
PULLED PORK.
THAT'S SOME GOOD--I KNOW
IT'S SOME GOOD PULLED PORK.
I KNOW YOU KNOW IT.
EVERYTHING I MAKE IS GOOD.
SO IT WAS NICE
MEETIN' YOU.
YEAH, TOTALLY.
AND THAT'S A WRAP. THAT'S
A WRAP. THAT'S A WRAP.
THAT'S A WRAP. NOW SHE'S
IN THE TV BUSINESS.
OOH!
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CHICAGO
TO A JOINT DOIN'
BARBECUE FUSION...
THIS REMINDS ME
OF TENNESSEE BARBECUE.
CAROLINA SAUCE...
THIS I COULD JUST DRINK.
TEXAS BRISKET,
TWO KINDS OF RIBS...
WOW, THOSE SMELL AWESOME.
AND THEY'RE KNOCKIN' IT
OUT OF THE PARK.
THAT'S CAPITAL T TENDER.
ON TRIPLE D, I AM ALWAYS
ON THE HUNT FOR BARBECUE.
I LOVE TO LOOK AT IT.
I LOVE TO MAKE IT.
I REALLY LOVE TO EAT IT.
SO WHEN I'M ROLLIN'
THROUGH CHICAGO
AND I HEAR THERE'S THREE DUDES
DOIN' BARBECUE UP RIGHT,
I JUST GOTTA STOP
AND CHECK OUT SMOQUE.
HOT BEHIND YA.
ZERO EIGHT!
TEXAS-STYLE BRISKET...
AUSTIN, TEXAS, HAS GOT THE BEST
BRISKET IN THE COUNTRY.
THIS PLACE HAS GOT
BETTER BRISKET.
MEMPHIS-STYLE RIBS...
I LOVE IT.
PULLED PORK DRENCHED
IN CAROLINA SAUCE...
PULLED PORK IS AN ART FORM,
AND THEY DO IT REALLY WELL.
EVEN BAKED BEANS THE WAY
THEY DO 'EM IN KANSAS CITY.
I HAD THE BARBECUE BEANS. THEY
WERE JUST UNBELIEVABLY GREAT.
THE FOLKS AT SMOQUE ARE SERVIN'
UP ALL KINDS OF BARBECUE...
96!
MODELED ON THE BEST
OF THE BEST.
THIS REMINDS ME
OF TENNESSEE BARBECUE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
IT'S JUST OFF THE HOOK.
IT'S OFF THE HOOK.
HOW FAR DID YOU TOUR
TO GO FIND BARBEQUE,
TO GO SEARCH OUT
BARBEQUE?
WE SPENT A LOT OF TIME
IN KANSAS CITY,
SPENT A LOT OF TIME
DOWN IN AUSTIN.
YOU KNOW, WE'VE BEEN TO
THE CAROLINAS AND MEMPHIS.
...AND BROUGHT IT ALL BACK HERE
LESS THAN A YEAR AGO...
YOU GUYS HAVE A GOOD
AFTERNOON. THANKS A LOT.
AFTER BARRY SORKIN
AND A COUPLE OF BUDDIES
DECIDED TO GET OUT OF HIGH TECH
AND INTO BARBEQUE.
SO HOW'S EVERYTHING
HERE SO FAR?
I WAS WORKIN' FOR
AN I.T. CONSULTING FIRM,
AND I JUST DECIDED
I'D RATHER MAKE RIBS.
NOW DID YOU HAVE A LOT
OF RESTAURANT EXPERIENCE?
I WORKED FOR A HANDFUL
OF CORPORATE RESTAURANTS.
YOU'VE NEVER BEEN A CHEF.
NO.
BUT HE WAS AND IS
A BARBECUE FANATIC.
SQUEEZE THIS AND PULL IT APART
WITH YOUR HAND.
AND HIS DREAM WAS TO BRING
THE BEST OF EVERYWHERE
BACK HOME TO CHICAGO.
- TWO FOR HERE.
-   IT WAS A LITTLE SCARY.
WE DIDN'T KNOW IF ANYONE
WAS GONNA SHOW UP OR NOT.
IS IT ALWAYS THIS BUSY?
EVERY TIME THAT
I'VE BEEN HERE, YEAH.
I'M GONNA DO THE BRISKET.
AND IT'S REALLY TOUGH
TO MAKE REALLY GOOD BRISKET.
IS THAT YOUR MOST POPULAR?
YEAH, WHICH WAS
A HUGE SURPRISE TO US.
WE DIDN'T THINK WE WERE GONNA
SELL ANY BRISKET IN CHICAGO.
IN FACT, WE ALMOST DIDN'T
PUT IT ON THE MENU.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
CHICAGO'S TRADITIONALLY
A SWEET SAUCE AND RIBS TOWN,
BUT THE DRY-RUB BRISKET
IS SELLIN' OUT.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE YOU
TO SELL THIS?
WE'LL GO
THROUGH THIS TODAY.
95!
I COME HERE FOR ONE REASON
ONLY--THEIR BRISKET.
AND THIS BRISKET'S
DONE THE TEXAS WAY...
I THINK RUB'S THE MOST
IMPORTANT PART OF BARBECUE.
OH, I'M DOWN WITH YA
ON THE RUB.
THAT'S 1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 10,
11, 12, 13.
THIS IS ALL GOIN'
FOR ONE RUB?
IT'S ALL GOIN' FOR ONE RUB. WE
USE THE SAME RUB FOR EVERYTHING.
WE DO SOMETHIN' A LITTLE BIT
SPECIAL FOR THE BRISKET.
WE PUT A LITTLE EXTRA
GROUND PEPPER.
WE JUST PUT A LAYER OF PEPPER
ON TOP OF THE OTHER RUB.
IT'S KILLER.
WITH SOME KEY INGREDIENTS
YOU MIGHT NOT EXPECT.
GROUND CORIANDER.
OOH, THAT'S TASTY.
IT IS TASTY.
FRESH SPICES.
VERY FRESH.
THAT'S YOUR REAL KEY.
IT'S VERY FRESH, YEAH.
GINGER, GROUND GINGER.
THAT'S FUNNY.
I PUT GINGER IN MINE.
LEMON PEPPER.
NOW THAT'S
AN INTERESTING ONE.
THESE ARE GROUND CLOVES.
CITRIC ACID, OR SOUR SALT
IT'S SOMETIMES CALLED.
AND JUST LIKE IN TEXAS,
PLENTY OF PEPPER.
YOU'VE SPENT SOME
TIME ON THIS.
MONTHS.
AND THEN LASTLY,
THE REST OF THE SALT.
WE USE KOSHER SALT.
PUT A NICE HEAVY COAT
ON BOTH SIDES.
AND THIS IS WHERE THAT EXTRA
SHIELD OF BLACK PEPPER COMES IN.
YEAH. I JUST THINK
BLACK PEPPER AND BRISKET
GO TOGETHER REALLY,
REALLY WELL.
YEAH, THEY DO,
ALL THAT FAT.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S IT.
YOU'VE BEEN RUNNIN' THESE
BRISKETS SINCE LAST NIGHT.
LOOK AT THOSE!
COME TO PAPA.
THAT'S A HOLY BARK.
MMM. THAT IS TASTY.
THAT'S CAPITAL T TENDER.
NOW WHAT SMOKE
ARE WE USING?
WE'RE USIN' A MIX
OF APPLE AND OAK.
I LIKE YOUR DOUBLE PEPPER IDEA--
ANT ITE
I LIKE YIT'S JUST TENDER. IDEA--
SO YOU'VE HAD BRISKET
DOWN IN TEXAS?
YEAH.
HOW DOES THAT COMPARE?
I LIKE THIS BETTER.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
DOIN' THIS?
WE'VE BEEN HERE
FOR ABOUT NINE MONTHS,
BUT I'VE BEEN DOIN' IT AS
A HOBBY FOR A GOOD LONG TIME.
LONG ENOUGH TO TRY TO CHANGE
CHICAGO'S MIND ABOUT RIBS.
THIS HAS ALWAYS BEEN
A BABY BACK TOWN,
AND BARRY'S GLAD TO MAKE 'EM.
HOT BEHIND YA.
BUT HE'S ALSO DOIN' THE BIGGER
AND MEATIER ST. LOUIS RIB,
WHICH HE PREFERS,
AND NOW LOTS OF FOLKS
ARE DECIDIN' HE'S RIGHT.
I'M GONNA DO THE HALF SLAB
OF ST. LOUIS.
PEOPLE THAT ARE USED TO BABY
BACKS HAVE BEEN ORDERING THESE
AND GOIN',
"I LIKE THIS BETTER."
PUT A THIN COATING
ON THE BACK.
PUT A MUCH HEAVIER
COATING ON THE TOP.
YOU WANT TO JUST
KINDA BARELY BE ABLE
TO SEE THE MEAT
THROUGH THE RUB.
NOW THOSE CAN GO DOWNTOWN.
YEP, THEY CAN.
WOW, THOSE LOOK FANTASTIC.
LOOK AT THAT NICE SMOKE RING.
NOT TOO MUCH SMOKE.
IT COMES OFF THE BONE CLEAN,
BUT IT DOESN'T FALL OFF THE BONE
LIKE A PIT STEAM.
THEY'RE GOOD RIBS.
...WITH A CHOICE
OF SAUCE, TOO--
MEMPHIS-STYLE...
GOT A LITTLE BIT MORE MOLASSES,
A LITTLE MORE SUGAR,
A LITTLE BIT--A LITTLE
BIT SWEETER STYLE.
OR A WESTERN
NORTH CAROLINA SAUCE.
THEY'RE USING
A TOMATO-BASED SAUCE
THAT'S GOT A PRETTY HEALTHY
DOSE OF VINEGAR IN IT.
RIGHT.
SO IT'S TANGY...
AND THEN YOU GET
THAT BIG VINEGAR BITE.
BUT ALSO SWEET.
I THINK
IT'S GOTTA BE COCA-COLA.
IT IS.
HE'S NOT KIDDIN'. THE COKE
ADDS SWEETNESS AND FLAVOR.
NOW THIS IS THE ONE
PREP OVEN WE'VE GOT
IN THE WHOLE JOINT?
YES.
AND YOU PUT IT
IN THE BUSIEST SPOT?
DID I MENTION THAT THIS
IS OUR FIRST RESTAURANT?
THAT'S MY CAROLINA.
MMM. OH!
THE SAUCE IS
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
LOVE THE VINEGAR
IN THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
YOU'RE A CULINARY GUY.
THIS I COULD JUST DRINK...
LIKE A FINE WINE.
AND BARRY AND HIS CREW ARE
PAYING JUST AS MUCH ATTENTION
TO SCRATCH-COOKIN'
THEIR SIDE DISHES--
MAC 'N' CHEESE...
IT'S A MONEY
MAC 'N' CHEESE.
HOMEMADE SLAW AND BAKED BEANS
WITH A HALF TON OF EVERYTHING.
DONK.
THE SUGAR TO BEAN RATIO
IS ALMOST 50/50.
YEAH.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE,
A LITTLE BIT
OF LIQUID SMOKE,
A LITTLE YELLOW MUSTARD.
THIS WE KIND OF JUST
JAM TOGETHER.
THEN THE BEANS GET BEEFED UP
WITH SOME BRISKET...
SO IF YOU HAVE
A LITTLE BRISKET
THAT'S LEFT OVER
AT THE END OF THE DAY,
YOU GO AHEAD, CHOP IT UP,
PUT IT IN YOUR BEANS.
YEAH. YES.
GOOD CROSS UTILIZATION
OF PRODUCT...
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
MR. I'VE-NEVER-BEEN
IN-THE-RESTAURANT-BUSINESS-
AS-AN-OWNER-BEFORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SOME OF THAT WESTERN
CAROLINA BARBECUE SAUCE
AND SOME THICK-CUT ONIONS.
NOW YOU STIR?
YEP.
I'LL WATCH FROM OVER HERE.
YEAH.
TELL ME HOW
IT'S GOIN' FOR YA.
AND THE BEANS DON'T
GO STOVETOP.
THEY GET COOKED IN THE SMOKER.
LOOK AT THIS. LOOK. NICE.
ALL THAT SMOKE CARAMELIZED
ON TOP WITH THE SUGAR.
THAT'S MORE THAN A SIDE.
THAT'S LIKE A MEAL.
BIG FLAVOR.
...IN A JOINT FULL
OF BIG FLAVORS
FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY...
TEN!
A KIND OF BARBECUE FUSION
ALL DONE UP IN SMOKE.
I PROBABLY EAT HERE
ABOUT THREE TIMES A WEEK.
DON'T TELL MY WIFE.
AND I AM TELLING YOU
THE SOUFFLéS HERE--
THE TUNA FISH SOUFFLé
THEY DO IS TO DIE FOR.
OH, OKAY. PERFECT.
ORDER UP!
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HITTIN' A KANSAS JOINT
WHERE THEY'RE GOIN' WHOLE HOG.
THERE'S JUST FLAVOR
GALORE IN THERE.
SO HERE WE ARE ON THE LAST LEG
OF MY REAL-DEAL BARBECUE-ATHON
IN PAOLA, KANSAS,
ABOUT 40 MILES SOUTH
OF KANSAS CITY.
NOW A LOT OF FOLKS THINK OF THIS
AS CATTLE COUNTRY,
BUT YOU MIGHT CHANGE YOUR MIND
AFTER YOU TRY SOME OF THE TASTY
PORK AT THE BBQ SHACK.
ORDER UP!
FROM WHOLE HOGS...
MMM.
TO RACKS OF RIBS...
FANTASTIC.
IT'S GO BIG...
LOOK AT THAT!
OR GO HOME AT THIS JOINT.
JUST GET INTO IT?
YEAH.
AND YOU CAN EAT
THE WHOLE THING?
COME BACK IN AN HOUR.
ORDER UP!
IT WAS A BIG GAMBLE...
COME ON IN.
THAT PAID OFF BIG
FOR RICK SCHOENBERGER...
GOT THE BARBECUE DELIGHT
FLOWIN'.
TO DO BARBECUE, RIGHT.
WHO LEFT A CORPORATE JOB
TO TURN HIS HOBBY
INTO HIS BUSINESS.
NOW HE'S FIRIN' UP
THE MONSTER SMOKER...
FIGURE OUT WHAT YOU NEED
AND GET THE NEXT STEP BIGGER.
- CRANKIN' OUT THE CLASSICS...
- ORDER UP!
AND SOME SURPRISES,
LIKE CHICKEN WINGS
AND HOMEGROWN JALAPEÑO POPPERS.
AVEIGHT WRESTLERS
DOWN HERE TO GAIN WEIGHT.
AND IF YOU ORDER AHEAD,
HE REALLY WILL DO
AN ENTIRE HOG.
SO GOOD THAT YOU PUT SOME
OF TOP OF YOUR FOREHEAD
AND WATCH YOUR TONGUE BEAT YOUR
BRAINS OUT TRYIN' TO GET TO IT.
WATCH YOUR TONGUE BEAT YOUR
IT STARTS WITH
HIS HOMEMADE RUB.
EQUAL AMOUNTS
OF SUGAR AND SALT.
OKAY.
GROUND CELERY,
CHILI POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC...
SEASONED SALT.
SEASONED SALT,
A LITTLE GRANULATED ONION,
PAPRIKA,
SOME MUSTARD FLOUR...
DIG IT.
ALLSPICE...
GROUND CLOVE.
A LITTLE GROUND CLOVE--
THAT IS IT.
AND YOU JUST
SPRINKLE IT IN HERE.
NOW WE FLIP IT.
AND THEN RUB THE OLIVE
OIL ON THE SKIN.
NOW CLOSE IT UP?
YEAH.
DO THE SEAM ON TOP.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO
WHEN I'M NOT HERE?
I GOT A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO WORK FOR BEER.
OKAY, NOW IN?
YEAH.
I THINK I PULLED A HAMMY.
THIS IS GONNA GO ON
FOR HOURS, RIGHT?
IT GOES LOW AND SLOW ALL DAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE HE IS.
THERE'S A LOT
OF SKIN THERE...
YEAH.
BUT THERE'S NOT
A LOT BEHIND IT,
SO IT'S JUST BEEN
RENDERIN' DOWN.
PULL.
SO LET'S CRACK HER OPEN.
SO IT DIDN'T COOK
TOO FAST, TOO HOT
WHERE IT BURNT
THROUGH THE SKIN.
I MEAN, THAT ALMOST RENDERED
DOWN ALL THE FAT OUT OF THERE.
THE, UH, HAM IS JUST
FALLIN' APART BACK HERE.
IT'S JUST FALLIN' OFF.
ITS ALL COOKED
IN ITS OWN FAT...
OH, YEAH.
ITS OWN SKIN,
ITS OWN BONES,
SO THERE'S JUST FLAVOR
GALORE IN THERE.
MMM.
THAT'S HOW I'D LIKE
TO HAVE SOME PULLED PORK.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
MMM.
COME ON OVER
AND GET SOME, GUYS.
VERY TASTY.
YOU KNOW THAT I WAS INVOLVED IN
THE COOKING OF THIS, GENTLEMEN.
MAKE A RABBIT
HUG A HOUND.
WHAT WAS THAT?
MAKE A RABBIT
HUG A HOUND.
GOOD EATS. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
NICE STUFF.
ORDER UP!
AND WHILE THE WHOLE HOG
IS A SPECIAL ORDER,
RICK'S EVERYDAY MENU
IS KEEPIN' THE JOINT PACKED.
IT'S GOT THAT SMALL-TOWN
HOMEY FEEL TO IT.
HERE IN BARBECUE COUNTRY,
FOLKS CAN'T STOP RAVING
ABOUT HIS BRISKET...
HOW'S THE BRISKET?
REAL GOOD.
IT'S REAL TENDER.
IT'S GOT GOOD FLAVOR TO IT.
PUT THE RUB ON 'EM.
AND HIS RIBS.
THAT'S A LOT OF RIB.
HE WON'T TALK
WHILE HE'S EATING.
HE'S CRANKIN' OUT BURNT ENDS,
HOMEMADE SAUSAGE
AND EVEN LOADIN' THE SMOKER
WITH CHICKEN WINGS.
THAT'S A MESS OF WINGS.
THEY'RE GOOD.
THEY'RE THE BEST
CHICKEN WINGS AROUND.
MOST PEOPLE JUST TAKE 'EM,
FRY 'EM, SAUCE 'EM,
BUT YOU'RE GONNA
SEASON 'EM, SMOKE 'EM
AND FRY 'EM TO ORDER.
THEN WE DEEP-FRY
'EM TO ORDER.
WE'LL JUST TAKE SOME
OF THIS RUB,
DUMP RIGHT ON.
GET A LITTLE OF THIS?
NOW THIS IS THE SECRET KICKER?
THROW SOME OF THEM PEPPERS
IN THERE, TOO.
THE DRIED CHIPOTLES. SEE,
THERE'S DRIED SMOKED JALAPEÑOS.
YEAH.
THAT'LL PUT A NICE
LITTLE KICK ON IT.
YEAH.
HOW LONG THESE GO
IN THE SMOKER FOR?
PROBABLY A COUPLE HOURS.
REALLY?
YEAH.
A LOT OF WORK FOR
A CHICKEN WING, MAN.
YEAH, BUT IT SURE
TURNS OUT GOOD.
BUT YOU GOTTA PUT A...
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
JUST DROP THEM IN.
AND THEY'LL TAKE...
OH, MAYBE A MINUTE.
LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE READY.
BUT ALL THAT SEASONING
STILL STAYS ON?
YEAH.
YEAH, IT'S COOKED INTO 'EM
OUT THERE ON THE SMOKER.
YOU GET THAT SMOKE
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
YEAH.
WOW, THIS IS GOOD.
GOOD STUFF, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
I'M TELLING YOU
GOOD EATS.
AND AFTER THE WINGS,
RICK'S STILL GOT MORE TO SMOKE.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
HEAT MEETS HEAT.
THOSE WERE FRESH PEPPERS?
BROTHER, THAT'S WICKED.
AT THE BBQ SHACK
IN PAOLA, KANSAS...
I THINK IT'S THE BEST PLACE
IN PAOLA TO EAT.
IT'S JUST REAL FRIENDLY,
JUST THAT KIND OF ATMOSPHERE.
RICK SCHOENBERGER'S KEEPIN'
HIS MASSIVE SMOKER SMOKIN'
WITH EVERYTHING
FROM WHOLE HOG...
MMM.
TO RIBS...
FANTASTIC.
- TO BRISKET...
- IT'S REAL TENDER.
EVEN CHICKEN WINGS...
THEY'RE THE BEST
CHICKEN WINGS AROUND.
AND NOW JALAPEÑO POPPERS
THE WAY THEY WERE DONE
BEFORE THE CHAIN RESTAURANTS
GOT AHOLD OF 'EM.
WHERE DO ALL THE PEPPERS
COME FROM?
THESE PARTICULAR ONES
I GREW IN MY GARDEN.
WE ACTUALLY JUST CORE
THE SEEDS, THE INSIDES...
OKAY.
OF THE JALAPEÑO.
SO YOU TAKE THE TOP OFF.
YEP. CORE THE JALAPEÑOS
WITH THE CHILI TWISTER.
NOW TELL ME ABOUT
THIS CREAM CHEESE THING.
OKAY. TAKE JUST YOUR
STANDARD CREAM CHEESE
AND JUST SQUEEZE
A LITTLE BIT
INTO EACH ONE
OF THEM PEPPERS.
THAT ENOUGH?
YEAH, THAT'S PROBABLY GOOD.
WE'LL TAKE IT
A STEP FURTHER.
I USE A WATER CHESTNUT
MARINATED OVERNIGHT
IN A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR
AND SOME SOY SAUCE.
I HAVE SEEN SOME FUNNY THINGS
TO STUFF A PEPPER WITH,
BUT THIS MIGHT BE
THE TOP OF IT--
A WATER CHESTNUT.
AND THEN SOME MORE CHEESE?
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE READY
FOR THE BACON.
TRY TO GET YOUR
BEGINNING AND YOUR END
TO MEET IN THE SAME SPOT?
THAT'D BE A GOOD THING.
AND THEN GO RIGHT
THROUGH THE CENTER.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
SPRINKLE THE DRY RUB--
THE UNIVERSAL DRY RUB...
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
KINDA USE IT LIKE PAPRIKA
TO GIVE A LITTLE...
JUST DUST IT
AND ADD SOME COLOR.
NICE APPEARANCE, YEAH.
NOW THESE GO
IN THE BARBECUE.
YEP, RIGHT ON THE SMOKER.
LOOK AT THOSE.
THOSE ARE LIKE
MONDO POPPER.
I'VE HAD SMOKED BRIE.
I'VE HAD SMOKED MOZZARELLA.
BUT SMOKED CREAM CHEESE?
BROTHER, THAT'S WICKED HOT.
IT IS.
I MEAN, GREAT FLAVOR.
...LIKE EVERYTHING
RICK'S ROLLIN' OUT.
BUT IT'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY GOOD.
IT REALLY IS THE REAL DEAL,
THE RUB, THE SMOKE
ALL DONE LOW AND SLOW.
AND IT'S THE SAME EVERY TIME--
WONDERFUL.
I'VE HAD EVERYTHING.
YOU HAVE?
YOU'VE RUN THE MENU?
I EAT HERE A LOT.
OUT GOES THE OLD THEORY OF
COOKIN' 'EM COOLS 'EM DOWN, HUH?
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
THE SEEDS IN PEPPERS
ARE HOT. WOW!
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
LET'S SEE, GUY.
OH, MAN, WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT. HOLD IT,
HOLD IT, JOAN. OH!
THERE YOU GO.
YOU'RE ALL SET.
THERE YOU GO. THERE.
OH, YEAH, YOU'RE
LAUGHIN' BACK THERE.