Hey, I'm guy fieri.
And you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun!
I'm on my way to flavortown.
This is
"diners, drive-ins & dives."
This trip...
Whoa!
...We're bringing the meats...
Where's that been
all my day?
...From bratwurst
to pork belly...
That right there --
that's the real deal.
...Like at a bomb brew pub
in washington state...
Out of bounds, bro.
...A not-your-everyday
asian spot in atlanta...
So, you just do
whatever you want.
...And in vancouver...
Boom!
...A throwback diner...
That's a game-changer.
...Packing a culinary punch.
I haven't had meatloaf like that
in quite awhile.
I've never had meatloaf
like that in my life!
That's all right here,
right now,
On "diners, drive-ins & dives."
So, we're here
in vancouver.
I'm with my buddy chad
from nickelback.
And we're here
to check out a --
Let me do it.
-Do what?
-Intro the show.
No, no, you don't have
any experience in doing this.
I got a demo.
While I was in japan,
I shot a demo.
You got to stop in.
It's right here
at my favorite spot...
All right,
you can do the intro.
All right!
Well, here we are
in my backyard --
Vancouver,
british columbia, canada.
And when you're looking
for diners,
You're gonna look
for a little authenticity.
You're gonna want something
farm-to-table.
Now, there's some people here
in town that are doing it
So well,
they mashed the two together,
And they called it
fable diner.
I've got job-security
issues.
French toast in the window.
Fable diner is like casual
comfort food with a punch.
Pulled-pork sandwich here.
This is a really cool diner.
It harkens back
to the good old days.
Which is exactly why
ron macgillivray
Bought the joint.
It has been a diner
since like, 1920.
It feels --
it's got that...
-Authenticity.
-Thank you.
See?
That's why you write the songs.
That's --
I'm here for one word.
But chef josef driemel
Isn't going old-school
with the menu.
They're doing things that
normal diners don't do,
Like a roasted duck pancake
with kimchi.
Got a duck pancake for table 12.
I love the duck pancake.
It's got a kick from the kimchi.
It's something
that you would never think
To put on top of a pancake.
So, we're gonna make
our pancake batter.
Rock 'n' roll it.
Flour, cornmeal,
brown sugar, white sugar.
Got a good mix.
Salt, baking powder,
baking soda.
Baking soda.
Next?
We've got our
wet ingredients here --
Eggs, grapeseed oil,
honey, buttermilk.
So, wet and dry
are done.
Bring them together.
Pancake will be ready to go.
Now we go to the duck?
Salt them,
air dry them overnight.
Roast this off
how long, what temp?
About 77 degrees
celsius.
Sorry.
Like, 185 fahrenheit?
I don't know.
Converting on the fly.
That's impressive.
I do not know
if that was correct.
-170.6 fahrenheit.
-170.6.
I mean, so really low
and slow for 12 hours.
And what do we have
after this?
Our kimchi.
Napa cabbage --
Let it sit in saltwater
two to three hours.
Pull a little bit of
the moisture out of the cabbage,
And then we'll make
the kimchi base.
Exactly.
Fish sauce.
Ginger, garlic.
White onions,
salt, sugar...
There we go.
...Gochujang...
Oh, this is
one of my faves.
...Dried korean
chili flakes.
You developed this recipe,
chef?
No.
A korean friend of mine --
This is his grandmother's
recipe.
Does your friend's
grandmother know
That you're using
her recipe?
I'm not sure if she knows,
but he knows for sure.
Throw it on top
of this cabbage.
-Kaboom.
-Sliced daikon.
Green onions and chives.
-Okay.
We'll let this ferment
three to five days.
Ducks are roasted off,
shred those, build the dish.
Chad's hungry.
-I can see it.
-It's his first day on the job.
Got our pancake on.
Nice heated duck.
Little hoisin glaze,
Some caramelized ginger
and garlic in there.
Got our pancake here.
Just go in with the duck.
We'll hit it
with the kimchi,
Japanese mayo,
green onions.
This is getting serious.
This is really taking
another step.
We call this
crispy business --
Crispy fried shallots,
puffed rice,
And little sesame seeds.
Where's that been
all my day?
--little cilantro.
There you go.
The key, I think,
is going to be getting...
The whole shebang.
-Whoa!
-Coming in.
How'd you do that?
That's a lot of stuff
going on there.
That's really good.
The kimchi is spot-on.
The fish-sauce funk
is coming through.
The duck's got great flavor,
good texture.
Great scratch-made pancake.
The fact that you can
come into an everyday diner
And you could get that --
that's a game-changer.
-Can I eat more of this now?
-Please. Get after it.
Roast-duck pancake
for you.
-That's a go-to?
-Absolutely.
Duck mixed with the kimchi --
it's awesome.
And that's some
real-deal kimchi.
It's just a great,
unexpected dish.
With that little bit
of meat on top of the pancake,
It can do for breakfast, and
you can also have it for dinner.
Loaded french toast
for you.
It's just a good, comfy spot.
They've captured the ambiance
of that old diner to a "t."
-How about the milkshakes?
-Amazing.
-Perfect.
-Add a little booze to them.
You can get booze
in this place?
-Oh, yeah.
-You can get boozy milkshakes.
We're gonna need to go back
to the kitchen real quick.
Where there's plenty more
to dig into.
Saucing the meatloaf.
The meatloaf is excellent.
It's way better than my mom's.
So, break us
into meatloaf.
Just gonna start off
with our veg mix.
Just a little grapeseed oil,
some cremini mushrooms,
Carrots next,
shallots, minced garlic.
Sweat all the veggies
down.
We've got sweet smoked paprika,
nutmeg, black pepper,
And just some kosher salt.
Worcestershire, some of
our housemade barbecue sauce.
So that's the veg done.
So, I make a panade.
-Very key.
-Eggs.
-Local organic?
-Of course.
-Salt.
-It's farm-to-table.
Farm-to-table.
Thank you, again.
I should have listened
to your intro.
We're going over
heavy cream now.
Bringing moisture
to the game.
Stale sourdough ends.
"stale," isn't
a real happy word.
some aged sourdough ends.
Put this in the blender.
Grab 50/50
ground-beef pork.
Lightly incorporate
the sweated veg with the panade.
Ah.
Throw it into a bread pan
and pop her in the oven.
Takes about
2 1/2 hours.
-At?
-120 degrees celsius.
Fantastic.
5,000 degrees.
Show me how to make this gravy,
'cause I'm excited.
-Butter down.
-Onions and celery.
-Salt.
-Bay leaf, peppercorn.
Couple sprigs of rosemary.
Thyme.
Building our base.
-Oh!
-Not too bad, eh?
-Smells good.
-We go in with our flour.
Duck stock.
Use all the bones
from the roasted duck.
Ah.
So, once it's cooked down
for about 30 minutes,
We're gonna go in
with our sherry vinegar
And just some
grainy dijon mustard.
This is gonna be
rockstar flavor.
Cut up our meatloaf here.
Lay it down on the flattop.
Get a little bit of color
on each side.
Gravy, smoked mushrooms,
caramelized onion.
Mark our plate with
a little carrot purée.
Definitely a little
elevated diner here, buddy.
Piping bag full of mash,
fresh veg.
Meatloaf coming in hot.
Nice little
caramelization.
-Got our gravy.
-The secret is in the sauce.
Buttermilk-fried onions.
That's kind of
an old-school move.
Little...
Blue-cheese butter.
-Come on!
-That's about it.
- Oh.
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh, oh.
-You didn't like it.
-Oh, my god. That's good!
The meatloaf is tender,
the mushroom gravy --
Great complement.
That pickled mustard seed
you added right there...
-Add a little pop.
-That's the pop, yep.
Great fried onions.
And then go get a little touch
of the blue-cheese butter.
-Mm-hmm.
-We are destroying this thing.
Oh!
I haven't had meatloaf like that
in quite a while.
I've never had meatloaf
like that in my life!
-Really?
-Never.
Fantastic.
Meatloaf for 17.
Service, please.
It's hearty, filling.
The mushroom gravy on it
is so delicious.
-Are you a meatloaf guy?
-I am here.
Chicken and grits for table 2.
It's really good comfort food,
but done with high quality.
You get something you wouldn't
expect anywhere else.
You can say a lot
of things on the menu,
But it's what you deliver
on the plate
That makes
all the difference,
And, my friend,
you delivered.
The next time I'm cruising
through vancouver
And I got some friends
in the car...
Yeah.
...I'm just gonna
let them know
We're stopping by
fable diner.
Huh?
-See ya. Buh-bye.
He opened the show,
closed the show.
-Boom!
-See you later.
-We're out!
Up next, an outrageous
asian joint in atlanta...
Get that funk and skunk.
...Stacking up powerhouse
pork belly...
That was
a great sandwich.
...And firing up
off-the-chain chicken.
I don't know whether
to attack it
Or take a picture of it.
You got to love america --
home of mom-and-pop joints,
And that's where
a lot of immigrants
Started to work
when they came to this country.
That's been going on
for hundreds of years.
So, here we are
in atlanta, georgia,
And we have just that story.
A young immigrant from
south korea at the age of 14
Comes to the united states,
finds adversity,
But battles through it and is
living the american dream.
This is pijiu belly.
Spicy dumpling and walnut.
Pijiu belly's been one of
our favorite spots to come to.
They do a really good
asian fusion.
...Udon stir fry.
It's just different.
You don't find it anywhere
like this in atlanta.
'cause lenny and lili shou
Aren't your typical
southern belles.
Born and raised in south korea
to chinese parents,
The siblings eventually
came to school in the u.S.
You're in college
in indiana?
-For one year.
-Then your father passed away.
I had to go make a living
at the chinese restaurant.
And six years later,
He and his sister
opened their own joint
With a menu
that's all over the map.
I have a burger,
ramen noodle,
Whatever in between.
So, you just do
whatever you want.
Pork belly with kimchi.
His pork belly is beautiful.
I mean, it's the sweetest meat.
And you have that nice
peach hoisin sauce on top.
You have korean and you have
georgia and the south
All in one sandwich.
What are we gonna make
today, chef?
Our crispy pork belly
sandwich.
Trim the pork belly down.
Season it with
a garlic-pepper seasoning...
Okay.
...Overnight,
and then we pan sear each side
For about 10 minutes.
Next step?
We're gonna mix up
the five spice...
So, you're gonna make
your own chinese five spice?
-Yes, I do.
-Okay.
Salt, dry red pepper,
szechuan peppercorn,
Star anise, and cloves.
And then here's your part.
Make you work.
Nice talking to you, chef.
I'll see you in a bit.
I saw that boat coming in
to port, buddy.
It is work, but the aroma
it give is unmatched.
Next?
Carrots, onions, celery,
and then a daikon.
Daikon radish?
Just give a nice
little coating.
Half-hour show, chef.
You put the spices in
and the shochu wine.
You put
the pork belly back.
Cover it with foil,
three hours in the oven,
Bring it out,
slice it into pieces,
Fry it, and serve it
with what kind of sauce?
Peach hoisin sauce.
peach hoisin sauce.
Peaches.
Just give a little blend.
Sugar.
You sure that's not
too sweet?
Never.
Think it needs more sugar?
- No more sugar.
-What's the final step?
-Easy-make kimchi.
-Yes.
Right here
at easy-make pijiu belly.
Napa cabbage and red miso.
Chili son bao?
Minced garlic, ginger,
shredded daikon, carrots.
-Korean chili flake?
-The clay pot.
Oh, you're gonna put it
in the clay pot?
Oh, yeah.
How long are we gonna
let this go for?
One week.
Oh, you're really gonna
let it ferment.
-Yes.
-Get that funk and skunk.
And now we're gonna
build a sandwich.
Kimchi, peach hoisin sauce,
pork belly.
Look how tender that is.
That's pork belly
chinatown.
That's right on.
Peach hoisin sauce.
I just want this
by itself.
That was
a great sandwich.
The peach sauce reminds me
of plum sauce.
It's not too sweet.
The pork's tender.
It's unctuous.
I don't know how to spell
that word.
Okay.
The kimchi is bright,
crunchy, funky.
That right there --
that's the real deal.
Pork belly with kimchi.
Pork belly -- oh, my god.
The sweet sauce sort of offset
The robustness
of the pork itself.
The kimchi is so good.
It's nothing I've had
on other burgers around town.
Couple of my buddies here --
They play professional
table tennis.
That's what you guys play,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
football maybe, too.
I am a huge fan
of pork belly.
The texture, the crunchiness,
the flavor -- it's unmatched.
It's really good.
That's a pretty good
description.
Yeah.
He's an experienced eater,
as you can tell.
-Yeah, right.
-Combo dukboki.
Pijiu belly's great.
They've got stuff that you can't
find at the pub down the street.
And what does
the name mean?
"pijiu" in mandarin
means "beer."
So it's a beer belly.
Beer belly --
you have to have great beer.
They keep a rotating beer menu
on tap,
So I can always try
something different.
What else can you do?
How about some
korean yangnyeom chicken?
That's just what
I was thinking.
Yangnyeom chicken's great.
The sauce is not like any other
sauce that I've ever had.
It's just packed full of flavor.
You got to come back
for this.
See you in a bit.
4, 3, 2, hit it.
We are here at
pijiu belly,
Atlanta, georgia.
I forgot everything you said.
-No, you did good.
You scared me,
but it was a great intro.
So, we're at pijiu belly,
And chef lenny is
just crushing it.
They found a really nice blend
of traditional korean foods
With foods that you'd find
in a gastropub.
-If I'm hungry I come here.
-It's a good place.
It is exceptional.
And now what are we making,
chef?
Yangnyeom chicken.
The sauce on this chicken has
that perfect blend of spice.
Even though it's covered
in a lot of sauce,
It's still very crispy.
That goes perfect
for selling beer.
Absolutely.
You sell a lot of beer here,
don't you?
-We sure do.
-"we sure do."
All of a sudden you talk
like you're from atlanta.
"we sure do."
so, we got whole roasters...
Rotisserie seasoning,
kosher salt.
Korean chili flake.
Rub this over the chicken.
-Right.
-This excalibur?
Skewer it up.
And how long will this roast?
For two hours,
500 degree.
And are we gonna make
the yangnyeom sauce?
-Yes, we are.
-Fantastic.
We have ketchup, black pepper,
dried chili,
Korean chili pepper,
good ol' soy sauce.
"good ol'."
White vinegar, sriracha,
minced garlic,
Granulated garlic,
sugar.
You and your sugar.
Corn syrup, cola,
the gochujang.
That's a lot of gochujang.
Next up?
-The chicken -- chop them up.
-What's our mix?
Corn starch and flour
and rice flour.
Drop in the fryer.
-Fire up the wok.
-Yangnyeom sauce.
Reducing it a bit
and just making it sticky
To coat the chicken.
Toasty sesame seeds.
I don't know whether
to attack it
Or take a picture of it.
That is dangerous, bro.
okay.
You've got great crisp
on the little bit of batter
That you put
on the outside.
The sauce is tangy...
And sweet, with just
a little bit of heat.
That's dynamite.
Excellent job.
-Yangnyeom chicken.
-The sauce is very elevated.
Perfect sweetness,
perfect spiciness.
Kung pao ramen.
Lenny and lili
are just amazing.
They're kind of like
another family to us.
She has had
her rehearsal dinner here.
I had
my 60th birthday here.
Come on.
Everything I've ever
ordered has been amazing,
And I can say that
wholeheartedly.
I really like your story.
You're super-enthusiastic
about everything you do.
What are we doing?
What's going on?
You gonna bring it in?
I'm bringing it.
Bring it in.
There you go.
Come on down
to pijiu belly
And try some
of the yangnyeom chicken
And the pork belly
and have lots of beer, too.
See you here.
Adios.
Coming up,
in kennewick, washington...
That's legit.
...A joint known
for their beer...
They go above and beyond,
right?
...But making a mark
with their menu.
That right there gets
all the respect.
It's been taking your dad
like half an hour.
Let me just see.
The kid's a pro!
'kay, how much should you
be paid for this?
-75.
-75 cents -- you got it.
Got top love
the great northwest --
Known for so many things,
and one in particular is beer --
I mean, in every way,
shape, or form.
So I'm in tri-cities,
washington,
Where this joint was --
well, it was a sport's bar,
Then it was a comedy club,
And now a husband-and-wife team
have come together,
And they're serving up beer.
It's like an epicenter of beer
backed up
With some real-deal barbecue
and some scratch-made sausages.
This is barley's brew hub.
Got another brat
on the flattop!
The food is fabulous.
-Pulled-pork sandwich.
-Always made fresh.
Goes great with all their beers.
This is like
a gigantic dorm room
Of beer signs
and handles.
Who's the curator?
Who's the sommelier
of the beer here?
Me.
-That's you?
-Yeah.
Where did the food
come into play?
I didn't want
the basic bar-pub menu,
So we're smoking our meats.
And tom and shari floyd
are going beyond the basic.
Chicken gyro sausage!
Normally gyros are made
with lamb.
Here they use chicken bratwurst.
I've never found that
anywhere before.
We're making
the chicken gyro sausage?
Correct.
All right, let's see it,
captain.
Bacon...
Boneless, skinless
chicken thighs,
Kosher salt, ground oregano,
slightly ground thyme.
Is there an attachment
for "slightly ground"?
Course basil,
chopped baby spinach,
Feta cheese.
Don't forgeta the feta.
Kalamata brine,
dry milk.
The dry milk is the key.
-It retains moisture...
-Yeah.
...And it's
a protein binder.
And beer.
I use a kolsch yeast.
That's top fermenting,
And then when they chill it,
it drops to the bottom,
And it's
a bottom-fermenting yeast.
So it's kind of
a different yeast,
And that's what
makes it unique.
Koooom!
Right over my head.
So we're gonna use
a synthetic casing.
21 inches.
This is gonna cook
in the oven at what temp?
300 for about
10, 15 minutes.
And we gonna give
a little tzatziki sauce?
You bet.
Greek yogurt,
fresh garlic,
Ground black pepper,
salt, dill....
That's big dill.
...Lemon zest
and lemon juice,
Fresh mint,
english cucumber.
Okay, are we gonna
make this dish?
Just came out of the oven.
'course, we have to...
Right, right, right.
One for the homies.
For the little bit of beer
that we put in there,
I definitely get it.
Get some lines on it.
Pita bread.
-Lettuce, tzatziki sauce.
-Tomatoes.
-Red onions.
Feta cheese.
And that's all
she wrote.
A gyro out of chicken and bacon
is a big risk.
I did it,
and it's doing good.
I don't know that "good"
would be
The term that I would use.
I think fantastic.
From the grind
to the ingredients --
Nothing is
too heavy-handed in it --
With a really nice pita
that's nice and soft,
A really clean tzatziki.
What beer would you
recommend with this?
An I.P.A.
-That's your go-to?
-That's me.
Out of bounds, bro.
The chicken gyro sausage
is perfectly cooked.
It's juicy,
and it's got a great bite.
The tzatziki really highlights
the meat.
But what really matters
at this joint
Is how the flavors
highlight the beer.
Usually the server
will pair beer with your food.
They'll help you find something
that you enjoy drinking.
I expected with the beer
being such the focus,
The food would be good.
But they go
above and beyond, right?
-That's why we come back.
-That's the best part.
Brats on the sharp!
You can't go wrong
with anything here.
I loved their smoked brat.
Chili on the brat!
The brat is great and just goes
perfectly with the chili.
It tastes like heaven.
Starts with
the chili paste --
New mexico chilies,
california chilies.
-Pasilla?
-Water.
-A little beer -- I.P.A.?
-No.
He said I.P.A.
Went with everything.
Not when you're cooking.
I.P.A.S make things bitter.
So we're using
a scottish ale.
And a little bit
of tomato bouillon.
This is the foundation
of the chili?
-The secret ingredient.
-Secret ingredient?
-It's not a secret anymore.
-I won't tell anybody.
We are now doing the chili --
rendered bacon and onions.
-Ground beef.
-House-made chorizo.
So, this is all getting
a pre-cook before it goes in.
Ground thyme, ground oregano,
table ground salt,
Fresh-ground
black pepper.
-Cumin?
-Fresh toasted and fresh ground.
-Nice. I like it.
-It really makes a difference.
Chili powder.
Garlic powder.
Fresh-squeezed lime.
Tomato sauce.
Sriracha.
Worcestershire.
Scottish ale?
-This is a scottish.
-Ah, see? I'm catching on.
Crushed green chilies.
The secret chili paste.
Yeah.
No new mexico, california,
or pasillas?
Nothing.
Ground tomatoes
with roasted chilies,
And some water.
Red kidney beans.
Black beans.
Garbanzo.
Chicks.
Pinto beans.
You let it cook
for four hours.
The chili cheese brat.
This is the chili part.
Oh, now you're doing
dance routines?
Yeah.
Just let me see it again
one more time.
Chili cheese brat.
This is the chili.
We got the chili.
Next is coming the...
-Brat.
-Got it.
Fresh-ground pork butt,
Coarse-ground mustard seed,
Sage,
fresh-ground cumin,
Ground black pepper,
salt, onion powder,
Granulated garlic,
nutmeg, and mace.
We're gonna mix this up.
Milk protein
and a german pilsner...
-There you go.
-...'cause it is a brat.
-Case this?
-Yes.
This goes on the smoker
Until the internal
temperature's 165.
We take
our locally baked roll.
-Smoked bratwurst.
-House chili.
Cheese sauce.
-Green onions.
-Shredded cheese.
-What's the white sauce?
Cilantro-lime
sour cream.
That's it.
Great texture.
Little smoke.
Dynamite chili.
Chili dogs don't get the respect
that they used to.
That right there gets
all the respect.
Scratch-meat ingredients,
cheese,
A little
fresh green onion --
That whole little
package deal.
You're running a beer hub,
And you want to be recognized
for your food.
That's legit.
-Cheese on brat!
-It's a good smoked brat.
One of the best I've had.
The chili is very layered,
has good depth to it.
Little bit of heat,
but nothing too spicy.
Two game changers.
Food's good. Drinks are good.
You can't really go wrong.
Doesn't say "barbecue house"
out there.
It said "brew hub."
that's what
we're going for.
This isn't playing
second fiddle.
This is right there
up front.
Delicious.
Nice job, chef.
So, that wraps this edition
of "diners, drive ins & dives".
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
Go to foodnetwork.Com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
On "diners, drive ins & dives".
12-hour duck cooked
low and slow.
-Somebody just stole your car.
-Take my car?
You didn't leave the keys
in it, did you?
I think I left the keys
in your car.