Y, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
HEY, SWEETIE,
HOW YOU DOING?
THIS TRIP...
HERE'S YOUR TENDERLOIN DINNER.
LIKE MAMA MADE.
MM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
YEAH.
LEGENDARY SOUL FOOD
IN ST. LOUIS...
THE CHICKEN, THE RIBS,
THE PORK CHOP,
THE MACARONI AND CHEESE--
I MEAN, IT'S EVERYTHING.
DISHED UP BY A FORMER SINGER.
I PUT DOWN THE MIC
AND PICKED UP A POT.
IN A PHOENIX GAS STATION,
A MEXICAN RESTAURANT.
WE JUST STOPPED BY
TO GET GAS,
AND WE SMELLED
MEXICAN FOOD.
AND IT'S ALL HOMEMADE
FROM MAMA'S RECIPES.
SHE'S 75 YEARS OLD, AND SHE'S
STILL MAKING TAMALES.
AND THE KENTUCKY TRUCK STOP...
IT'S THE BEST THAT YOU CAN FIND
AROUND THIS COUNTRY HERE.
WHERE'S MAMA'S
COUNTRY COOKIN'...
GOOD GRAVY, GIRL--
JUST LIKE MAMA WOULD MAKE.
HAS EVERYBODY COMING BACK
FOR MORE.
THEY MAKE THE BEST IN TOWN.
YOU GAVE ME TOO MUCH.
WELL, THAT'S BETTER
THAN NOT ENOUGH, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
Closed Captions provided
by Scripps Networks, LLC.
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
WHEN YOU THINK OF SOUTHERN FOOD,
YOU KNOW, FRIED CHICKEN,
MAC AND CHEESE, COLLARD GREENS,
THE QUESTION COMES TO MIND
WHEN DOES SOUTHERN FOOD
TURN INTO SOUL FOOD.
HERE AT A PLACE CALLED
SWEETIE PIE'S IN ST. LOUIS,
PEOPLE TELL ME
IT'S ALL IN THE HEART
OF THE FOLKS WHO ARE MAKING IT.
DEFINITELY A LOT
OF LOVE GOING INTO IT.
HEY, SWEETIE,
HOW YOU DOING?
YOU GOTTA PUT SOME LOVE
IN THERE, SERIOUSLY.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
THIS CHICKEN
IS MADE WITH LOVE.
IS EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT OVER HERE?
AND THE WOMAN DISHING OUT
THE LOVE IS ROBBIE MONTGOMERY.
SHE'S BEEN SERVING SOUL FOOD
TO ST. LOUIS SINCE '97.
THE CHICKEN, THE FISH
AND THE RIBS,
THE PORK CHOPS,
THE MACARONI AND CHEESE--
I MEAN, IT'S EVERYTHING.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE
THING TO GET HERE?
THIS RIGHT HERE.
THIS.
DEFINITELY THE MACARONI
AND CHEESE IS MY FAVORITE.
IT'S PROBABLY THE BEST
MAC AND CHEESE I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU WANT GREENS, TOO?
DRESSING AND GREENS.
GOOD TEXTURE, CRISP.
SWEET POTATOES.
I HAVE
THE BAKED CHICKEN.
CHICKEN CHICKEN.
IT'S SO TENDER.
SEE HOW IT'S FALLING
OFF THE BONE?
THE FRIED CHICKEN REMINDS ME
OF MY GRANDMOTHER'S
AND THE CORNBREAD--THE WAY
SHE USED TO MAKE IT.
IT'S SO GOOD, YOU DON'T
NEED ANY BUTTER.
NOBODY COOKS LIKE
SWEETIE PIE, NOBODY.
NOBODY?
NOBODY.
I GOTTA GO SEE
ABOUT MY PORK STEAKS.
AND GET THIS.
IT'S READY.
ROBBIE DIDN'T START OUT
AS A CHEF.
OKAY, BOBBY, I NEED
MY TURKEY WINGS BACK IN.
SHE STARTED OUT AS A SINGER.
MET IKE
AND TINA TURNER...
HOW CRAZY IS THAT?
AND FROM THERE, I WENT
FROM THAT. THAT WAS CRAZY.
AND YOU USED
TO COOK ON THE ROAD.
YEAH, BECAUSE THINGS
WERE SEGREGATED,
AND WE WEREN'T ALLOWED
IN A LOT OF THE, YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER RESTAURANTS.
BUT WE HAD ELECTRIC SKILLETS,
AND WE WOULD COOK IN OUR ROOM.
SO WE GOT ONE, TWO, THREE.
YOU GOT THE NEXT PAN
OF CHICKEN READY?
AND AFTER ALMOST 40 YEARS,
SHE LEFT ONE STAGE
AND JUMPED UP ON ANOTHER.
PEACH COBBLER UP.
I PUT DOWN THE MIC
AND PICKED UP A POT.
ALL OF THESE RECIPES...
...ARE MY MOM'S.
ARE YOUR MOM'S WITH YOUR
ROBBIE SPIN ON IT.
EXACTLY.
'CAUSE I GOTTA BELIEVE THAT
THERE'S ALWAYS A ROBBIE SPIN.
IT IS, IT IS.
DURING MY TRAVELS,
I PICK UP LITTLE THINGS,
ADD 'EM,
LITTLE TIT-TATS AND STUFF
AND ADD IT TO MY RECIPE.
LIKE HER MACARONI AND CHEESE.
I'VE BEEN MAKING THIS
ABOUT 40 YEARS.
RIGHT OUT OF 8th GRADE?
OUT OF 8th GRADE,
EXACTLY.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE PASTA.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD 2 POUNDS
OF VELVEETA CHEESE.
NOTHING BUT VELVEETA.
NO IMITATIONS,
DON'T STOP NO PLACE ELSE.
DON'T GIVE ME IMITATION
IMITATION CHEESE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO THEN WE GOT
A POUND OF CHEDDAR.
COLBY AND JACK--
WE GOT A POUND OF THAT.
THEN NEXT WE'RE GONNA
ADD 2 HEAPING TABLESPOONS
OF SOUR CREAM.
AND JUST, SUNSHINE, SO YOU
KNOW, THAT'S NOT A TABLESPOON.
WELL, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S YOUR SPOON.
THAT'S MY TABLESPOON.
THEN WE'VE GOT
BUTTER AND MARGARINE,
SALT, PEPPER AND SUGAR...
FIVE EGGS. YOU CAN CRACK,
AND I'LL WHISK.
A MESS OF MILK.
AND HOW MUCH OF THAT?
JUST SOME?
YEAH, JUST SOME.
JUST SOME.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH THE FANCY MILD.
WHAT IS THIS--ABOUT
30 POUNDS, 25 POUNDS?
IT FEELS LIKE IT,
I TELL YOU.
IT'S A HEAVY PAN.
LOOK AT THE CRISPY CRUNCH
ON TOP OF THAT.
MM. MMM.
YOU HAVE MACARONI...
IT'S REAL.
THE PASTA'S REAL.
THE MIXTURE
OF THE CHEESES INSIDE.
THAT DOES ME PROUD
TO SEE YOU EATING IT
MORE THAN ONCE.
YOU GET ME A STOOL AND BIB,
I'LL BE HERE FOR ABOUT A DAY.
JUST LIKE MOM
COULDN'T MAKE.
JUST LIKE MAMA
IT MAKES YOU FEEL RIGHT.
EVERYONE TALKS
ABOUT SWEETIE PIE'S.
IT'S GREAT.
AND FOR ROBBIE,
WHAT MATTERS MOST
IS MAKING SURE EVERYONE'S
LOVIN' WHAT SHE'S SERVIN'.
I WANTED TO STILL
DEAL WITH THE PUBLIC.
OKAY, I'M GONNA
GO OUT HERE.
I GO OUT IN THE DINING ROOM,
MAKE SURE EVERYBODY'S HAPPY.
YOU LOOK GOOD, TOO.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT
WAS ME UP THERE, DID YA?
HERE YOU GO, BABY.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I LIKE THE SERVICE.
OKAY.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT
FOR YOU LADIES OVER HERE?
NOW HER SON TIM IS FOLLOWING
MOM INTO THE BUSINESS.
WE'RE GONNA CHANGE SPOTS.
THIS IS MY MOM'S DREAM.
I CAN'T LET MY MOM'S DREAM DIE,
NO MATTER WHAT.
AND THAT MEANS COOKING
FOR EVERYONE ELSE
THE WAY ROBBIE COOKED FOR HIM.
ALL I KNOW IS I'VE BEEN EATIN'
MOM'S COOKIN' BEFORE I WAS BORN,
YOU KNOW, SINCE
BEFORE I WAS BORN.
YEAH, YOU WERE, YEAH.
I LIKE IT, MAN.
ALL OF HIS FAVORITE RECIPES
DONE THE SAME AS ALWAYS,
LIKE ROBBIE'S
FAMOUS SMOTHERED PORK.
WE'RE GONNA FLOUR IT
AND FRY IT.
FRY IT?
FRY IT. AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA SMOTHER IT.
I THINK THE FRYING IT
WILL HAVE SMOTHERED IT.
BUT WE'RE GONNA KILL IT.
THIS IS OUR SPECIAL BLEND
SEASON SALT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GRANULATED GARLIC--
A LITTLE EXTRA.
PEPPER.
YOU JUST STACK 'EM UP IN THERE,
AND THEN THEY GO TO THE FRYER?
THEY GO TO THE DEEP
FRYER. EXACTLY.
IT'S LIKE
FRYING A PORK CHOP
IN YOUR HOT TUB.
EXACTLY.
BUT THAT LOOKS READY?
THAT LOOKS READY.
WHAT AM I PUTTING IT ON--
ONIONS AND WHAT?
ONIONS AND MY LITTLE
SPECIAL SEASONING.
AND YOUR LITTLE SPECIAL
"I'M NOT GONNA TELL YA."
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS GRAVY MADE
WITH THAT DARK ROUX.
DARK ROUX, RIGHT.
THAT'S IT.
AND THIS PROCESS JUST KEEPS
GOING ON ALL DAY LONG?
ALL DAY LONG.
COOKING AND MAKING
AND COOKING AND PUTTING IT
AND TAKING IT AND GOING
AND SERVING IT.
EXACTLY.
LOOK AT THE SIZE.
MMM.
OH-OH. OH-OH.
OH-OH-OH.
THE TEXTURE OF THE MEAT
AND THE FLAVOR
AND THEN THE DEEP RICHNESS
OF THAT ROUX, THAT GRAVY--
THAT'S SO GOOD.
OH, GREAT.
AND THEY JUST KEEP PACKING IN
FOR THE SMOTHERED PORK
AND EVERYTHING ELSE
ROBBIE'S MAKIN'.
TASTES LIKE FOOD YOU ATE
WHEN YOU WERE AT HOME?
JUST LIKE IT.
JUST LIKE IT?
MM-HMM.
AND YOU CAN KIND OF FEEL
THE FAMILY ATMOSPHERE HERE.
WING, WINGS. UH-HUH.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL
ALL THE TIME.
YOU KNOW WHAT? I GOT ONE
DISAPPOINTMENT, THOUGH.
I WISH I HAD AN EXTRA STOMACH
TO EAT SOME MORE FOOD.
THAT'S MY ONLY
DISAPPOINTMENT.
IT'S REALLY SOUL FOOD.
WHEN YOUR HEART'S IN IT
AND WHEN YOU BELIEVE IN IT
AND IT'S MORE
THAN JUST FOOD...
...THAT'S SOUL FOOD.
THEN IT'S SOUL FOOD.
THAT'S RIGHT,
FROM THE SOUL.
COMING UP...
THIS IS ABOUT THE CLOSEST THING
TO MOM'S COOKIN' I COULD GET.
A MEXICAN RESTAURANT WHERE
EVERYTHING'S DONE FRESH...
THAT'S A LOT OF JALAPEÑOS.
DONE RIGHT...
SO YOUR GRANDMOTHER
AND YOUR MOTHER
TAUGHT YOU HOW TO COOK?
YES.
AND DONE IN A GAS STATION.
I WANT TO BE
THE AMBASSADOR
TO CHIMICHANGA
FLAVOR TOWN.
THERE YOU GO.
THERE IT IS.
SO I'M CRUISIN'
THROUGH PHOENIX, ARIZONA.
TIME TO STOP AND GET
SOME FUEL FOR THE CAMARO
AND SOME FOR THE GUID.
NOW I KNOW YOU'RE SAYING
TO YOURSELF, COME ON,
THERE IS NO WAY HE
IS GOING INTO A GAS STATION
TO GET ONE OF THOSE FROZEN
MICROWAVED HAMBURGERS.
NOW PEOPLE AROUND THESE PARTS
SAY THIS IS SOME REAL-DEAL
FAMILY-MADE MEXICAN FOOD.
ACTUALLY, WE JUST
STOPPED BY TO GET GAS,
AND WE SMELLED THE SMELL
OF MEXICAN FOOD.
THIS VENTILATION IS DESIGNED--
IT GOES RIGHT OUTSIDE--
OH, YOU HAVE IT AIR-
DUCTED OUT TO EACH--
YEAH, WE GOT IT
RIGHT OUT THERE.
EVEN THOUGH
IT'S IN A GAS STATION,
THIS IS ACTUALLY
TRUE MEXICAN FOOD.
I WAS BORN AND RAISED IN MEXICO.
THIS IS THE CLOSEST TO MEXICAN
FOOD THAT I'VE TRIED
HERE IN THE STATES.
THIS IS ABOUT THE CLOSEST
THING TO MOM'S COOKIN'
I COULD GET.
WITH GOOD REASON.
I LEARNED HOW TO COOK
SINCE I WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
SO YOUR GRANDMOTHER AND YOUR
MOTHER TAUGHT YOU HOW TO COOK?
YEAH.
SHE'S 75 YEARS OLD, AND SHE'S
STILL MAKING TAMALES.
WE ALL MAKE
THE SAME RECIPE.
FOR MARIA ESTRADA
AND ROGER AMAYA...
NEED THOSE TACOS.
AND THEIR KIDS,
THIS REALLY IS HOME COOKIN'.
NACHO GRANDE.
YOU'RE MAKING FOOD
FROM SCRATCH.
OVER AND OVER ALL DAY.
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS MAKING A WHOLE BATCH
AND LETTING IT
SIT ALL DAY.
FROM CARNE ASADA TO MARINATED
PORK CALLED EL PASTOR
TO ENCHILADAS, CHILI RELLENOS,
A KILLER GREEN CHILI SAUCE...
ANYTHING THAT I'VE TRIED HERE,
LIKE THE TAQUITOS,
YOU KNOW, THE SALSA,
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND THE DEEP-FRIED
CHIMICHANGAS.
- ARE YOU      CHIMICHANGA-ED?
-  YEAH.
SHREDDED BEEF. I WANT
TO BE THE AMBASSADOR
TO CHIMICHANGA
FLAVOR TOWN.
THERE YOU GO.
THERE IT IS.
I WON'T GO AND SAY
THAT IT'S BETTER THAN MOM'S,
BECAUSE SHE'D KILL ME,
BUT, YES, IT'S VERY, VERY CLOSE.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE
AND FRESH MADE...
HOMEGROWN.
RIGHT HERE IN THE GAS STATION.
WE'VE BEEN HERE FOR
ABOUT NINE YEARS NOW.
NINE YEARS FROM A COLD START,
AND HERE YOU ARE?
MAKING THINGS HAPPEN.
AND WE'RE STILL HERE.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
THE CARNE ASADA'S JUST SO GOOD.
I CAN'T MAKE IT
AT HOME LIKE THIS,
SO WE HAVE TO COME HERE
TO HAVE IT.
GRILLED
AND MADE TO ORDER,
OR DO YOU SOMETIMES HAVE CARNE
ASADA STACKED UP AT LUNCHTIME?
NEVER, NEVER.
THAT'S THE KISS OF DEATH
RIGHT THERE. NO WAY.
WE COOK IT RIGHT ON THE GRILL,
TOP BROWNED.
A LITTLE AJO--
GRANULATED GARLIC.
A LITTLE
A LITTLE SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
SO THE SEASONINGS--
YOU DO IT TO EACH ORDER?
YOU SEASON TO EACH ORDER?
THAT'S IT.
MMM. IT'S SIMPLE,
BUT IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND CHECK OUT THIS
MEXICAN CLASSIC--EL PASTOR.
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE SEASONS HIMSELF.
MADE OF PORK MARINATED
IN RED CHILI, ONIONS, GARLIC,
VINEGAR AND PINEAPPLE.
PINEAPPLE?
PINEAPPLE. YOU'VE GOTTA HAVE
THAT LOVE AND TOUCH TO THIS.
I KNOW. OKAY.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S GOOD.
NOW IS THAT A NORMAL ORDER,
OR THAT LIKE A FAMILY PLATTER?
RIGHT THERE, THAT'S JUST
GONNA BE FOR A PLATE.
$6.95?
$6.95.
YOU KNOW WHAT? THEY'LL KEEP
COMING BACK MORE AND MORE.
EVENTUALLY YOU'LL GAIN A PROFIT
AFTER EVERY 30 CENTS YOU GET.
NOW DO YOU SIT THERE AND MESS
WITH IT THE WHOLE TIME?
I GIVE IT
A LOT OF ATTENTION.
I GIVE THIS THING
THAT WAY IT DOESN'T
GET COOKED ON ONE SIDE.
I JUST MAKE IT HAPPEN
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
TWO TORTILLAS.
MAKE THIS BAD BOY
INTO A TACO.
I ALWAYS LOVE WHEN
MY MEAT-TO-TORTILLA RATIO
IS ABOUT 90 TO 1.
SO THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
PUT SOME PICO ON HERE.
PICO DE GALLO.
OOH.
YOU CAN'T SAY
THE "OOH" FOR ME.
OKAY.
PINEAPPLE BROKE DOWN REALLY
NICE, HAD GREAT SWEETNESS.
I GOTTA TELL YA,
I'VE HAD SOME EL PASTOR.
SERIOUSLY, VERY GOOD.
YES!
THE SIDES THAT COME WITH IT
ARE ALL HOMEMADE, TOO.
THE BEANS ARE GREAT.
THEY'RE HOMEMADE.
THE RICE IS PERFECT.
AND THE PICO DE GALLO ON TOP--
THEY'RE MAKING THEIR OWN SALSA.
AND IT'S FRESH.
AND A KILLER GREEN CHILI SAUCE.
THAT'S A LOT
OF JALAPEÑOS.
IT'S A LOT
IT'S HOT.
THERE'S A LITTLE
BIT OF HEAT IN THERE.
IT'S JUST GOOD QUALITY.
THIS IS ALL HOME-COOKED
FOOD. IT'S REAL GOOD.
THIS IS REAL MEXICAN FOOD.
THIS AIN'T NO WRAPPED-UP
PROCESSED FOOD OR ANYTHING.
NOT WHEN THEY'RE
SERVING UP MENUDO,
A TRADITIONAL MEXICAN SOUP
MADE WITH COW'S FEET...
MM, MM.
AND TRIPE. THAT'S COW STOMACH.
DON'T WANT TO DO THAT.
WHOA.
THEY SAY THAT WHEN
YOU GET HANGOVERS,
THEY EAT MENUDO NEXT DAY.
MEXICAN GET-WELL SOUP.
BUT REALLY, THIS IS A STAPLE
IN MEXICAN FOOD?
YES.
IN HERE, THE TRIPE.
I GOTTA BE HONEST,
I'M SCARED
OF THE TRIPE.
I DON'T THINK I HAVE
A CONCERN WITH THE HOOF.
I PUT MY FOOT
IN MY MOUTH A LOT.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD AN ONION,
GARLIC--THE WHOLE THING--
AND THE WATER.
GONNA LET IT SIMMER
FOR HOW LONG?
IT TAKES HOURS.
REALLY COOK DOWN
SO EVERYTHING, EVEN THE BONES,
ALL THAT FLAVOR ALL COMING OUT
OF THE MARROW OF THE HOOF.
YES.
GUAJILLO PEPPERS.
PUREE THAT, AND THEN THAT'S
GONNA GO IN THE MENUDO.
NOW DRINK SOME OF IT,
STRAIN IT?
STRAIN IT.
AND NOW WE PUT
THE HOMINY IN?
NOW WE PUT THE HOMINY.
SO THIS IS BIG
GIGANTIC CORN?
SALT.
THAT'S READY TO GO.
WHERE DO YOU START?
ONE, TWO, THREE.
GREAT.
SOMETIMES
YOU JUST DON'T KNOW.
YOUR EYES ARE BIGGER
THAN YOUR STOMACH.
OKAY, I'M NOT A MENUDO GUY,
BUT IF YOU GREW UP LOVING IT,
THIS JOINT'S THE PLACE TO BE.
IT'S REAL CLOSE TO MY GRANDMA'S,
TO MY NANA'S AND MY MOM'S.
IT'S REAL CLOSE. VERY GOOD.
I LOVE IT.
JUST LIKE THE EL PASTOR.
IN THE WORLD OF EL PASTORS
THAT I'VE ENJOYED...
THIS IS IT.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE CARNE ASADA,
THE CHIMICHANGA...
MMM,
THAT SHREDDED BEEF, MAN.
REAL-DEAL HOME COOKIN'
LIKE MAMA USED TO MAKE
IF HER KITCHEN
WAS JUST PAST THE PUMPS.
MEXICAN RESTAURANT
IN A GAS STATION.
NICE JOB.
UP NEXT...
IT'S JUST GOOD EATIN'.
WE'RE HEADIN' FOR KENTUCKY...
IT'S GOOD COUNTRY FOOD
AND A GOOD COUNTRY ATMOSPHERE.
AT ANOTHER JOINT THAT STARTED
OUT COOKIN' WITH GAS.
THEY NUMBER ONE.
YOU DON'T SAY?
OH, YES, I DO SAY.
SO I'M PULLING OFF INTERSTATE 64
HERE IN KENTUCKY
TO A TRUCK STOP,
A TRUCK STOP I EXPECT
TO BE ABLE TO GET SOME FUEL.
BUT THEY TOOK THE PUMPS OUT
A FEW YEARS AGO.
SO WHY SO MANY CARS?
WELL, WORD IS AROUND HERE
THEY'RE MAKING ALL SORTS OF FOOD
LIKE MAMA USED TO MAKE.
TABLE ONE.
GRAVY AND BISCUITS.
IT'S JUST GOOD EATIN'.
ALWAYS THE BEST.
BRITNEY, YOU'RE UP.
HERE'S YOUR
TENDERLOIN DINNER.
IT DOESN'T STOP,
DOES IT?
NO.
DEEP-FRIED CHICKEN BREAST,
CATFISH.
BRING IT.
THEY NUMBER ONE.
YOU DON'T SAY?
OH, YES, I DO SAY.
A LOT LIKE MOM USED TO MAKE.
THAT'S THE WAY
JUANITA FLANNERY LEARNED
BEFORE SHE OPENED
THIS PLACE 29 YEARS AGO.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
AND JUST LIKE AT OUR LAST STOP,
FOLK HERE GOT USED TO FILLIN'
UP WHILE THEY WERE FILLIN' UP.
IT'S THE BEST THAT YOU CAN FIND
AROUND THIS COUNTRY HERE.
TILL JUANITA DECIDED THE GAS
PUMPS WERE TOO BIG A HASSLE
AND SHUT 'EM DOWN.
HAD WE KNOWN THAT IT WOULDN'T
HAVE AFFECTED THE RESTAURANT,
WE WOULD HAVE
A LONG TIME AGO.
...YOU WOULD HAVE
DONE IT A LONG TIME AGO.
IS IT BUSIER NOW THAN
WHEN IT WAS A TRUCK STOP?
OH, YEAH.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN WORKING HERE?
ALMOST 24 YEARS.
IT'LL BE 14 YEARS IN MAY.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE, PROBABLY,
EVER SINCE THEY'VE OPENED.
REALLY?
JUANITA AND I WENT
TO SCHOOL TOGETHER.
DEEP-FRIED
CHICKEN BREAST.
HOW DOES THIS STACK UP
TO HOW MOM USED TO MAKE IT?
IDENTICAL.
AND NOTHING SAYS
MAMA'S COUNTRY COOKIN'
LIKE JUANITA'S SPECIALTY.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
THEY MAKE
THE BEST IN TOWN.
AND SHE'S DOING IT
FROM A KITCHEN
THAT LOOKS MORE LIKE IT'S
IN A HOME THAN A RESTAURANT.
YOU KEEP THE EGGS
WHERE I KEEP MINE.
NOW WHERE DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO MAKE BISCUITS?
WHEN I WAS 12 YEARS OLD,
I WENT TO A BOARDING SCHOOL.
WE ALL HAD TO DO A TASK.
AND MINE WAS TO MAKE BISCUITS
FOR THE WHOLE SCHOOL.
AND MY GRANDMOTHER MADE 'EM
EVERY, EVERY MORNING.
OH, SO YOU'RE
A BISCUIT QUEEN THEN?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THAT.
THIS IS SELF-RISING FLOUR. IT
ALREADY HAS OUR BAKING POWDER.
THIS IS SHORTENING.
AND YOU WORK ALL THIS IN.
YOU TRY TO GET THOSE
GRANULES. HOW MUCH?
JUST POUR SLOWLY,
AND I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
GOOD POUR IS
THE PREREQUISITE IN BISCUITS
TO GET THE FLOUR
EVERYWHERE?
YES.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE IT
TO YOUR NOSE TO YOUR ELBOW,
YOU GOT ISSUES?
EVIDENTLY.
OKAY, GRAVY.
SHORTENING.
I'M GONNA GET THIS HOT.
AND LET'S
GET SOME FLOUR.
WE'RE GONNA START
THICKENING THIS UP.
THIS IS LIKE
A LITTLE ROUX HERE.
UH-HUH.
IT'S STARTING TO BROWN UP
A BIT ON THE BOTTOM.
OKAY, TURN IT DOWN
IF YOU WOULD, PLEASE.
AND I'M A GOOD STIRRER.
YOU ARE. YOU'RE VERY GOOD.
YOU STIR ALMOST
AS WELL AS YOU EAT.
AS I EAT?
OH, NO. I'M A CHAMPION.
I'M LIKE A PRO-BOWL CHAMPION.
YOU FOLD IN A LITTLE BIT
OF FLOUR SO IT'S MANAGEABLE.
THOSE ARE SOME THICK UN'S.
AND YOU SPOON ON A LITTLE
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
THIS IS SHORTENING.
WHOO, THAT'S A NEW WAY
FOR BISCUITS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT MUCH
SHORTENING GO ON. I LIKE IT.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
THE BISCUITS TO COOK?
ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
SAUSAGE GOES DOWN
INTO THAT.
IF YOU PUT THE SAUSAGE IN
RIGHT AWAY, IT GETS TOO HOT.
KEEP GOING UNTIL I HOLLER.
OKAY, STOP.
HOLLER THEN.
AAH.
THAT WASN'T A HOLLER.
THAT WAS A SQUAWK.
OH, LOOK AT THOSE.
OW!
THEY'RE HOT.
AND LADLE ON? IS THAT
THE RIGHT RATIO?
I'D GIVE MYSELF A LITTLE
MORE IF I WERE YOU,
UNLESS YOU'RE NOT HUNGRY.
NO, I'M ALWAYS HUNGRY.
MM. THAT WOULD MAKE YOU
WARM IN THE WINTER.
THE BISCUIT IS SO FLAKY
THAT WHEN IT
GETS IN MY MOUTH,
IT ALMOST
JUST FALLS APART.
WELL, YOU KNOW
IT'S GOOD GRAVY
WHEN THE FIRST BITE
THAT YOU GET
HAS A BIG OLD PIECE
OF SAUSAGE IN IT,
AND IT'S NOT JUST TEASING YOU
WITH SAUSAGE FLAVOR INSIDE.
MM.
IT'S HOT, ISN'T IT?
THAT'S GOOD GRAVY, GIRL.
JUST LIKE MAMA WOULD MAKE.
HARD TO BEAT.
I'D EAT 'EM
THREE TIMES A DAY.
'CAUSE AFTER BREAKFAST,
YOU CAN GET 'EM
WITH ANYTHING ELSE ON THE MENU.
IT'S GOOD COUNTRY FOOD
AND A GOOD COUNTRY ATMOSPHERE.
WHICH MAKES THIS
EVERYBODY'S GO-TO KITCHEN.
WE'RE DOWN TO 90 TICKETS.
RIGHT BEHIND.
THANK YOU, SWEETIE.
THIS IS LIKE
A CULINARY BALLET.
I'M IN THE WAY.
Y'ALL BEEN HERE BEFORE?
YES.
OH, YEAH.
EVERY DAY. SERIOUSLY, WE DO.
WE COME EVERY DAY.
I CAN NOT BELIEVE YOU TURN OUT
THIS VOLUME OF FOOD THAT QUICK.
CRANKIN' OUT COUNTRY CLASSIC...
I'VE GOT SOME BAKED STEAK,
MASHED POTATOES, GREEN BEANS.
AND LOCAL FAVORITES.
THEIR SMOKY BURGERS--
THEY'RE HUGE.
YOU GONNA BE ABLE
TO FIT THAT?
I'M GONNA TRY.
HOMEMADE HAMBURGER WITH ITALIAN
SEASONINGS IN THE BURGER--
IT'S VERY GOOD.
AND IF YOU'RE GOING
FOR A HOT DOG...
TO EXPECT IT TO COME
WITH MEAT SAUCE ON TOP.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY WE EAT
HOT DOGS AROUND HERE.
IT'S A LEAN BURGER.
85/15?
MM-HMM. I WILL
PUT SOME ONIONS IN.
NOW WHERE YOU'D LEARN
HOW TO MAKE THIS ONE?
JUST IN MY HEAD.
NOW WHAT STARTS GOING IN?
SOME SALT.
A LITTLE TICKLE.
SOME GARLIC.
THAT'S CHILI POWDER.
UH-HUH.
THIS IS SOME KETCHUP
AND TOMATO SAUCE.
IT LOOKS LIKE IT'S GOT
SOME SPICE IN THERE.
YEAH, IT DOES.
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR.
OH, A LITTLE MUSTARD.
I'M GONNA LIKE
SOME OF THAT BITE.
MM-HMM.
MM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
YEAH.
OH, WE DO NEED ONION.
THAT IS GOOD SAUCE. A SIMPLE
SAUCE, BUT GOOD SAUCE.
YOU GET TOMATO FLAVOR,
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SPICE.
I COULD HAVE
3 OR 12 OF THOSE.
AND SOME OF JUANITA'S
HOMEMADE DESSERT.
SMOKY VALLEY'S
COCONUT CREAM PIE.
IT'S THE BEST AROUND.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE BAKING JUANITA'S WAY.
THAT'S VODKA!
AT THE SMOKY VALLEY TRUCK STOP
IN OLIVE HILL, KENTUCKY...
OKAY, I'VE GOT THIS
HOME FRY.
JUANITA FLANNERY'S COOKIN' UP
ALL THE LOCAL FAVORITES.
IT'S JUST LIKE WE MAKE AT HOME.
DELICIOUS.
LIKE HOME COOKING.
...COOKING.
ESPECIALLY THE PIE.
COCONUT CREAM PIE.
VERY FEW REAL RECIPES
AROUND HERE.
THIS IS GREAT FOR ME, 'CAUSE
I CAN'T BAKE TO SAVE MY LIFE,
AND NOW WE'RE NOT EVEN
GONNA HAVE A REAL RECIPE.
BEAUTIFUL.
AND WE NEED A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT AND A LITTLE MORE.
AND THIS IS YOUR
SHORTENING.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO BEAT THOSE UP
FOR ME WHILE WE DO THIS,
OR WOULD YOU
LIKE ME TO DO IT?
DUMB EGG!
HOW OFTEN DO YOU
MAKE THE PIES?
TWO OR THREE TIMES A DAY.
A DAY?
UH-HUH. ALWAYS ROLL
FROM THE CENTER OUT.
FOLD IT OVER.
LOOK AT THAT. WHAT A PRO.
LOOK HOW NICE
IT TURNED OUT.
OKAY, THEN WE'RE
GONNA DO THIS.
POKING A LITTLE BIT
OF HOLES IN IT--
LET'S IT BREATHE
SOME OF THE STEAM
SO IT DOESN'T BUBBLE UP.
EXACTLY.
AND THAT'LL GO DOWN
FOR WHAT?
15 TO 20.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE COCONUT CREAM?
YEAH.
CORN STARCH.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF MILK.
AGAIN, THOSE
MEASUREMENT RATIOS I LOVE.
AND WE'RE GONNA
CUT SOME SUGAR IN IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT OUR YOLKS
IN HERE AND MIX THAT TOGETHER.
WE'RE GOING TO STRAIN THIS
MIXTURE INTO OUR MILK,
BECAUSE THERE COULD
BE SOME EGG WHITE IN HERE
THAT WOULD CAUSE
SOMETHING FUNNY.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
CONTINUE TO STIR THAT
UNTIL IT THICKENS.
YOU GOT CORN STARCH IN THERE, SO
THAT MIXTURE STARTS TO HEAT UP,
THAT'LL REALLY
START TO TIGHTEN.
LET'S GET OUR PIECRUST.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
WE'RE GOING
TO PUT SOME BUTTER.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF VANILLA EXTRACT?
THAT'S MY SECRET.
THAT'S VODKA!
YOU SEE WHY THEY
LIKE 'EM SO WELL.
WHOO! THEY ALL
KEEP COMING BACK.
A LITTLE BIT OF COCONUT.
WANT TO LICK THE SPOON?
THAT IS HEAVY.
WE SHOULD MAKE SOME
MERINGUE FOR IT.
GET ANGRY WITH IT.
OH, I DO.
AND NOW A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR?
BRING IT.
LOOK OUT.
ROBBIE, THAT IS--
THE MAGIC YOU DO
WITH JUST A SPOON--
A LITTLE COCONUT.
AND THAT'LL CRISP UP BROWN
WHEN WE PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
WOW, IT'S CHRISTMAS
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I HAVE EVER
JUMPED INTO AN ADVENTURE
OF THAT MUCH OF THAT.
WOW. GOOD MERINGUE.
YOU'RE PRETTY EXCEPTIONAL.
MY FAVORITE PART IS THE CRUNCHY
COOKED COCONUT ON TOP.
MMM, YEAH.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
COME TO KENTUCKY,
AND BUY YOUR PIES.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
LIKE MY MOTHER USED TO FIX.
LIKE JUANITA
FIXES EVERYTHING...
ANYTHING ELSE
FOR YOU GUYS?
UP AND DOWN THE MENU.
GOOD HOME COOKIN'.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
VERY FEW PLACES
SERVES FOOD LIKE THIS.
THEY'RE ALL HERE FOR YOUR HOME
COOKIN' LIKE MAMA USED TO MAKE.
A LOT OF HAPPY FOLKS.
I MEAN, THE PLACE IS PACKED.
YOU GAVE ME TOO MUCH.
OH, WELL, THAT'S BETTER
THAN NOT ENOUGH, RIGHT?
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
LOOK AT THAT PARTY RIGHT THERE.
BUT I DON'T EVEN THINK
A GREAT COLD MEXICAN BEER
AND A MARIACHI BAND WOULD
HAVE MADE THAT GO DOWN.