Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
You guys do have
a heart-paddle kit here, right?
Yes, we do.
...it's a full hour
of deep-fried all stars.
Drop it like it.
Eh!
On a stick...
Slagious, gelatinous
maximus.
It's a big-bacon twist
on the corn dog.
Confit,
pork belly corn dog.
Yes.   Yes.
And a lobster tail
tucked in tempura.
Yes. Yes.
In a ball...
What size ball are
you gonna make them into?
Oh.
...with cheesy fried goodness...
Mmm. That's nuts.
...and a roundup
of Cuban and Italian classics.
Ranchera sauce?
Ranchera sauce.
Its slam-dunk clam cakes...
Hold onto it, Gilligan. We've
got rough seas in a minute.
...real-deal fish-and-chips...
The whole experience
is coming back.
...a crispy clucker sandwich...
That's like a Pink Floyd
concert, Man.
...and a Philly-fried take
on the PB&J...
Oh, man. Right?
How bad can that be?
...and a take
on the childhood fave.
Are you guys excited
at home?
Plus...
real-deal chicharrones.
Got some raw pigskins.
That's a little
"Silence of the Lamb"-y for me.
It's all scary-good,
deep-fried food.
Do we look like we're on
some health tour?
Look at us.
Come on.
Let's go jump some buildings.
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
-- Captions by VITAC --
Closed Captions provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC.
Okay.
I'm here on Cambridge Street,
Cambridge, Mass, right between
M.I.T. and Harvard --
almost right in the middle.
I'm going to a joint that's
got a funny, little story.
So, it's a Cajun place
for like 20, 25 years.
Then all of a sudden,
they decide to sell,
and it's gonna become
a Chinese restaurant,
except one of the neighbors
that owns a bakery
doesn't want that to happen,
so she buys the joint
and hires this crazy chef.
And what do they name the place?
After the birthplace of Elvis.
It's a story you hear every day.
This is Tupelo.
Catfish going down.
Don't tell anybody
about this place
because we want to keep it
to ourselves.
You do not see a lot of Southern
restaurants around here.
This is, like, a beacon of light
in the darkness.
From owner Renee McLeod's
light-bulb idea...
You say, "No, we're not
gonna let it become
a Chinese restaurant.
We're gonna build our own..."
New Orleans, Southern --
Funky joint?
Funky joint. Yes.
...that gets its groove
from Chef Rembs Layman,
a true character,
that was raised on his mom's
Crescent City cooking...
Shrimp and grits.
...but who brings his own kind
of style to the party.
There's a "Z"
in your head.
That's my flair.
Always been doing it?
No.
'Cause you were coming.
Oh, I love that.
I needed flair.
Way to put something on
extra, you know...hey.
But he's putting that flair
into the gumbo,
the beer-battered crepes...
You can't miss that
right there.
...and his zigzag take on bacon
that literally made me do
a double take.
Confit,
pork belly corn dog.
Yes.   Yes.
Belly of the pig.
Like a surgeon.
Put a nice, little rub
on them.
Beauty.
Stick this into a tub.
Stack them up. Wrap them up.
Let it sit for 24 hours.
We'll take it out.
We're gonna submerge it
in duck fat, roast it off.
2½ to 3 hours or until done.
Or until done.
Now we make the batter.
All-purpose flour.
Cornmeal.
Sugar. Salt.
Baking powder.
Baking soda.
Wow.
Lighten it up.
Paprika.
Gave it a little Elvis there
at the end, didn't you?
I did.
Buttermilk.
Very nice.
Whole milk. Huevos.
Finally, oil.
Combined well.
Then, of course, this has to sit
for a little while.
Dig it.
Yeah, you will.
Look at that, man.
Yum.
Slagious, gelatinous
maximus.
I'll grab the skewer.
Now we do the skewer.
Yep.
Make sure you get
inside the meat.
Correct.
Into the dredge.
tipig,
Correct.
and now we're gonna go
to the batter.
We are.
There we go.
We're just trying to, like,
build a barrier here,
so it doesn't go
right to the bottom.
Anticipation's
just killing me.
It's a "hunka hunka
burning love."
You guys do have
a heart-paddle kit here, right?
Yes, we do.
You're all set.
Some of them pickled
habeneros and onions.
A jalapeño aioli?
Yeah.
All right.
Let's get after this.
Smells like corn dog.
That's a perfect storm.
It just has that really rich,
intense pork flavor.
Then you get the texture
and the crunch of the batter.
Then everything is cut
and put into order
by the pickled onions
and the habeneros.
That's a must-try.
Yeah.
I saw that on the menu.
I said,
"I must try that."
Awesome. Seriously.
Corn dog.
I love the dog. There's
the richness of the pork,
but then there's
this awesome crunchiness
from the outside of the batter.
To die for.
It's a funky joint.
You cruise in and tell me
that I would find
a dish like that,
I'd say you're crazy.
And the fact of the matter is,
I think you are.
A little.
Yeah.
Takes one to know one.
If you want to have your taste
buds completely electrified,
this is the place to come.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Thanks for saving
the neighborhood.
Thank you for coming.
Now we're cruising
across the country
to the West Coast for some
real-deal fish-and-chips.
So, here we are. Hunter and I
are cruising State Street,
Santa Barbara, California,
and we're looking for
the real deal --
I'm talking the authentic --
British fish-and-chips joint.
And I think this might be it.
Hunter, grab us a table.
Don't start without me,
all right?
I'm on it.
Because this is
Mac's Fish & Chip Shop.
And fish, chips, and mushy peas
in the window.
Finding a fish-and-chips place
in Santa Barbara
is like a dream come true.
By far the most authentic
I've ever had in the U.S.
Well, that makes total sense,
since owner
Grant "Mac" Macnaughton...
Fish is up.
...is a real-deal Brit
from across the pond.
All right, Chef, so I hear
you're the fish-and-chip guy.
It's true. It's true. We make
some good fish-and-chips here.
What do you like about
fish-and-chips?
I'm all about the real deal.
I like everything.
I like, you know,
the crispiness, the saltiness.
Good man. We got some killer
fish-and-chips for you.
All right.
So, let's start off.
We're gonna throw some
all-purpose flour down.
Paprika.
Some kosher salt here.
We'll get this
all nice and mixed up.
This is where
the beer comes in.
You wouldn't believe
parking the car --
I'm trying to park the car.
You take over my show.
This is "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives" with Guy Fieri.
Hunter!
Chef, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Is my kid behaving
himself in your kitchen?
Very much so.
Where are we at so far?
Yes, so, we're making
some of our beer batter
that goes
on our crispy fish.
So, now we're gonna throw
some beer in.
We're looking for the fizzier
the beer, the better.
We're looking to get
this nice and sticky
to start off with.
So, now we've kind of got this
kind of paste.
It's almost like bread dough.
Some cold water.
So, this batter's
pretty much ready now.
Let's start
rocking and rolling.
Next we're gonna make
our dry dredge.
All right.
Now, season flour.
Kosher salt in there
and a little pepper.
Ready to go.
Now the star of the show?
We use wild Alaskan cod.
Super sustainable.
How many pieces
do you get with an order?
One whole fillet.
So, we're looking at around
about an 8-ounce piece of fish.
We're gonna drop it
into the seasoned flour.
Make sure it gets
completely covered.
Drop it into the batter.
Pop it in.
Let it float away.
How long does this take?
3 or 4 minutes.
These fish are pretty close
to being ready.
We definitely want to get
these chips dropped now.
So, you don't call
them fries.
We call them chips, yeah.
They're
a much thicker cut.
All righty.
So, these fries are ready now.
Oh, I'm calling
them fries.
I didn't do anything.
You're Americanizing me.
Go ahead and pull
those fries out.
All right.
These chips are done.
Our fish are there resting,
ready for us, as well,
and let's get this plated up.
Dig in.
Fresh fish, hand battered,
chips you make yourself.
Look how thin
that batter is.
Yeah, I like that
a lot better.
I went to London
when I was a kid
when I was an exchange student
in France.
Had some fish-and-chips.
My friend,
that's the real deal.
I appreciate that.
Nice job.
ank you, man.
What do you think?
Awesome job.
Fish, chips,
and coleslaw.
What is it about the
fish-and-chips here
that make them so good?
Oh, it's just that fresh
sort of crispiness,
but you still get
the lightness of the fish.
Some things we're just good at.
Classic food. The comfort food.
And we do it well.
In here,
you do it authentic.
Uh-huh.
Real deal.
Accent and all.
Indeed.
Coming up...
Cheese fritters.
...we're headed
to Horn Lake, Mississippi...
That is the most cheese I've
ever seen in a cheese fritter.
...for a barbecue shack...
I didn't really put
"cheese sprinkler" on my résumé,
but now that
I'm thinking about it.
...serving up the cheesy side
of fried goodness.
It's an advertisement
for a gym.
You know, at "Triple D,"
we have shot
so many barbecue restaurants,
but I got to tell you,
the ones I really, really dig
is where the owners compete
in barbecue competitions.
These folks here'tt et c.
They be kicking butt and taking
names at some of the biggest.
So, I'm about 15 miles
outside of downtown Memphis,
but I'm in Mississippi to
check out Memphis Barbecue Co.
One of the few restaurants
that I can say
that you will get
world-championship barbecue.
Can I get some
cheese fritters please?
But for this deep-fried
appetizer,
pit master Melissa Cookston's
putting down the meat
for 13½ pounds
of creamy goodness.
4½, 4, 3, and 2.
Seriously?
It's about the cheese.
I love cheese.
All right.
Give me the rundown.
We're gonna start off
with some sour cream,
minced garlic, green onions,
garlic salt.
Nice.
Yes.
Kosher salt,
parsley flakes,
and a little bit of cayenne
for a little kick,
and whole lot
of beaten eggs.
Can I lick the bowl?
Add flour.
Is this all-purpose flour?
This is actually
self-rising flour
because we want to be able
to get the cheese balls
to puff up a little bit.
I'm gonna need your help
in a minute.
Oh, absolutely.
Yeah, my hands are
gonna be nasty, so.
Get a foot in there,
or what do you want to do?
Just start pouring
some of the cheese in.
Mozzarella.
I didn't really put
"cheese sprinkler" on my résumé,
but now that
I'm thinking about it.
Swiss.
You're doing a great job.
Awesome.
Parmesan.
That is the most cheese I've
ever seen in a cheese fritter.
Cheddar.
All right.
This is where you really
start to get your workout.
Yes.
Makes for
nice big muscles.
Ah, okay. So, we take them,
roll them into a ball.
What size ball are you
gonna make them into?
Whoa.
All right, so, we're just gonna
put them in oil --
350 degrees.
In what?
Oil.
No, you didn't say it
that way before.
I love it. That's one of
my favorite Southern words.
"Oll."
Oll.
How long is this gonna
go down for?
Two minutes.
Okay. Wow.
These are golden.
This is the honey Dijon --
a mixture of honey,
Dijon mustard,
spicy mustard,
sugar, you know,
ooey-gooey goodness.
And then, voilà.
Mmm. That's nuts.
The cheese that I really
like out of that,
right off the bat,
is that Swiss.
It holds together.
Not overly salty.
Not overly one flavor.
I do get that garlic.
I do get that Swiss.
Nice little crunchy texture
on the outside.
This honey Dijon moat that's in
does perfect for it.
That's crazy.
It's got a little bite to it.
It's almost like a hush puppy
stuffed with cream cheese.
It's more than just
your average cheese stick.
Cheese fritters.
The finest barbecue
in the Mid-South area.
What else
do you want?
I got a cop
and a guy that's with a cop.
They don't mind.
Next up...
Check it out.
...a tap room
on Philly's South Side...
Peanut butter and jelly
going to table 5.
...turning the kiddie plate
into a sweet masterpiece.
It's normal to see things like
a fried peanut butter and jelly?
Normal for here.
And in Hoboken, New Jersey...
My eyeballs
are sweating a bit.
...the Cuban joint
taking their turn in the fryer.
This is the first discovered
culinary cave of Flavortown.
"Triple D"
is here in South Philly
to go to this
funky little tap room.
You're just gonna --
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
I said
you could drive the car.
This isn't "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives Unwrapped."
I'm Guy Fieri.
This is Marc Summers.
And we're here to check out
the South Philadelphia Tap Room.
Yeah, Man.
Check it out.
Unbelievable.
Just knock their socks off.
Vegan hoagie going to 21.
This bar
is the neighborhood.
We always knew that we were
gonna put something here
that probably didn't belong
in this neighborhood.
But if you build it,
they will come,
and they have.
This bar really had
a vital role
in revitalizing
this neighborhood.
And that gamble's
been paying off big-time
for John Longacre since 2003.
This is, like,
where it's at?
It really is.
I mean, this is
as South Philly as it gets.
Those props
go to Chef Scott Schroeder.
Scott is fearless
in the kitchen.
It's a little challenging,
and it pushed the boundaries
of your own taste buds.
It's normal to see things like
a fried peanut butter and jelly?
Normal for here.
You know Marc Summers.
I do.
Extraordinaire.
Since "Double Dare."
Oh, my.
You know what?
Marc lives here in Philly.
I thought he would be
the perfect guy to bring down
to South Philadelphia
to try the Tap Room.
So, Chef Scott,
what are you gonna make us?
My signature dish,
a fried peanut butter
and jelly sandwich.
So, we're gonna start
with making
the french-toast batter.
We have eggs,
fresh-ground nutmeg,
salt, black pepper.
Really?
Vanilla extract, cinnamon.
Just whisk that in
a little bit.
Some sugar.
Heavy cream.
Some whole milk.
Okay.
Peanut butter and jelly.
White bread.
This is from Baker Street,
a local bakery
out in Chestnut Hill.
Peanut butter...
and then
strawberry preserves.
Okay.
PB&J's made.
Yeah.
So, now we're gonna just dip it
in the french toast batter.
What is this concoction here
of dust?
Ground Frosted Flakes,
just pulsed in a food processor.
Yeah, just on both sides,
nice and crusted
Oh, man.
Right?
How bad can that be?
Well, you get this
and you get a free Spanx shirt.
Look at the cup of butter
that he put in there.
And the trick is
don't touch it at first.
The sugar
in the Frosted Flakes
are gonna
kind of caramelize.
So, how long on that side
are you frying it?
Two to three minutes.
Split it into fours.
Bon appétit.
You go first.
Oh, my.
Mmm.
Wow. That's awesome.
It's light.
It's not super heavy.
A really good jam,
nice creamy peanut butter.
Everybody loves a PB&J.
Take something simple,
push it up another level.
Outrageous.
What do you think, huh?
The corn-flake topping...
...is the pièce de résistance.
Frosted flakes --
Corn flakes would
almost make it healthy.
Do we look like
we're on some health tour?
Look at us.
Come on!
Let's go chug some doughnuts!
It's like being a kid again.
The twist on it
is the Frosted Flakes.
It just adds, like,
a texture and a crunch to it.
Cassie, pick up --
Table 20.
Once people find out it's here,
they just keep coming in.
That just comes with being
a great restaurant.
I think everybody
who misses a night here
and goes some place else
in Philadelphia is
missing out on the best.
Well, listen, it's
a funky joint, nice people,
and you've got a real boss thing
there with Chef.
I mean,
he is a true talent.
This is a place
people got to check out.
Thank you.
Thanks for having me.
Appreciate it.
From South Philly to New Jersey,
where we're hitting
the fryer again, Cuban style.
I'm here on Washington Street.
Now, this is like the main drag
here in Hoboken, New Jersey,
and I'm right across the
Hudson River from New York City.
Now, this area is loaded
with great ethnic restaurants.
But when I hear
that there's a Cuban restaurant,
you know I got to check it out.
This is La Isla.
One picadillo,
one arroz con pollo,
one camarones encendido.
Good Cuban food. Makes you
put a smile on your face.
World-class flavors
and a down-home experience.
Just what chef Omar Giner
dreamed of as a kid.
He used to tell me all the time,
"I'm gonna be a chef.
I'm gonna have
my own restaurant."
Here it is.
Sometimes dreams do come true,
and in '96, Omar and his wife
bought this neighborhood joint
with her family...
When Omar took over,
it was a whole new flavor.
Mom, grandma,
mother-in-law.
Mother-in-law?
Mother-in-law.
Absolutely.
They've even got a Cuban spin
on meat and potatoes.
Papa rellena salsa ranchera.
Pick up.
Okay, what are we making?
The ground filling that we make
for La Papa rellena.
We freshly grind
our beef in-house.
Okay.
Heat up our pan, and we're gonna
add our olive oil in there.
Drop in our diced onions,
garlic,
our bay leaf in there,
oregano.
This is cumin that we toast
and we grind in-house.
That's just
my little twist on it.
And then we also add a little
smoked paprika, as well.
Add our ground beef.
Now we're gonna hit
the tomato paste.
Cook that out --
give it a little color.
We'll add a little salt,
and we'll add some white wine.
Give it
a little liquid there.
Now we're gonna assemble
our papa rellena.
We got the mashed potatoes.
Mashed potatoes.
The picadillo
that we cooled.
So, what we're
just gonna do is
get ourselves a nice
little ball here of potato.
so, if you're late for work,
you get stuck with this job.
That's it.
Look at that thing.
We're gonna drop it
in the egg wash.
I'm gonna use a spoon,
so that way,
I can keep off my hands.
Next, they go
into the fine panko.
Back in again.
And then into
the coarse panko.
Okay.
Now goes the fryer.
For about four minutes?
Four minutes
till it's Golden Brown.
Oh, boy.
Ranchera sauce.
Ranchera sauce?
So, look at that.
This is the first discovered
culinary cave of Flavortown.
Mmm. Oh.
That sauce is ridiculous.
Mmm!
But I think that the combination
that you put together,
along with this meat
and the potato
and the little crunchy
crispiness on the outside
from the panko --
that is killer, dude.
Mmm.
Chef, awesome job.
My eyeballs
are sweating a bit.
Papa's ready.
What do you think
makes it so good?
It's authentic.
This is like Cuban plus.
Chef, you're the bomb.
Awesome. Awesome.
Thanks, man.
Coming up
on "Deep Fried All-Stars"...
Jazz hands.
There you go.
We're heading
to Memphis, Tennessee...
Mommy!
That was hot.
...where they're spicing up
a Southern staple.
Can I get a little John Candy
before we go?
All right.
Then in Narragansett,
Rhode Island...
Clam cake please.
...a summertime clam shack...
Ladies and gentlemen at home,
I want to explain this to you --
this is a cement mixer.
...dunking the classic cakes.
Ooh!
You cooked it in beef fat.
Oh, I dig coming down
to Memphis.
I mean, so much history and some
great "Triple D" joints.
So, I'm in an area
called South Main
right by Central Station
to check out a little
hole-in-the-wall joint
called Rizzo's Diner.
When you walk in
off the streets,
you really don't know
what to expect.
Lobster Pronto Pup up.
Michael is a well-known chef
around this city.
We've been following him
around Memphis
from restaurant
to restaurant.
I stalked Michael Patrick,
the chef.
He is our favorite.
You mean Rizzo?
A nickname
that followed Michael Patrick
all the way
from his hometown of Cleveland.
It's nice
to follow him here
to where we can share
in a little piece of his dream.
Which involved opening a joint
with his name on it in 2011.
Order up.
We're a casual, upscale diner.
I take some traditional
Southern food
and kind of jazz it up
with a chef's interpretation.
Put them both up please.
Like this.
Jazz hands.
There you go.
That's jazzing it up.
Got ice cream
on the French toast.
Smoked Duck Tamale Pie.
Lobster Pronto Pup.
Sort of like healthy
carnival food.
Lobster Pronto Pups?
Lobster Pronto Pups.
Yeah.
I wanted to take
the Pronto Pup
and jazz it up,
as I said before.
Jazz hands.
Wow, that's a full
floor show, isn't it?
All right, we're gonna start
with some flour.
Sugar.
We got dry mustard.
Salt and pepper.
Cornstarch.
An egg.
Now we're gonna add
our milk.
And we have
some lemon-lime soda.
For the carbonation?
Right.
So, we're here
in the South.
We want to sweeten it up
a little bit.
Scald this together.
Nice and creamy.
Our next step would be
to do our lobster meat.
Five of them.
Little slipper lobsters.
There you go.
One, two, three, four, five.
Take this.
Split it all the way down.
Remove the meat.
It curls up pretty good
when it blanches.
You gonna blanch
the meat first?
It's gonna be
a little parcooked.
Then we got
our boiling water here.
A little lemon.
Salt and pepper, you want?
Yes, sir.
We'll add the meat.
Drop them in.
This is just gonna go
hot and fast.
All it needs is
about 2 to 3 minutes.
All right, so, we're gonna
remove the lobster.
Kind of like
bobbing for apples.
And then ice bath?
Gonna rest them here just to
absorb some of that moisture.
Now we're gonna
skewer this meat.
Run it through here.
Want to get to the middle of it
to get it nice and tight.
This isn't any joke here.
This is the real deal.
I mean,
you're loading it up.
So, now we're gonna batter
the Lobster Pronto Pup to fry.
Nice little coating.
Oh-oh.
That's gonna be good.
When they're floating,
I'll give them another,
you know, 30, 40 seconds.
All you really have to
wait for on this
is for that batter to brown up
on the outside
because that slipper lobster
is cooked all the way through.
Yes.
How we looking?
We're looking there.
A lobster corn dog.
Only in Memphis.
Now we're gonna take
a little arugula.
A little olive oil.
Salt and pepper.
Lay these on
in a little cross.
Then we're gonna drizzle
a little Creole mustard aioli.
Okay.
Wow, that's hot.
Mommy!
That was hot.
Wow.
The lobster's super tender.
It's just delicate.
Mmm.
I mean, this isn't even
tempura-batter tender.
This is even lighter
than that.
And there's a little bit
of sweetness to it,
but then you balance it out
with the acidity,
you know,
of that Creole mustard.
That is
Lobster Corn Dog 101.
Nicely done.
Thank you very much.
It is like heaven on a stick.
You didn't know
his name was Rizzo?
No, I always called him
Michael Patrick.
Michael Patrick?
Yes, sir.
Dude, I loved you
in Riverdance.
You were the bomb.
Now we're gonna boogie up
to the Rhode Island shore
for a little more sizzle.
I've been coming to Rhode Island
for like the last 20 years
to visit the in-laws.
And my father-in-law Bob --
greatest guy in the world --
would always make sure
that I got to try some of
the "regional specialties."
Oh, he introduced me
to coffee milk and hot grinders
and hot wieners and Johnnycakes,
and then he says,
"Guid, you got to try this one.
This is a clam cake."
I said, "Clam in a cake?"
So I'm here in Narragansett
right by Point Judith
to check out a joint
that is rocking the clam cakes.
This is Aunt Carrie's.
Clam and lobster.
Everybody knows about it,
and they do come back.
A lot of times
it's year after year.
Since the '20s,
when Carrie Cooper
and her husband Ulysses
opened this summer-only joint.
Hey, girls.
Hi, El.
The family tradition
continues today
led by third generation owner
Elsie Foy.
This place has got
to be bananas busy.
Once Fourth of July
rolls around,
it's kind of busy
every night, yeah.
Thanks to
the star attraction...
Clam cake, please.
...a deep-fried
Rhode Island legend
that's been around
for over 90 years.
So we're gonna make the flour
for the clam cakes.
Yes.
This is what
we're mixing it in?
We are.
Ladies and gentlemen at home,
I want to explain this to you.
This is
a cement mixer.
Never used for cement.
No, I understand that.
All right,
so all-purpose flour.
And you want this
in the mixer?
Yes, please.
Baking powder.
And this is gonna sit here
and just mix up.
And a little bit
of salt, too?
Little bit of salt.
What an awesome sound.
Mix this,
dump it in the tub.
I'm gonna be pushing this,
aren't I?
Yes.
Now it's clam cake time?
Yeah.
We're gonna add
some eggs.
Okay.
Clams.
So this is real deal.
This is not
some frozen product.
All of 'em?
All of them.
Bucket o' clam.
We do add
a little bit of water
because we also
want them fluffy.
Okeydokey.
And our special
clam cake flour.
I might have
to have you -- yes.
Hold on to it, Gilligan. We've
got rough seas in a minute.
Look at that.
Perfect batter.
The fryer's at what temp?
375.
Like that?
Absolutely.
No.
Oh, that's why you rock this.
We ready to go?
We are ready.
So you're just
going in.
Very, very careful.
It takes
about five minutes.
We want to make sure
they're done.
Okay. Comes out clean.
Like a cake.
You're good to go.
And what do people
eat a clam cake with?
Usually with "chow-dah."
With chow-dah.
You're ready to rock.
We are. Simple, simple
South county food.
Oh!
You cooked it in beef fat.
It's rich. It's light.
A lot of clam flavor.
Mmm. This is exceptional.
Our base chowder --
Now you have to dip
your clam cakes in that.
Okay. Mm-hmm.
It's simply done --
Mmm --
and done to perfection.
I love it.
Thank you.
Combo with clear chowder.
You pull apart the clam cake,
dip it in the chowder,
and you get to taste lots
of clams and a ton of flavor.
It's delicious.
Carrie's is like an icon
to Narragansett,
and it's just fun to see
that the place hasn't changed.
You get a chance to come here
a couple times in the summer.
This is an indulgence.
You're down by the water.
If you're gonna have a clam
cake, cook 'em with lard.
Tell my secret.
Oh, I am down with it.
I am so excited.
You're gonna love it.
Coming up...
Let's get
into the sandwich.
...we're headed
to San Francisco...
Fried-chicken sandwich.
Order up.
...where a hot-dog shop...
That's like a Pink Floyd
concert, Man.
...is knocking fried chicken
out of the ballpark.
It should say
"Show Chicken."
And in Chatham, New Jersey...
We're gonna go
on the crispy chicken
and the penne vodka now.
Whatever you want, Honey.
The Italian joint...
Hello.
...where an old buddy...
Easy. Easy.
...and his better half...
That right there,
rocks the house.
...are frying up
pure Italian comfort.
If you've never had an arancini
ball, you must try it.
So, I'm here in the Tenderloin
district of San Francisco,
right on the corner
of Market and Golden Gate,
to check out a hot-dog joint --
Not just any hot-dog joint.
I mean,
this is San Francisco.
They love food in this town.
This place, they're
scratch-making the mustard,
the ketchup,
and the gourmet dogs.
This is Show Dogs.
Wild-boar sausage.
This is definitely
not your average hot dog.
Every dish has
a different twist to it.
'Cause owner John Clark
isn't just a businessman.
He's a flat-out food dude.
My background as a chef is
to make everything in-house.
It's the opposite
of fast food.
So, he brought in
Chef Seth Carter...
Polish dog. Order up.
...and together,
they've created a menu
full of scratch-made sodas,
sauces, and sides
to pair with their
gourmet dogs and sandwiches,
like this high-end clucker.
Fried-chicken sandwich.
Order up.
We are making
the spice mixture
that we use to marinate
the chicken
for the fried-chicken
sandwich.
So, we have kosher salt.
Vinegar powder.
Vinegar powder?
Onion powder.
Madras curry powder.
Turmeric.
Garlic powder.
Black pepper.
Toasted ground cumin.
Bring it together?
Bring it together.
We have grape-seed oil.
We're gonna put some of that
over the chicken...
Look at that beautiful color
on that grape-seed oil.
...and spoon some
of the marinade over it.
And then we're gonna
mix it up.
How long are we gonna
let this marinate?
A couple hours.
We got
our marinated chicken.
We're gonna add the salt
to the flour.
A.P. flour?
A.P. flour.
Okay.
All right.
Chicken --
We put it in the flour.
Get it in the buttermilk.
Flour sticks
to the chicken.
Buttermilk sticks
to the flour.
And back into the flour.
And that's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
We're gonna fry this
for about two minutes,
and then we'll be
ready to go.
We take the bottom bun,
slather it with our
lemon-cayenne aioli
that we make
here in-house.
Slather?
Slather.
It's a very specific word.
Our house-made coleslaw.
Our pickled ginger
that we also make in-house.
There's
our fried chicken.
And slather this bun
with our lemon-cayenne aioli
again.
And there we go.
Let's get
into this sandwich.
Whoo!
Shut the front door!
That fried chicken is
out-of-bounds.
Yeah.
This is -- Whoa.
There's flavor
all over the board on this one.
That's like
a Pink Floyd concert, man.
Classic.
It is a classic,
but wow.
Yes.
The crunch from the chicken
and the saltiness to it
is just perfectly
in balance.
That is an awesome
fried-chicken sandwich.
Mmm!
Thank you.
It should say
"Show Chicken."
Out of the chicken sandwiches
I've had,
this is, by far,
my favorite.
and the window show is
unbelievable.
Come with a sense of humor
and an open mind,
and it's great.
Speaking of a sense of humor,
you got to meet my friends
doing a fried dish right.
So, I'm here
in Chatham, New Jersey,
about 35 miles west
of New York City.
Now, I've been cooking
with Carl Ruiz for years --
awesome chef.
And I've been telling him,
"You got to open
your own joint."
Finally, he and his wife
took my advice
and opened their own place.
And they were smart --
they named it after her.
This is Marie's
Italian Specialties.
This is like sitting
in my mother's kitchen.
On a scale of 1 to 10,
I would give this place a 15.
Makes sense.
Carl's one of the craziest
chefs I know.
Easy, easy!
What makes your
Italian food different?
It's just
simple Italian food,
but we do it
with the best ingredients.
And a little sideshow.
Today we're gonna --
Aah!
Don't make me nuts.
I have a family.
This is like culinary
Disneyland, and this is Goofy.
Hello!
Now I get to work with the real
brains of this operation...
We're gonna go on the crispy
chicken and the penne vodka now.
Whatever you want, honey.
...his wife, Marie.
Marie is the biggest
hidden secret you ever met.
Okay, what are you
gonna make me?
Okay, we're gonna make
the risotto for the arancini.
Okay, the arancini.
Arancini.
They're rice balls, okay?
Different styles
of making them.
This is
gonna be interesting.
That's hot, so we're just
gonna take arborio rice.
And we're gonna
toast it first.
Okay, so now it's toasted
up to the color we want.
So, we add one quart
of salted water.
We don't want it
to get really mushy.
Normally, with risotto,
it's very, very creamy.
We want it to almost have
the same texture as rice.
Now we're gonna make
the tomato sauce.
Extra virgin olive oil,
pureed garlic.
And then we're gonna add
tomato sauce.
Dry basil,
granulated garlic.
Copious amount. Wow!
And just
a little bit of salt.
We get it going
for about an hour,
and then we put
our raw meatballs in.
This has got the --
Ground beef,
granulated garlic and basil,
parmesan cheese,
bread crumbs, salt.
So, they'll cook
inside the sauce?
They cook in the sauce.
Okay, we're gonna make
rice balls.
Give me a rundown.
So, we're gonna start
with our homemade meatballs.
The meatballs that we cooked
in the sauce.
The parmesan cheese,
dried parsley,
granulated garlic,
six large eggs,
shredded mozzarella,
and seasoned bread crumbs.
Now we're gonna add
the rice.
We're gonna fluff it up
a little bit.
Then we're gonna add
our salt,
some of the tomato sauce,
give it a final mix.
And now you start to form
the arancini.
Exactly.
Just a little coating
of some bread crumbs.
350.
3½ minutes.
That's it?
That's it.
Some of
the homemade tomato sauce.
Dig in.
Look at that --
nice and tender,
cheese coming through.
And I can already hear
the crunch just from the fork.
The texture's outrageous.
I like the little bit
of the meatball in there.
Tomato sauce
is outstanding.
But the crunch on the outside --
crunchy and then creamy.
It's killer.
That right there
rocks the house.
Thank you.
You're the bomb.
All right,
here's the rice balls.
They're out of this world --
all kinds of goodies
on the inside.
If you've never had an arancini
ball, you must try it.
You got to come check
this joint out -- real deal.
And this guy...
Up next...
Wow.
That is funky.
...the final stop on our
deep-fried all-star tour.
Whoa!
A Denver, Colorado, dive bar...
One of the best things
I've seen on "Triple D."
...taking a tot...
This is the moment.
...and a convenience-store
classic.
Pork rinds in the window.
, out of bounds.
...and a convenience-store
classic.
That might be
in the Top 10 coolest.
I'm here in
the Highlands neighborhood,
about a mile from downtown
Denver, Colorado,
and about a mile away
from Citizen Pictures,
the folks that happen to produce
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives,"
but don't let those details
confuse you.
I'm here to check out
a joint that I hear
has the most real-deal,
off-the-hook,
outrageous bar food
you can find.
This is Highland Tavern.
Stupid Burger
in the window.
Much more upscale than what
you would consider a local bar.
Just when owners
Brian Sommatino and Andy Stutz
had in mind
when they bought this old joint.
The building we're in is
an old Coors Brewing building?
Yeah, built in 1901
by Coors.
It's been a bar pretty much
from 1901 till now,
minus prohibition.
So, they kept the suds flowing
and hired fine-dining chef
Jeremy McMinn
to build up the menu.
Every dish has a little
something added to it
that just makes you
remember it.
And they hit the jackpot
when Jeremy
showed he could tackle
the Everest of bar food...
Tavern Tots.
...the homemade tater tot.
Do I need
to freeze-dry them?
to dehydrate them?
What exactly --
Eventually I just gave up
and we made up our own thing.
All right.
Well, let's see how you do it.
We're gonna cook
the potatoes.
Cold water.
We're gonna bring these up
to just barely a simmer.
Okay.
And then even
the heat out on it,
and just let them sit.
It usually takes about 40
minutes until they're al dente.
Al dente -- No, okay.
Yeah, that's probably
a pretty good description.
So, do you have a timer
on this?
No.
Awesome.
So, there's a variable
here.
Yeah.
All right.
So, we got our parsley,
cooked potato
that's just cooked enough
that it'll still make shreds.
Yeah.
So, hash brown-ish.
Hash brown-ish, yeah.
There you go.
Ooh!
It's like a snow blower.
So, if you're
a breakfast house,
you would die to have
hash coming out like that.
A little bit of grit
to it,
so it's not completely finished,
and this is the foundation.
That's it.
I love it.
Now what's the process?
Then we got to mix in
our dry ingredients.
Salt?
Salt.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion.
Cayenne pepper.
Nice.
The key is there's a lot
of nooks and crannies
to all that --
All those different pieces
of potato,
so the more evenly
you can distribute this...
Okay.
We're gonna add tamari
to our eggs.
Really?
Yeah.
So, that little bit of egg's
gonna help bind it.
Yeah.
I'm excited.
Are you guys excited
at home?
Now, we got to form these,
freeze them,
form them, set them up.
Form them
and drop them.
Like it's hot?
They will be hot
once we've dropped them.
Okay. What size tot
do you make?
It's about an ounce
and a quarter.
Okay.
Cook them on 350?
375.
Till they're GBD.
That's golden brown
and delicious.
I pick it up.
A little salt on these.
There it is.
Small order of tots.
This is the moment.
Good separation.
Looking good so far.
That's what you're looking for
in a tot.
Out of all the house-made tots
I've had...
mine included...
that's the most
tot-alistic.
This is ridiculous.
Way to hammer that out.
Thanks.
In the world
of "Triple D,"
that's probably one of the best,
if not the best rendition
of a homemade tot.
Thanks.
Nice job.
And great seasoning.
Watch out
for this guy.
This will ruin tots
for everywhere else
because they are really
just the best.
We have declassified
the tots,
and now we are
going to make...
Pork rinds
in the window.
We're gonna make
our pork rinds.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Give me the rundown.
Got some raw pigskins.
Now, these are pigskins
from the --
Belly skin.
Belly skin, primarily,
is what you want to use in this?
This is where the bacon
has been taken out,
just to give you
some reference,
and you are now
going to...
We're gonna drop this
in some boiling water.
Drop it.
Drop it
like it's skin.
Great. That's a little
"Silence of the Lamb"-y for me.
So, you got to cook this
through.
Got four hours
at a full-on boil.
Salted?
No salt.
All right.
Wow.
That is funky, man.
Now you'll cut them into chunks,
pieces, strips?
Little strips.
Okay.
So, this little
munchkin dehydrator
is gonna do
all the work.
It's gonna do
How long
are these gonna go?
Set it and forget it
for about 26½ hours.
Not 27?
Not 27.
Not 25.
26.
26 and a...
Half.
When you dehydrate it
and take all that moisture out,
that's what gives them
the chance to really puff up?
Yeah.
All right.
Load 'em up,
shut 'em down.
26½ hours,
and here we go.
That's it.
Genius.
Okay.
They're ready
to come out.
Dehydrated pig skin.
Really?
Yeah.
Like, hard plastic.
So, now we're gonna go
to the fryer.
Let's go.
Whoa!
It's amazing every single time
you do it, too --
doesn't get old.
That is --
I'm telling you,
I have seen some cool things
on "Triple D."
That might be
in the top 10 coolest.
Bring over
those mouth killers.
Wow.
Hot!
Okay. Next.
We're gonna make
the chili lime-salt mix.
We got our lime salt.
Korean chili flake.
Chili powder.
A little mix.
Season 'em.
That's ridiculous.
There you go.
Look at that.
That's a lot of work,
buddy.
Dude, you kill this.
Thanks.
This is how they were
to be appreciated.
Fresh, crispy, light,
not dense.
The flavor jets
just turned on.
They're trying
to shut down
that flavor fire
I got in my mouth.
You want another one?
Maybe a little Tebow.
Hang on a second.
That is ridiculous.
I don't say this often,
but that's the best chicharrone
I've ever had.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
I'm really taken back,
man.
I love the pork rinds.
I think they should be
prescribed to me by my doctor.
One of the best "Triple D"
experiences I've had.
That's saying a lot.
Okay?
There we go.
Thanks, man.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."