You know, it doesn't get
any more old school
than this -- meatloaf.
You know, I've traveled
all over the country.
I've seen meatloaf made
with anything
you could imagine in more ways
than you could imagine.
So I figured
today on "Big Bite,"
let's go old-school Americana,
startin' off
with my Andouille-stuffed
brisket meatloaf.
It's got a classic look
on the outside
and a flavor-packed
Andouille sausage core.
This is so out of bounds.
Now, on the side, we've got
smashed fingerling potatoes
with barbecue sauce.
They're crispy, spicy,
tangy and a little sweet.
And I bet you can't
eat just one.
Now to wash it all down,
I'm stirrin' up
a maple pig cocktail
with cherries,
whiskey and bacon.
Yup.
Wait till you see
how I make that one.
I'm just finishing up right now,
uh, doing the pork shoulder,
just a little bit of pork
shoulder to make the Andouille.
Thin stripped, as cold
as you can get that pork.
Listen, we're making
fantastic meatloaf,
why not go ahead
and grind it ourselves?
We have the attachments.
We know we wanna do this.
Okay. So now taking
the last little bit out.
I'm just gonna leave it set up
'cause I'm gonna be back here
in a second doin' it
for the brisket.
Okay. We're --
we're talkin' about Andouille,
a famous Louisiana sausage.
I mean, everybody's
got a recipe.
Everybody has a buddy
that made it the best.
So we're just gonna start off
with a little kosher salt,
some black pepper.
We're gonna go into, uh,
a little paprika,
little smoked paprika,
sweet paprika.
I mean, you're just thinkin'
about flavor city.
We'll do a little cumin,
just a touch.
A little chili powder,
I mean, yes,
we are runnin' through
the spice cabinet.
Just a touch
of red chili flake.
Just a little bit of cayenne.
This, you can take it
as spicy as you want it.
Smoked sausage,
Andouille sausage,
I mean, all those sausages
comin' outta there, hotlinks.
Mm. All right.
Let me just get
a little bit of garlic here.
Now I've had bad meatloaf.
I've had fantastic meatloaf.
Wait until you see the style
of meatloaf that we're doin'.
I guarantee you, no one will
walk away from the table
and not go, "Wow.
That was some
flavor-packed meatloaf."
Okay.
So diced garlic.
So what's gonna happen
is I mix all this together,
let all those flavors
come together.
And later, we're gonna
form this into a log
and set it in the center
of this meatloaf.
I know.
I know. Just work with me. Okay.
So I'm gonna get this down,
let it sit in the fridge.
Okay.
Let me wash up real quick.
The idea was it first started
with taking
a whole Andouille sausage
and wrapping meatloaf around it.
Well, why am I
gonna make a meatloaf
that I'm scratch making
and then put a processed
Andouille in the middle?
I know how to make Andouille.
Can't beat it.
Let's talk about doing
potatoes next.
Fingerling potatoes,
one of my favorites.
When it comes to
doin' this dish,
fingerlings are the key.
And the reason is the way
we're gonna treat 'em, okay?
So let's do this.
Grab some water.
Got a pan.
You know that we're gonna
start with cold water
and cold potatoes.
We'll drop in
a little bit of water.
Okay.
Fingerlings nice, buttery,
thin-skinned,
play well with others.
Here's what's gonna happen.
I'll drop the potatoes in,
already been rinsed off,
dried off, okay?
We'll drop these in.
And we're gonna add
a lotta salt.
And I mean a lotta salt,
like 3 tablespoons of salt.
This is just gonna soak right
into the potatoes as they cook.
And right when
they get done cooking,
let 'em cool a little bit,
and then I'm gonna smash 'em.
All right.
Let's talk about panade.
Okay. I make meatloaf.
I make meatballs.
Panade is one of the --
is one of the centers of it.
This is how you get
all the moisture in there
or keep all the moisture
in there.
So let's just
think about this.
The meatball or meatloaf
is cooking.
And the fat's starting
to render down.
Okay?
The fat's starting to --
to render down
outta the meat.
Well, what does it wanna do?
It wants to leave the building.
It wants to end up on the tray.
And then it wants
to make a dry meatball.
But if we put the panade --
So we're gonna take this bread
and add a little bit of,
uh, of egg and milk to it.
If we take the panade
and mix that in with the meat,
well, as the meat starts
to render out its fat,
the bread soaks up the fat.
That's my theory.
I'm stickin' to it.
Okay.
So a nice pullman loaf.
I like to make
my own breadcrumbs if I can.
So I'm just gonna pulse
this a little bit.
We're gonna do some mirepoix
here in a little.
But we're just kinda
building the layers of this.
And not too much
of the bread,
this should be
just about enough.
And again, leftover bread,
never throw it away.
Keep it dry.
Keep it from molding.
Oh, you'll find
something to do with it.
Pulse it.
Yeah. There we go.
It was just dry enough
that it would work.
You can throw
anything in here.
The only thing
I try to do is stay away
from any of the breads
that have a real pred--
that have a real
predominant flavor,
like a, uh, caraway seed
or like a rye bread
or something.
Okay. That looks good.
Hang on, one thing.
Now getting into this,
before I add that panade,
gonna get a couple eggs...
and some milk.
And then I'll add
the bread into it.
And the egg's gonna work
as a great binder
into this meatloaf.
And some milk.
Okay. Three-quarters
of a cup of milk.
Give that a quick
little whisk.
Okay. Here we go.
Beautiful, fresh breadcrumbs.
Sourdough breadcrumbs
would work awesome right here.
Fold that in.
And again, remember,
just like when we're making
meatballs, on this meatloaf,
we don't wanna sit there
and work it a bunch
and try to mix
the egg and the --
and the panade all together
with the meat all together,
just gonna make it tough.
Okay.
So the panade's done.
Potatoes are done.
Okay.
Let's get into
grindin' the meat.
So let me grab, uh,
let me see here.
I've got --
Here's my sirloin
and my brisket.
Okay.
Make sure that's ready.
So there we go,
nice, big piece.
Cut it in a strip.
Make it a little
bit more manageable.
This is the brisket here.
Actually, the thinner
I can do it,
the better, especially
with that fat cap on top.
Okay. Like so.
And I -- like I said,
if you have, you know, like,
anytime you're trying
to slice something,
if you're gonna
have to slice it,
if you can have it
a little bit a frozen,
especially when it's going
through that little mixer,
or, you know, that blade,
it's gonna make it a lot easier.
So here's the sirloin.
Okay. That gets me enough
to get started
'cause it takes a little bit.
Okay. Just throw it right on...
Stand back. Don't have this
aiming at anybody.
We drop it right in.
So here's what's happening.
We're makin' old-school
meatloaf on "Big Bite."
This is not
your ordinary meatloaf.
I'll see ya in a bit.
Welcome back to "Big Bite."
So I've got this meatloaf
that we're gonna stuff
with Andouille sausage.
I've already made
the Andouille.
And it's sitting down
there in the fridge.
And it's gonna be
a free-form.
But we're gonna stuff it
right in the middle of it
just like it was a big sausage.
So over to, uh, the mirepoix.
Get a little heat on here.
Little olive oil.
And I was just right
in the middle
of doing this cast
of characters.
So you've got this --
onions, celery, carrots.
Really nice and easy.
Okay.
Move the garlic outta the way.
Okay. We'll just add
a bit of salt to 'em
to kinda expedite this a bit.
Let me just rough chop
some garlic in here.
Okay.
Garlic's ready to go.
We'll drop that down.
And I already hit a little
bit of salt into there.
And like I said,
all I'm gonna do
is just kinda sweat 'em a bit.
Now, let's look
at the potatoes.
Fingerling potatoes
in the water.
You can see the dried salt
around the edge here.
These should be
just about done.
Fork tender, perfect.
And this is where things
are gonna get weird.
Follow me.
Bring this over.
Go right here.
Drain the potatoes.
They're not gonna come out.
That's fine.
I'll put 'em back in there.
But this is where it
gets kinda interesting.
Watch this.
Bring the sheet tray.
Got a little parchment
paper there.
I was waiting
for this to happen.
Okay.
Now drop the potatoes
on to the sheet tray.
Nice salt in there.
Great flavor already
built into 'em.
Like I said, super tender.
Gotta kinda spread 'em
out a little bit,
not too far to the edge.
Drop the parchment paper
on top of 'em.
And wait for it...
Exactly.
Now...
they're gonna smash real easy
when they're, uh...
Voilà. Huh?
Winner winner, chicken dinner?
What do you think of that move?
Not the spinning the tray thing,
but the other move.
Isn't that cool?
So they're nice and hot.
They smash easy.
Now we'll just let 'em cool.
And we'll mess with 'em
in a little bit. Okay?
Drop those back here.
Okay.
Veggies have had
a chance to sweat.
Just sweated these a bit,
took the crunch out.
We'll let 'em
just cool down.
You know, I'm not
too worried about it.
We're gonna cook
this meatloaf right now.
So I'm not too worried that
these hot veggies
are gonna cook the meat.
It kinda poaches a little bit.
That's not gonna be the issue.
I just don't wanna
necessarily mix all that
in with my hand
and have it all be
screaming hot.
Okay.
This goes here.
And let's bring
the meat up.
We'll get a little bit of salt,
some black pepper,
a little, uh, mustard powder.
Everybody knows this move.
Their mom used to do it,
half a cup of ketchup.
Now, I make a variety
of barbecue sauces.
So this is my bourbon
brown sugar barbecue sauce.
That was too bad, wasn't it?
A little hot sauce,
whatever your favorite is
and depending how spicy you
wanna make this,
and a little
Worcestershire of course.
That's the right size.
Okay.
Gonna mix the meat
up real quick.
Little bit there.
Shouldn't start mixin' yet.
We'll drop in the mirepoix
with the garlic.
That's had a chance
to cool down a little bit.
Okay.
Now we get the panade
with the milk,
the couple eggs.
And the idea is to mix this up
as little as possible
and get it done
as quick as possible,
um, so we don't beat it up
and make it all --
all tough.
Okay.
Look at that, though.
All that flavor.
Mix it as little as possible.
Have everything done.
There we go.
I think that looks good.
We'll see what it looks like
when we dump it
out here onto the foil.
Get it all, little bit more.
And this is a lot of meatloaf.
Don't worry, you'll have
leftovers with this.
Wait till you see
how we present it.
It's gonna be so cool.
Okay.
So now, kinda layin' it
out here like this,
kinda forming this up
to a rectangle.
Got all that
seasoning in there.
Okay. Give me a second.
That's why I have
the foot pedals.
Wash my hands more time
in this one little piece.
Now we grab the Andouille.
Okay.
Look at this.
Gonna take this,
kinda roll it into a sausage.
You got everything,
smoked paprika, sweet paprika,
cumin, chili powder,
red chili flake,
a little cayenne
all mixed in there.
Okay. So now what I'm gonna do
is just kinda bring
this over halfway there.
Bring this over halfway.
Okay, like that.
See how we're startin'
to form that together?
You pickin' up
what I'm layin' down?
Oh, exactly.
Stuffed inside of it.
We're gonna cook
the whole thing up.
So take this, roll it over,
continue to roll it.
There we go.
Okay, we're gonna twist
this end up nice and tight,
twist this end up
nice and tight.
Huh? Right there?
On the seam -- Right --
It looks like one big, round,
stuffed meatloaf.
Into the oven, 350 degrees.
We'll take it out later,
out of the foil,
crisp it up.
You're gonna love it.
I got a lot to do.
I'll see you in a bit.
Welcome back to "Big Bite."
Yes, I am canning bacon.
No, I'm not.
I'm actually making
some fantastic whiskey
with a little thing
we call a fat wash.
So I rendered
down some bacon.
I've got some whiskey here,
gonna dump it right in.
Let this whiskey take on
all this fantastic bacon flavor.
And then to -- well, to --
to get the fat out of it
that I'm imparting flavor
with right now,
I'm gonna freeze it.
Gonna freeze it
and then I'm gonna strain it.
And all that comes together
to make a little bacon whiskey.
Okay.
So we got all kinds
of homemade goods
goin' on around here.
And one of 'em is meatloaf.
Let me throw this
in the freezer.
One of 'em is meatloaf.
And it's comin' out
of the oven right now.
Take a look.
Stuffed with Andouille sausage.
Did all the grinding myself.
Now what I'm gonna do
is just open this up,
throw a little
barbecue sauce on it
and pop it back in the oven.
So it should be extremely hot.
That's always fun.
There ya go.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Now the great thing is is
by locking it into the foil,
by keeping it in the foil,
I had a chance
to really lock all the fat
and flavor in there.
So as it cooked and the fat's
trying to leave the building,
all that panade grabbed it.
Now I'm just gettin'
a little barbecue sauce
right on top of that.
There we go.
Grab this bad boy.
Back in the oven -- oven for
about another 30 minutes.
Then we're good to go.
350 degrees.
Now, I've got some oil
workin' over here already.
Making sure
that's at 350.
I cooked these potatoes
in a little saltwater,
actually heavy saltwater.
And now I take 'em,
just start droppin' 'em down.
There we go.
We use these
fingerling potatoes.
So we'll load that up
a little bit.
And then we're gonna do
this great barbecue sauce.
I don't wanna overload this.
There we go.
You can't just
do a French fry.
You can't do
a boring baked potato.
You can't just
do mashed potatoes,
not with a meatloaf that's
stuffed with Andouille sausage.
Have to go big.
And since we're in the theme
of grinding meats
and doing scratch-made
ingredients,
why not make our own bourbon,
apply a little bacon fat
and bacon,
and make a cocktail
out of it?
It's the holy trinity.
Now I'm gonna make --
Of course, I've got
my own barbecue sauce,
my own wing sauce,
a few of these things.
But I'm gonna make a little
fortified sauce here
that's gonna go with these --
with these, uh, twice-fried
or twice-cooked potatoes.
So a little of my wing sauce.
Of course, a little hot sauce.
Let's see here.
There we go.
A little agave
to sweeten it up.
And a little more vinegar
coming for some ACB,
some apple cider vinegar.
And last but not least,
you know I'm not gonna
make anything that's spicy
that's not gonna have
a little Sriracha.
There we go.
So you got the sweet.
You got the heat.
You got the Guy Fieri
wing sauce.
All that together,
don't need to cook it
or anything.
And it'll keep in the fridge.
All right.
Potatoes are down.
Meatloaf is finishin'.
We got a cocktail to make.
I gotta freeze some bourbon.
Come back.
You're gonna love this.
Welcome back to "Big Bite."
Yes, making my own
bacon bourbon.
What I did is I cooked down
some bacon,
took the fat, the bacon,
everything with some,
uh, whiskey, let it set up,
strained it,
then froze it,
got the fat to float to the top.
Now I'm straining it.
And this, ladies and gentlemen,
is making bacon bourbon, okay?
We'll let that
rest right there.
Let's make a cocktail. Okay?
Now, a little
maraschino cherries,
the good kind, okay?
You know there's the ones
that are glowing.
I don't like to use those kind.
So a couple of those.
Get a little bit
of bitters here, little --
little bacon bitters,
we call it.
If you don't,
just regular bitters'll be fine.
But since we're in that
bacon theme, little maple syrup.
This is the maple pig cocktail.
There we go.
Touch of some lemon juice.
Okay.
A few ice cubes.
Give this a little muddle,
break those cherries down a bit.
Now we'll pour one.
I know this is not
the conventional thing
to pour it in --
pour it out of.
But, uh, throw a little bit
of that bacon bourbon in.
Give it a little stir
as to not bruise the bourbon.
Okay.
Here we go,
right over the top.
Beautiful with those
muddled cherries.
Give it a little
squeeze of some lemon.
And...
oh, we're off to the races.
I'm tellin' you this,
the bacon flavor is so intense.
With the cherries
and the bacon, fantastic.
All right. So I've got
some fingerling potatoes
that are just
finishing on a fry.
I've got a barbecue sauce that
I'm gonna toss these in that
are just going
to rock your world.
I'm tellin' you, this is kind
of like the best of --
of, uh, baked potato,
fried potato,
skillet potato,
French fries all at once.
So we'll take that.
Pop the potatoes
right in the bowl.
Now, the barbecue sauce
I made with some Sriracha,
a little agave,
wing sauce,
hot sauce,
all coming together.
And that's right over here.
And a little sweet,
I hit a little bit of,
uh, agave in there to --
to make it nice and sweet.
Pour some of this
over the top.
Give that a quick
little toss.
Oh, yeah.
Tons of flavor.
This is kind of like, uh,
Vegas fries at my restaurant
but just in a little bit
different form.
Get a few of these out
with some of the sauce.
You'll wanna make that sauce on
the side, make a little extra.
It'll keep in the fridge.
Okay.
Now to the star
of the show.
It all started
about the meatloaf.
I was sayin', "How
do you make fantastic meatloaf?"
I've had meatloaf a million
definitely ways.
What I did is first,
I made Andouille sausage.
I ground my own pork, uh,
did all the spices,
smoked paprika, sweet paprika,
cumin, chili powder,
red pepper flake.
You name it.
Everybody was in there.
Let that come together with some
great flavor and some garlic.
Then I ground
my own sirloin and brisket.
And I just want you to see...
Nice and easy.
Still nice and warm.
Stuffed it inside
of this brisket
and sirloin meatloaf
with this panade.
And tell me that
doesn't look dynamite.
And it's nice and light
and tender and falls apart.
That's what we're lookin'
for right there.
Mm.
I mean, if you're gonna go
to the point and eat --
If you're eatin' meatloaf,
if this is what's on the menu,
then it should look like this.
And I know how much fat,
and I know exactly
what I put in there
'cause I made it.
It's sweet and tender
on the outside.
As soon as you get
in the middle,
that Andouille's got
tons of spice.
It's a little bit more firm.
Got some mirepoix
and some garlic.
And that panade holds it
all together.
Mmm.
That's how you do meatloaf.
You know you want the recipe,
foodnetwork.com/guysbigbite.
You'll love this.
When you're out at the ranch,
this is what you
should eat --
should be eating,
that along with
a little bacon bourbon.
See ya next week.
That is killer.