You know, when you think about
what you're gonna give
for Valentine's Day, everybody
says you give chocolates.
But me, uh, I'm not much
of a dessert, sweets guy.
So I don't know a box of
chocolates for me is gonna work.
But I do agree.
You gotta give chocolate
on Valentine's Day.
So mine'll be inside of a dish.
That's the idea,
starting off with
my grilled chicken mole negro.
Coated in a smoky chile rub,
grilled and served
with a dark mole sauce,
deeply flavored
with dried chiles and chocolate.
I mean, this makes
the perfect Valentine's Day.
Now I've also got a hominy
with pomegranate and cilantro,
fortified with black beans and
a citrus tequila vinaigrette.
So that's it. We got, uh,
chicken and chocolate,
and we got tequila
and salad dressing.
I know it sounds crazy,
but, uh, trust me.
You're gonna love this.
So stoking up the fire,
getting it ready because we
are gonna grill some chicken.
And the sauce
that's gonna go with it,
I'm not kidding you,
is gonna knock you out.
So let's talk about this sauce.
Let's talk about this, uh, mole.
Now mole's kinda like sayin'
to somebody, uh, "Yeah.
I've got a great --
I've got a great salsa.
Or I got a great curry. Or I got
a great barbecue sauce."
Moles are those kinda recipes
that have been passed down
through the family for years.
So as I'm explaining this,
I'm trying to open this pepper.
Um, what is it?
Well, there's a lot
of different styles of it.
This is gonna be a dark mole.
And typically,
what would that have in it?
Exactly.
Some chocolate.
So in this dark mole,
we're gonna start off here
with a little ancho chile.
This was picked at its peak
of ripeness, then dried.
And you're gonna get
this really nice, dark, rich,
almost like cherry
and chocolate.
I mean, fantastic.
So we're gonna toast these off.
About four of each.
All right.
So some of the anchos in.
Now let's get my favorite.
This is the guajillo. Okay.
Take these seeds
and stems out
because we don't
want the stems particularly
or too many of the seeds 'cause
there's inherently
gonna be a few in there.
Tear these up.
Toast 'em off.
I got some boiling water
to reconstitute these.
And they'll be going
into this mole.
Okay.
So we'll drop all these in
and let that hang out.
And I'm -- Not raging heat.
You can just see it starting
to smoke a little bit.
And I'm touching it. And if you
don't wanna do it that way,
just get the tongs out.
Just move 'em
around a little bit.
Don't want 'em to burn, but we
do want 'em to toast. Okay?
And they're almost there.
You can see how they've really
started to darken up.
There was the original color --
kind of a reddish hue.
There's the toasted color.
Okay? So we're almost there.
Just about another minute or so.
All right.
While that's workin',
let's talk about hominy.
Listen. I had this buddy
when I was a kid,
and he was such a hominy
fanatic.
I had never had hominy before.
Or maybe I had.
But he used to love hominy
any way he could get it --
if he could get it cooked,
if he could get it cold
in a salad.
And that was the first time
I think I really ever went, "Oh.
Wait a second.
I like this stuff."
Now this is dried hominy.
If you can go
from the dried corn and,
uh, cook 'em yourself,
you're just gonna
get a better texture.
So these have been soakin'
for about 24 hours.
I'll dump it in.
And this is going to make --
I know this is gonna sound --
We'll call it a slaw salsa.
A slaw salsa.
This is gonna be part salsa,
part salad, all from the hominy.
I'll double the water on it.
There we go.
You're gonna let those cook
till they're nice and tender.
And speaking of nice
and tender and cooking,
that's just about enough there.
'Kay.
This is gonna -- You don't have
to do it in a cast iron
if you don't want to.
I like it because it's not gonna
stain the pan.
Uh, non-stick would not be
your choice
on this to toast these.
Just enough water.
We'll let 'em steep.
Matter of fact, I can even
take 'em off the heat 'cause
the work has been done.
That hot pan, that hot water,
those hot chiles...
They're gonna steep
and get nice and pliable.
We'll be able to work with 'em.
Okay?
Let me get some heat
under this.
Uh, let's talk
about the chicken.
All right.
The key here is free-range.
I'm a big fan of chicken.
I'm a big fan of anything that's
in that free-range attitude.
No hormones, no antibiotics.
The great thing
about a free-range chicken
is it's had a chance
to not live in a cage but go out
and work and be a chicken,
all right?
And build --
And there's something.
I mean, that just does flavor.
You got that chicken moving.
You got that chicken
finding things, foraging.
There's just gotta be --
Well, that all works
into the development
of the flavor of the chicken.
So my butcher --
gotta have a good butcher --
...broke it down to me
into eight pieces.
Look at that.
Eight beautiful pieces,
no feet included.
And we're gonna make
a little dry rub for it.
So let me get a bowl.
Got a nice fire going
with some briquette charcoal,
some lump charcoal and then I
threw on some hard oak.
Wanna get a little bit
of that smoky
wood flavor coming into this.
So we'll start off
with just a touch of cayenne,
little cracked black pepper,
little more kosher salt,
granulated garlic,
a little chipotle
chile powder...
a little ancho chile powder.
There we go.
The cumin.
Okay. Now that chipotle
and the ancho, why the two?
Looking for a little bit more
heat coming from that chipotle.
You had the cayenne. Of course
that's really big heat.
Then we'll go to the chipotle,
then the ancho.
All right. Mix this up.
And what I'm gonna do --
And this really goes back
to the old-school methods.
I'm gonna season this
ahead of time
and just let this sit here
for a second out on the counter.
Remember,
this is all the bone in.
We'll get some great color
out of this rub.
Look at that.
Great way to start
this whole thing off.
Now you can get the whole
chicken yourself
and break it down.
But this just gets right
to the point.
Give this a little rub,
little flip.
Okay. One more.
And then enough
to get the other side.
So here's what's happenin'.
We're, um,
sharing our Valentine's Day love
with a little chocolate.
It's just gonna happen to be
in a dish served
over some chicken with, uh,
a funky hominy slaw.
Oh, you're gonna love this.
Write it down for sure.
See ya in a minute.
You know, I wish I had an intro
song coming back in to like...
You know, something like that.
Do you guys
have a song like that?
Would you send it my way?
I'd love to see that.
Well, welcome
to "Guy's Big Bite."
We're still back here
in the kitchen, uh,
making Valentine's Day
happiness.
Uh, yes, there will be chocolate
coming into this dish.
I do not put chocolate
in the box.
That's just not my style.
So what am I making?
I'm making some fantastic --
Well, not yet.
But it'll be
a grilled chicken mole negro.
So busting down some onions
right now for this mole sauce.
And I have some peppers steeping
over here.
Got some ancho in there,
which is gonna
give some really nice, deep,
rich tones of pepper and then
a little bit of that spiciness
coming through
from the guajillo.
I toasted those off
just a second ago.
Now they're steeping
in the hot water.
There we go.
Some onions done.
Let me pop a little bit
of garlic,
give this a quick little dice
and into the food processor
we'll go.
And this is where we're gonna
start the beginning
of this, uh, mole.
Now as I said, moles, well,
everybody's got a recipe for it.
Or a lot of, uh, you know,
a lot of my Latino friends,
their family has it.
And so trying to get one of
these from somebody
is kinda like trying
to get the family secret.
Um, let me see here.
This is hot.
There we go.
Okay.
So we want the peppers
and about a cup of the liquid.
Okay.
Little bit of that pepper,
steeping water.
I'll just go
over the old-school way.
I'm in the outdoor kitchen.
I can drag it over the top
of everything.
So we get the onions in.
Now comes a whole host
of ingredients --
Mexican oregano, cloves,
cinnamon and sesame seeds.
Oh, yeah.
Toasted sesame seeds.
Absolutely.
There's gonna be some more nuts
in this in just a second.
Little toasted sesame seed.
Mexican oregano.
You hear me talk about it
on "Big Bite" all the time.
Big, big oregano flavor.
And we'll do
a little ground clove.
This is just a touch.
There we go.
Just a touch of some cinnamon.
Yes.
And it does have those tones --
the cinnamon,
the chocolate, the sugar.
Okay.
There we go.
Now these are the two
ingredients
that you're probably gonna
look at me and say, "Really?
That's in a mole?"
And it's going to be, uh-huh,
slivered almonds and raisins.
I know.
Don't shoot the messenger.
But you're gonna dig this.
So we'll get in some raisins.
And that -- You know,
raisins have that real --
that distinct, sweet, um, like,
like, dark brown sugar kinda
flavor to 'em.
That's why they
play into this so well.
And then the almonds'll create
some really nice texture to it.
And again, you're wanting
to think, "Where was this made?"
We're talking about
down in Mexico.
We're talkin'
about what ingredients,
what was available down there.
Dried nuts
definitely play into it.
Okay.
This is the one --
this is the one that's gonna
take some explanation.
This is brown sugar.
The Mexican sugar
that looks like it's in a cone.
And this is unrefined.
So this isn't a white sugar
with molasses added to it.
This is an unrefined
Mexican sugar
that has a really nice, rich
molasses smell and flavor to it.
And it's called piloncillo.
There we go.
Just depends on
how dried out it got.
Okay.
All that together.
And one last thing -- a little
bit of chicken stock.
Let me get my heat up
on this Dutch oven.
Why the Dutch oven?
Okay.
That's a really good question.
The Dutch oven because you
gotta think about this.
We got some --
we got some sweet going into it.
We even have more sweet
going into it.
And this is gonna
go low and slow.
And nothing worse
than going low and slow
and burning it because
you're not keeping an eye on it.
So these old Dutch ovens,
that was kind of the, uh,
the idea
is to have enough insulation
that it wasn't gonna burn,
okay?
This...
Eh, it comes out the sides.
Don't worry about that.
Clean that up later.
It's a really nice look, though.
Awesome.
There we go.
All right.
You know what?
I gotta set this down 'cause I'm
forgetting one key ingredient.
Let's talk about lard.
Now lard --
What are we t--
So -- So here's
some pig fat for ya.
Now here's something
you're not gonna believe.
If I told you that this had
less saturated fat than butter,
would you believe me?
Well, you should 'cause
it's my show.
I'm telling you the truth.
Less than butter.
And here's the beauty
about this.
This right here,
we're talking tons of flavor.
Now this isn't just bacon fat.
That's not what this is.
This doesn't have a lot
of flavor to it.
In the Latin world of food, what
were they using to cook with?
Well, pigs are abundant.
They're sustainable.
The Italians and the Greeks,
we had the olive oil.
And the French,
you have the butter.
Well, in Mexico,
you got the pig fat.
All right.
So that cooks down.
It's gonna bubble just a bit.
There we go.
Awesome.
Okay.
Give this a little stir.
Oh!
You should smell the flavors
right off the bat --
raisins, sugar, cinnamon,
nutmeg coming right through.
But don't worry.
This is not a sweet dish.
This is savory.
Okay.
Done there.
Now let's get the chicken down.
Uh, mole... I'm telling ya.
So many ingredients,
I gotta remember 'em all.
Look at the chicken.
Made a nice, little dry rub.
We've got some salt
and pepper, of course.
Then we've got
a little chipotle powder,
little ancho chile powder,
little cayenne, little cumin,
of course.
Look at this.
Bone in.
Nice, big bird too.
I mean,
that is a real-deal-size bird.
So what I'm gonna do is
let this get hot.
I've already oiled the grate,
flip it over, charred the skin.
But this -- See, a lot of times
you wanna see the chicken
go into the mole, and that's
how it would cook together.
Me, I want a little bit
of this crust,
a little bit of this char,
a little more of
this California-style to it.
So we'll grill the chicken,
get it done
and add it with the mole.
So here's the last thing
I got -- the hominy.
I haven't even talked
about that.
Oh. It is gonna be this
hominy slaw salsa.
Beans are gonna go in there.
Pomegranate's going in there.
So what I've gotta do --
Look. We're just about done.
Check that out.
I'll drain this,
drain and wash my beans.
You come back.
We'll keep putting it together.
And I gotta keep an eye
on the mole.
So I'll see you in a little bit.
Mm.
Huh? Look at that.
Steaming hot hominy.
Don't hear that every day.
Oh, that's fantastic.
We're doing this whole
Valentine's Day
cookin' with chocolate.
But I say mole,
and I think hominy.
I don't know why.
But talking of mole,
look at this.
A beautiful, deep, dark,
rich mole that's gonna go
with this grilled chicken
that I have over here.
Really nice, um, Mexican theme
going to it. Oh.
We've got everything from
slivered almonds, brown sugar,
raisins, spices, guajillo,
ancho chiles in there, onions,
garlic, a little chicken stock.
Speaking of chicken stock,
I need to get
a little bit more in there.
Just getting a touch too thick.
And I'm trying to keep
that heat down.
And what's the star
of a great mole?
Exactly.
A little chocolate.
Now this is
the Mexican-style chocolate
you'll find in the markets.
What I'm gonna do is...
I'm gonna try to break it here
if I don't break --
There we go.
That and...there we go.
Give it a little grate.
But I'll ya something.
As much time as this is
gonna spend here working,
I'm just gonna
throw the whole thing in.
But I'll do this just so I kinda
follow some of the rules.
Hey. Look over there.
Okay.
You were gonna do it
anyways, right?
So that chocolate's not just
regular chocolate.
It's not overly sweet.
But it's got a little bit of a,
like,
a little cinnamon undertone,
little nutmeg to it.
So we'll let this just sit here
and cook down.
And again, with time, this just
becomes really luxurious.
Remember, we got a little bit
of manteca,
we got a little pork fat
in there.
Fantastic.
Okay.
Hominy's done.
Beans are rinsed.
Let's get into some chicken.
Now this chicken
has a nice dry rub on it.
And it's a free-range bird.
Big, beautiful breast
right there.
Skin on, bone in,
all kinds of flavor.
And we got the wings as well.
So we'll throw this right
into the oven
right around 350 degrees.
Okay?
Tuck it right around the corner.
Voilà.
Okay. Hominy.
Okay.
Let's get into the hominy.
Let me get rid
of this chocolate.
Let's --
I did a little zesting.
And this is always
such a boring part of this,
but it's so critical,
because if you wanna really get
that awesome citrus flavor,
you're gonna
have to do a little zesting
without getting all that acid.
So first we'll go in with lime
and orange zest.
And this is gonna
be this dressing for --
What should I call it?
I called it a slaw --
slaw salsa?
Something along those lines.
That's exactly what it is.
It's part slaw, part salsa
because we're using the hominy,
but we're also using the beans.
So these are all gonna come
together.
And I'll show you the key
ingredient here in a second,
which you're gonna love this.
'Cause you're thinking
Valentine's Day.
Of course
you're thinking tequila.
Little bit of juice.
Lime juice in here.
Okay.
So the juice is in.
How about a little
red chile flake?
Touch of some cumin.
Now we got acid in here.
We got a little bit of spice.
What do we need next?
going with a little agave.
So a little sweetness
of the agave.
You know what?
Valentine's Day.
Eh -- tequila.
We need tequila.
I think that says -- that's --
Nothing says "I love you"
like a little tequila.
There's something
about the combination
of tequila, lime and agave.
A little sweetness,
a little tequila
and a little lime...
Uh, I think they call
that a margarita.
So when you're almost making
a margarita dressing,
it just kinda
triggers a natural memory.
So -- and it works great.
And it's not overdone.
But it's that little bite of
that tequila, a little bit
of that fresh lime juice
and a little bit of that agave
that works so well together
in a drink,
work perfect in a dressing.
Oh.
I'm gonna tell ya something --
The zest does everything.
One last key,
super-key ingredient --
It's the pomegranate.
I went to Croatia.
I saw pomegranate trees
growing everywhere.
And I will tell ya something --
I've always been a fan
of pomegranates.
I didn't know exactly what they
looked like on the tree,
but they were awesome.
So here's my little technique
to get these pomegranates out.
Just take 'em.
I think everybody uses this one.
Hit it with the wooden spoon.
Knock 'em out.
That's it.
So I'm gonna add the beans,
uh, the hominy.
You got the pomegranates.
Mole's done.
Gotta fix the chicken 'cause
it's gonna burn up.
And you come back, and I'm gonna
put it all together
on a nice platter.
It's gonna look fantastic.
See ya in a bit.
Welcome back.
All right.
So I'm just puttin'
this all together.
Still thinkin'
about that theme song.
I'm thinking maybe
some soft piano.
Not s-- No, I agree.
Not so much. Okay.
So some cilantro
and some onions,
some scallions ready to go.
Chicken is just finishing up
in the oven.
Let's grab this.
I had to cover it.
You know, sometimes
with a wood-fired oven,
things get a little crazy
in here.
And, uh, well worth it
because take a look at that.
Gorgeous.
There we go.
Bring it over.
Now the mole sauce -- Oh!
This is -- I mean,
this is really coming together.
Nothing says "I love you"
like mole.
Well, I don't know.
You put that in a box,
someone would be really, really
scared what you're giving them.
But here's what we've got.
It's really cooked down
nice and silky.
We've got chocolate in there.
We've got, uh,
some ancho chile, some chipotle,
a little guajillo pepper,
almonds, raisins.
Oh, the raisins --
I'm telling you,
that's one of my favorite parts
about it.
Okay.
Now let's drop this chicken
right on here.
Look at that.
Nestle it right in there.
Beautiful, isn't it?
And the chicken
has a dry rub on it --
salt and pepper, of course,
little cumin,
little chipotle powder.
Right inside.
What do you think?
And I'm just gonna give
these all just a little kiss
of some sauce.
Oh. This is gorgeous.
This is -- Well, they say
you're supposed to give
chocolate for Valentine's Day.
I'm doing it.
I'm just giving it
a different form
than you'd usually expect.
Okay.
This guy on top of that.
Look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
And you know what?
This is kind of a quick mole.
I'll be honest with you.
This one'll go pretty fast.
You can get
this done in 45 minutes or so.
But not to say
that it lacks in flavor one bit.
All right. There we are.
Let me get this outta my way.
And let's get to this slaw,
this slaw salsa.
Now drain the beans,
black beans.
Check this out.
Got a little pomegranate
in there, a little orange zest,
a little lime zest,
tequila, agave,
a little bit of cumin.
The beans go in.
The hominy --
Started this from dry.
Boiled it a little bit.
Little bit of salt.
It's tender,
but it's got texture.
Drop that in.
Grab a little more
of the cilantro.
Just kinda give it a little
rough tear right into that.
Mm.
And this vinaigrette --
I mean, come on.
Look at the beans.
Look at the beautiful
pomegranate
just poppin' through.
Touch of some salt.
And you know what the great
thing about this is?
Is this is gonna eat
like a salsa.
It goes right alongside.
But then it's nice and rich
with the beans in there,
so it'll be kind of a salad
alongside of that.
Oh.
Gotta get a bite of this.
Tender beans, little snap,
just a little pop of
that pomegranate,
the big chew coming through from
that hominy, the vinaigrette,
the tequila shining
right through, little agave,
little kiss of the sweetness.
I gotta serve this
all up for my mom
and for Lori, get this ready.
But I'm just going to --
All right.
For responsibility's sake,
I need to just,
you know, kinda break into this.
I mean, I'm not having --
I'm not eating ahead of time.
I just wanna make sure that Lori
and my mom are getting the best.
Don't tell anybody.
Oh! That's exactly
what I wanted to do!
Grill the chicken,
give it its own texture,
its own identity,
and then add that awesome mole.
So many times
you'll find that chicken
cooked in the sauce.
It's great.
Don't get me wrong.
But this has another layer.
This has some crunch.
This is -- Oh!
This is what you wanna do.
Foodnetwork.com/guys-big-bite.
Get the recipe. Download this.
This'll be awesome for --
I don't know.
You take the holiday,
especially Thanks--
especially Thanksgiving
and Valentine's Day.
This is your bird.
I'll see you next week
on "Big Bite."