Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
This trip...
Gimme a high-five.
-[Laughs]
...we're cruising
out of the city...
-Are you ready?
-I have my seatbelt on.
...for a full hour
of small-town standouts...
Just a little
somethin' somethin'.
...everything from
an oldschool Wisconsin diner...
That is really good.
...to a funky Salem shanty.
Like we're making
a witch's brew.
A quirky club in Alabama...
Wow, that's weird.
...and a slope-side
Park City café.
I can't say it's good.
I can say it's great,
though.
Plus, a local legend
in Carolina...
You are a hero
in this community.
...and a Tennessee joint
Here we go.
turning up the heat.
Awesome.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪
I got a great story for ya.
I'm here in Summerville,
South Carolina,
about 20 miles west
of Charleston.
Now, this is where
a local football star
who goes on to play for Alabama
has a career-ending injury.
So what's he decide to do?
Yep, come back to his hometown
and open up exactly
what they needed:
a hot dog joint.
This is Perfectly Frank's.
♪
Frankie Elvis.
French toast Frankie.
I didn't know you could do
so many things with a hot dog.
[ Laughs ]
So, what makes
this place so good?
It's not only the food.
Perry was the star quarterback
on the high school football team
in the late '70s.
Order up!
FIERI:
That'd be Perry Cuda,
who drew up a whole new playbook
for dogs back in '07.
He has so many different things
that he puts on a hot dog.
MAN: Pulled pork.
-Bananas and peanut butter
and bacon.
Macaroni & cheese.
Anything you can imagine
on a hot dog.
All right,
Frank Cuda dog up.
I like the one he named
after his dad,
with the blue-cheese
cole slaw.
♪
-What are we gonna make?
-The Frank Cuda.
So, this is named
after your dad.
-It is.
-Okay, let's get into the chili.
-Okay.
-Whose recipe?
-My recipe.
-First thing in, 80/20?
Yep, ground beef, diced onion,
granulated garlic, cumin,
BOTH: oregano.
-Yes, sir. Brown sugar.
-Nice call.
-Paprika.
-Chili powder?
-Chili powder.
A little yellow mustard,
Worcestershire sauce, tabasco.
[ Whistles ]
Crushed tomatoes,
and cinnamon.
Red-chili flake,
and some olive oil.
How long you gonna
let this cook down,
'til that meat
just breaks up
into little pieces,
-Exactly.
-really nice and thin?
-About 45 minutes to an hour.
What kind of dog
we gonna put it on?
[Grunts]
-All-beef, skinless,
yeah, ready to go.
-What are we into now?
-We're gonna make
the blue-cheese cole slaw.
Shredded cabbage,
shredded carrots.
No culinary classes
for you,
just experimenting on
-Oldschool.
-your friends and family.
-Exactly.
A little cole slaw dressing,
mayonnaise, sugar,
apple-cider vinegar,
celery seed,
salt, black pepper,
and crumbled blue cheese.
Then, we just mix it up
by hand.
What other body part
would you mix it with?
[laughing] Well.
-Gimme a high-five.
Time to bring it
together.
-To the fryer.
-We're gonna fry the dog?
Fry it up.
Chili we made earlier.
♪
Me like. Don't go
skimpy on the chili.
Mm-hmm-mm!
[ Laughs ]
[ Grunts ]
-Cheese sauce.
-All right.
Fried applewood-
smoked bacon.
Not just bacon, it's
fried bacon.
-Fried bacon, correct.
Some of our blue-cheese slaw,
crispy onions,
and that's the Frank Cuda dog.
♪
-Do I have any here?
-No.
Not at all.
-I like the dog.
I mean, you gotta start off
with a really good dog
right off the bat.
The chili's great.
-Thank you.
-Chili works perfect.
The crunchy onions,
of course, fantastic.
The slaw is
nice and cool.
Man! That's
a righteous dog, dude.
-Thank you.
-Nice job, Perry.
Thank you.
-Frank Cuda?
-Thank you.
Messy, but good.
-Frankie Valli up!
FIERI:
And these dogs are almost
as iconic as Perry.
Look at that guy!
Yeah.
A lot thinner then.
Perry hasn't just made
good with hot dogs.
There's a whole lot
more to this menu.
You can get anything:
salads, sandwiches, tacos.
-Sweet-tea-marinated pork chop.
-Awesome.
I think it may
be the best sandwich
I ever put in my face.
What's next in the adventure?
We're making red-eye
gravy mayonnaise
to go on our fried
pork-chop sandwich.
Red-eye gravy.
Now, just so you understand,
although I do look
like I'm full Cali,
my mom was from
North Carolina.
Red-eye gravy
is like a religion.
A little olive oil,
country ham.
That's
a country-desiac.
Brown sugar, garlic;
some árbol chilies,
little Mexican chilies;
strong black coffee.
So, we let this cook down,
let it reduce.
We take the ham blender.
We're gonna purée
the ham into the sauce?
We are.
[Grinding, whirring]
[ Outro plays ]
-All right.
-Whisk up the red-eye gravy,
red-eye gravy
into the mayonnaise.
-Let it chill?
-Ready to smear.
-So a little pork loin here.
-Right.
Take the cap off of it.
[ Thudding ]
and put it in the marinade.
And the sweet tea, this is
like sweet tea you drink?
-Sweet tea you drink.
-How long we let it marinate?
Six, twelve hours.
You can do it overnight.
It'll be better.
We're gonna make
the seasoned breader
for the fried
pork-chop sandwich.
Okay.
All-purpose flour, cornmeal,
pinch of salt,
black pepper, and some thyme.
And we'll take it
through the process here --
the all-purpose flour.
Into the buttermilk,
then into the dredge.
Into the fryer?
-Into the fryer.
And then,
we build the sandwich.
We do. Toast the bun
for the pork chop,
red-eye gravy mayonnaise,
and a good helping of it.
Lettuce.
All right, sounds like
the pork's done.
Yep. Pork chop.
Tomato.
-What's it called?
Sweet-tea-marinated
fried pork-chop sandwich.
The pork?
Cooked perfectly.
Not sweet --
it's not sweet or anything.
-Right.
I gotta say, the red-eye
gravy mayonnaise
is the bomb.
It doesn't taste
a ton like coffee.
You get the fattiness
of the mayo.
It's juicy,
it's got rich flavor,
and what I think
is really cool about it
is you're not a chef.
-No. No.
Don't claim to be.
-You're just a dude
that loves good food.
-Yep. Just wanted to bring
something different
to Summerville.
-That's good stuff.
-Thank you.
-Nice job.
-Thank you very much.
Sweet-tea-marinated
pork chop!
Gets a little messy,
but very good.
Now, what do you think?
He drags you out for dinner,
and he takes you
to a hot dog joint.
-We love it.
-You are a hero
in this community.
Summerville's lucky to have you.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate you coming.
-Nice to meet you, Perry.
You're an awesome guy, man.
-Thank you.
♪
Comin' up...Southern flavor
in Franklin, Tennessee...
I like where
you're going with it.
from jammin' jambalaya...
[Clink-clink]
This'll make ya happy, man.
...to some chicken
that's kickin'.
That's where you let the
funkalicious get in there.
♪
I'm in Franklin, Tennessee,
about 15 minutes south
of downtown Nashville,
to check out a joint the people
in the know say I gotta see.
This is 55 South.
Pork-chop sandwich.
There's no better place to be.
Everything is perfect.
Hot chicken,
bag of shrimp.
The food is amazing.
It's different,
it's fresh, it's tasty.
-BLT in the window.
-Plenty of variety --
that's what makes
it really good.
FIERI: And all part
of Jason McConnell's
personal road map.
A poli-sci grad
turned off by DC politics
and turned on
by Southern cookin'.
And, in 2010, it all became part
of the 55 South menu.
It's a little bit
of everything.
Cajun, it's country,
it's a little bit
of Memphis, Franklin.
FIERI:
Even a local dish I like
to get when I'm in town.
Hot chicken.
The hot chicken knocks
it out of the park.
It'll set you on fire.
What are we gonna
make first?
We are going to make
hot-chicken marinade.
-[mimicking accent] Marinade.
-It's got a little twang,
you know?
-I'm throwin' twang at it.
-You're doing good.
We got a little paprika --
it's the base 'cause you wanna
have red chicken.
We got salt, black pepper,
Louisiana hot sauce, cayenne.
-[Whistles]
Granulated garlic, a little oil.
You wanna get
this kind of going.
Got a little bit of water.
This is paste.
This is spackle.
♪
That's the napalm.
If you can't afford
pepper spray,
just carry
a handful of it
when you walk
down a dark alley.
[laughs] That look.
-It's not that bad.
Awesome.
-We're gonna marinade
and finish the chicken
sandwich with this.
We're gonna save
just a little bit.
We'll put the chicken in this.
Old Ranger Danger over here
took the chicken breast
and it gave it
a little score,
you know, just [slurp]
sucked it up.
Just gonna get
the paste on it.
Now, how long
would you really like
to let this marinate?
A couple of days.
♪
Now, we're gonna
make the dredge.
We got some flour with
a little bacon powder in it,
granulated garlic,
just a little paprika.
We really wanna get
some colors in that.
Cayenne, Creole seasoning.
And more salt.
-Okay.
Kind of an all-purpose
Cajun dredge.
And then, we've got
our atomic chicken.
♪
We got the oil.
-Got the oil.
-We're just gonna lay that in.
-No dropping these into a fryer.
McCONNELL:
No, you gotta go
with the skillet. 375.
-Three to five minutes?
-Yeah.
[ Sizzling ]
The key here is that
score to that breast.
That's where you let the
funkalicious get in there.
-So, we're good.
-Okay.
So, we're gonna do
a little white bread.
-White bread.
-Little mayo, a little --
-little schmear.
-A little schmear.
-Two pieces.
-Two?!
I'm not gonna fit
in my swimsuit.
A breast, a breast.
You're gonna put more
of that on there?
Enough already.
That's the way you normally
make it for people?
Yeah, it's a perfect amount.
This is a key component.
Gotta have lots of pickles.
And always, you know,
you gotta give it the --
bring it all together.
A lot more
than I bargained for.
Just a little
somethin' somethin'.
Here we go!
♪
Not hot.
Do I have any here?
Not here or here,
but like right here.
-A little.
-Little bit?
But you're good.
The chicken
is super-tender.
There's great crunch,
nice texture
on the outside of it.
Not overly done
with batter.
The pickles
are the only thing
that are gonna
save your life.
Chef, awesome job.
Definitely spicy.
Slightly peppery, good
crunch, texture, flavor --
this has got it all.
Outstanding.
This gentleman right here
is Lori Arnett's husband.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, he also happens
to be Jeff Arnett,
master distiller.
And libations
are just one thing
that anchors folks
to this place.
I love cold drinks,
and 55 South provides me
with something cool
to drink.
It's kind of a Cajun
Cheers, I guess.
-Cheers.
-[Laughter]
♪
I'm still sweatin'
after the chicken sandwich
that we had.
-Keeps you young.
If something makes you
young, it's jambalaya.
-This is real-deal.
-I'm just telling ya.
So, what are we...?
In your jambalaya --
Mine, I like to do
pork butt, chicken thighs,
smoked sausage --
holy trinity.
I mean,
I go the whole gambit.
Is that where we're going?
-Chicken and andouille.
Chicken and andouille.
We make the andouille here.
-You make the sausage?
-We do.
Of course you do.
♪
The mise is ready.
First thing, you got
a hot pan over here,
put some blended oil in,
chicken.
This is breast.
We're gonna get that
going just for a second.
Got some celery,
bell pepper, on-ion,
a little garlic.
-Lovin' it.
-Let that go for a second.
Really, just kind of
breaking up the chicken
in there a little bit.
-I gotcha.
We're gonna cut up
some of this andouille.
Look at that.
♪
So, we got the sausage
going in.
I like the way
this looks, man.
We're gonna do
some dried thyme,
basil, oregano,
chopped Italian parsley.
-Hot sauce?
-Some Louisiana hot sauce.
Creole.
-Yep.
I like where
you're going with it.
And then, we're gonna
do our liquids:
tomato juice, chicken stock,
a little bit
of crushed tomatoes.
Got a little simmer going on.
We're gonna add
some long-grain rice.
And now you can't leave
'til it's over.
We're just gonna let that simmer
'til all the rice absorbs
the liquid, and that's it.
If you gotta make
any phone calls,
check your emails, I can
watch the pot for a bit.
[ Sniff ]
Looks awesome.
Good color.
Lot of product,
lot of sausage.
♪
And a little extra hot sauce
on the top,
some fresh scallions, that's it.
That's all she wrote.
[ Outro plays ]
[as "Cool Hand Luke" Captain]
What we have here
is real-deal jambalaya.
Not too spicy.
The really nice piece
is the andouille.
Great smoke coming
out of that.
But that's the little element
that pushes it over the top.
It just makes
all the difference.
The rice is tender.
Little scallion
on the outside,
nice round heat coming
from that Cajun seasoning
and the spices you put in.
[Clink-clink]
This'll make you happy, man.
My friend.
♪
Chicken-and-sausage
jambalaya.
It's so good.
LORI:
It's not too spicy.
It's just perfect.
It's good to know
that we won't have
to just travel down
to New Orleans now
to enjoy some
good jambalaya.
You see?
♪
Up next...
a small-town treasure
in Daphne, Alabama.
-Don't tell anybody!
-I won't. Shh!
-You're putting us on the map.
-Part bar...
You are the Bloody Mary
capital of Alabama?
The world.
...part po' boys...
You rotate up
and in.
...and full-fledged crazy.
[laughs]
I can't keep up!
♪
Back in '36,
a guy named Frank Manci
started serving beer
in his gas station.
Now, over the years,
the pumps went away,
but the place became
a local legendary hangout.
Now, three generations later,
people say things
are better than ever,
a real unique experience that
they just can't quite explain.
So with that said,
I gotta check out
Manci's Antique Club.
Overwhelming.
[laughs]
You don't know
what you're walking into.
Every time you come in,
you see something new.
I'm actually just
a little freaked out.
[Laughter]
But not by the food.
-Here's your medium steak.
-Thank you.
Love it.
It's awesome.
FIERI:
It has been at this
Daphne, Alabama institution
for 83 years.
Mmm!
Wow, that's good!
Especially since '94...
-That's looking good.
-when Gwen Manci
started serving a full menu
-Mmm!
-at her husband, Alex's, bar,
-Thank you.
getting back to something
she's always loved.
My father owned
a few drive-ins,
and he's been having me
cook beside him
ever since I was
about 13.
Now, she's serving up
Gulf oysters,
piled-high burgers...
Go at it too fast,
it'll collapse on ya.
...a steak sandwich
to the max...
A lot of great
stuff on it.
...and their signature dish.
When they say --
They say, "Give me
a seafood po' boy."
Shrimp po' boy.
It's delicious.
Humongous.
Fresh, wonderful.
-I am the queen.
-You are po' boy royalty.
There you go.
Are you ready?
-I have my seatbelt on.
-All right, let's fly.
This is gonna be my dredge.
You're gonna start
with some milk.
-Chug your eggs, Rocky.
-Just kinda lightly mix.
Then, it's gonna be
a little bit easier
and hopefully not so messy.
I'm right here
behind the safety shield.
-All right.
-So, a little hot sauce.
And then, we have
a little beer.
That was full when
we started the show.
No, I refilled.
[ Laughs ]
I can't keep up!
Dry mix over here.
Flour.
-Pepper.
-Just a pinch.
A couple pinches.
Maybe one more.
That's four pinches
exactly.
-Yes.
-Some Cajun seasoning?
-You're right!
-It's not my first rodeo.
I can tell.
Blend it all together.
All right, we're through
with the dry ingredients.
We're gonna do it
with a wet and dry hand.
-I wanna see it. Look at this.
-Yes.
You're holding it
like you're a doctor.
Aahhh!
Deveined,
and it looks like
a little bit
of a butterfly on that.
-Yes.
-So they lay down nice.
Yes. Then we're gonna put 'em
back into this.
-And how many...?
-Eight shrimp go in a po' boy.
-Thank you.
-See? Wet, dry.
-Look at you!
-Yes!
Pluck 'em all out.
So, you did wet, dry,
and then
what'd you just do?
My hands aren't that big,
so I can't.
You could've got yourself
a little plate.
-Oh, I didn't wanna --
-Young Jedi,
you have to stay
in the training.
I know. [laughs]
And you don't wanna put 'em
all on top of each other.
They gotta have their own
little separate places to cook.
We got our buttered
po' boy bun.
Okay. Now, what's gonna go
on the po' boy?
We do everything
with tartar sauce.
So it's mayonnaise,
pickle relish,
white onions, red onions,
and then capers.
-Just a little bit of caper.
-Yes.
And it makes that shrimp
taste whoo!
It makes the shrimp
taste whoo!?
You want me
to grab the shrimp?
-Yes, thank you.
-Yahtzee!
-Ready?
Mmm! Wow.
When you say a po' boy --
when you look in a dictionary,
that should be the picture.
You taste the great shrimp,
you taste the fresh veggies,
the crunch of the lettuce,
served on a nice roll.
That's some really good
[laughing] tartar sauce.
Big explosion of happy.
-And all kinds of po' boys.
-Oyster po' boy.
The combo po' boy:
oysters and shrimp.
This is
a spider sandwich.
It's always good.
It's really a softshell-
crab po' boy.
GWEN:
It does look like a spider.
The legs and everything hang
off, and you eat it whole.
You know the stance.
Wanna learn?
-Sure, let's go.
-Get this hand --
you gotta get this
hand ready under here.
You get this one
over here.
[ Laughs ]
And then you rotate up
and in.
♪
Wow, that's good!
The reason you're doing it
is so you don't get
your bowling shirt messed up.
-Oh! I see.
-You see this?
You see how this whole thing's
working right here?
-Mm-hmm.
-[Cackles]
Mm, that is good.
-That just works.
-Doesn't it work?
Everything blends together.
-It does.
Kinda like the decor.
It's just a mishmash
of every weird thing
you could ever think of.
Your dad put all this in.
I put stuff in it, too,
but he put the majority.
The biggest thing
Alex put in this joint?
I'll have the Bloody Mary,
obviously.
You are the Bloody Mary
capital of Alabama?
-The world.
-It's wonderful.
FIERI:
And to go with the drink...
-Cheers!
-You need to flip.
-You know what you're gonna get.
-...from hand-cut steaks...
It's delicious.
It's very juicy.
...and fresh-grilled shrimp,
to something called
a Jazzy Burger,
topped with a local
favorite sauce.
Jezebel sauce?
-You bet.
-Yeah.
I use ground horseradish
from the root.
That gives it that extra kick.
Dried prepared
mustard, okay.
What is that
gelatinous fun?
This is apple jelly.
Not something I see
cooked with a lot.
Wait until you see
the next ingredients.
Pineapple preserves.
Does kitchen sink
come in soon?
Right at the end.
Black pepper.
Don't be scared.
Make sure you get plenty.
Now, put your lettuce, tomato,
and onion on there.
We've got an opening,
if you'd like to fill out
an application.
I have an opening, too,
and I plan
on shoving this
Jazzy Burger in it.
All right.
Just go jazzy
with that Jazzy sauce.
Do the stance.
Let's do the stance.
Do your own show!
[ Laughs ]
♪
Quite different, isn't it?
Yeah.
Wow, that's weird!
I mean, it's good.
Don't get me wrong.
It's good, but it is
tangy and spicy.
It's sweet; it's sour.
[laughing] This is the
craziest sauce I've ever had.
It's kind of sweet and spicy.
-There we go.
-Food's always been good.
It just gets better
all the time.
Other places don't have
the quirkiness
that this place has.
-Best-kept secret.
Well.
'Til now.
It is. But don't
tell anybody!
-I won't. Shh!
-You're putting us on the map.
Coming up on this
small-town power hour...
Wow!
Cold-weather comfort
in Park City, Utah...
You got sweet and heat,
on meat you can't beat.
...and a spot servin'
double-diamond dishes.
Good Mexican-Texan-
Southern combo
with a twist, elevated.
Real easy to explain.
♪
I'm here at Park City, Utah,
at the Silver Star Village,
which is right at the base
of Park City Mountain Resort.
Now, I know that's a mouthful,
but I want you
to find this place,
'cause I hear they're doing
way more than you'd find
at your average ski lodge.
This is the Silver Star Cafe.
Got a sea bass
and osso buco for 112.
The best place to eat
in Park City, bar none.
-And braised truffle.
-There really is something
that makes this place special
n Park City,
and it's Jeff and Lisa.
FIERI:
That would be veterans
of the local food biz
Jeff and Lisa Ward.
I've been doing restaurants
in town for a long time.
We've never owned one ourselves.
We took the plunge.
FIERI:
That was in 2010,
when they took over
this joint at the bottom
of the Silver Star chair lift.
-We're a local joint,
but we resonate with
the destination visitor.
FIERI:
Thanks to an eclectic menu,
cooked up by Chef Dave Bible.
Comfort food brought
to a higher level --
it's familiar,
but with some twists to it.
I have the pork osso buco.
-Pork osso buco
-Right.
with tomatillo salsa.
-Yes, sir.
-Mexican-Italian.
-Yes.
The first thing we're gonna make
is the roasted-tomatillo salsa.
Start off with some oil
in the pan.
Chopped onions, tomatillos,
poblano chilies,
salt, pepper.
[Sizzling]
We'll cook these
for about 20 minutes.
All the vegetables are cooked.
Add chicken stock.
It's a roasted-chicken stock,
and I use tomato paste
to kind of get like
a brown.
-I got you.
And then, just Bermix it.
[ Whining ]
Your tomatillo
salsa's done now.
Now, we're gonna start
our pork shanks.
First thing I'm gonna do
is season 'em --
lots of salt and pepper.
A little bit of oil the pan.
Throw a little vegetable on here
so these will roast
at the same time
as the pork rounds,
and then I place the pork.
♪
And we're gonna roast
these off in the oven
at what temp?
-Right about 560 degrees,
about seven or eight minutes.
-So, we're done being roasted?
-Yes, sir.
So, I'm gonna place them
into the pan.
Flip the veg through the pan.
-Homemade chicken stock?
-Yep.
Foil this back up, put it
back in the pizza oven?
Yes, sir, for three hours.
It's like Christmas morning.
So, we've got these yellow grits
spiked with chipotles.
Dude, my middle
name's chipotle grit.
Gorgeous.
-Put one of the shanks on there.
Got that tomatillo salsa
already hot, ready to roll.
Just a little garnish
of queso fresco,
just a little bit
of chopped cilantro,
and there we are.
That's the pork osso buco,
roasted-tomatillo salsa.
♪
Outrageous.
Nice acidity
in the tomatillo salsa.
Porks fall apart, tender.
Love the poblano note.
The grits play into it.
Good Mexican-Texan-
Southern combo
with a twist, elevated.
Real easy to explain.
-[Laughs]
-Chef, great energy, great food.
-Appreciate that.
-Nice job.
-Thank you very much.
Wow! At a ski resort.
♪
Pork osso buco.
It absolutely melts
in your mouth.
[chuckle]
It's really, really good.
And it's a cozy, wonderful
atmosphere in here.
FIERI:
Which fits right in
with the food.
I like the
mushroom stroganoff
if I'm really hungry
after a day of skiing.
A bunch of different mushrooms.
It's delicious.
Okay so, we're gonna be
making the spaetzle for the
vegetarian mushroom stroganoff.
-Love me some spaetzle.
We'll start off with the flour.
We'll sift it a bit.
Create a little hole there.
Toss in the eggs,
a little warmed milk,
little bit of water,
and a little salt.
I'm gonna start working it
with my hands.
Doesn't take
very long at all.
I've got a spaetzle
maker over here.
♪ Roll out
the spaetzle ♪
We're just gonna take it --
gravity will eventually
do it's job.
So, you just slide it
into the boiling water
back and forth.
The sliding action will actually
cut the dough as it goes in.
A lot of people refer
to spaetzle as pasta.
It's actually
more of a dumpling.
Now, it needs to cook in here
for just a couple minutes.
And we just put it
in an ice bath.
[ Sizzling ]
And then we sauté it
at the time of service, yep.
Got it.
Fire up the pan.
Little bit of oil,
then I go ahead and dump in my
sliced domestic mushrooms.
-So, the buttons?
-Yep.
The oysters.
This is the shiitakes.
-Okay.
-A little salt and pepper.
All right, and then
I just stir it.
This'll get cooked down
for about 25 minutes or so.
So, now we're gonna
assemble the dishes.
So, we're gonna get
a little oil in the pan,
a little bit of red onion.
-Got your garlic.
BIBLE: Mushrooms.
[Sizzling]
Little toss.
Let those cook
just a moment or two.
One of the keys to this
is the roasted-vegetable stock.
Add a little bit of sour cream
right off the bat,
sort of swirl that in.
That's where you kind of get
that classic stroganoff flavor.
Chive, salt, pepper.
And now, we're gonna go
for the reduction.
We're gonna be
plating the spaetzle.
Next is the mushroom,
[Sizzling]
with just a touch
more sour cream,
and then a little bit of chive.
There you go,
and that is the vegetarian
mushroom stroganoff.
Boom boom boom boom,
mushroom!
Little mix.
I can't say it's good.
I can say
it's great, though.
The type of mushrooms,
the way you cook 'em down
but leave them
with integrity --
I think that the mushrooms
are still tender enough.
You brought -- they brought
out tons of flavor.
I think that stock plays
a huge role in it.
It's hearty, it's comforting.
Outrageous. You're a gangster.
-Thank you, sir.
♪
Tastes like you're
in Germany somewhere,
and it's perfect when you
come right off the slopes.
I was gonna leave,
but between the slopes,
the snow,
and the dude that made
the awesome mushroom stroganoff,
I gotta stick around.
You got another dish?
I have a crispy
pork belly.
-All right, bring it.
-First thing I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna score the meat.
Next thing I'm gonna do
is smear molasses on it.
Black tar, Texas tea.
Next, I'm gonna season it.
-And just one side --
just the fat side?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-Just salt and pepper,
real liberal on this one.
You just throw it on the pan,
and we're gonna toss it
in the pizza oven
for about seven
or eight minutes.
Just put a little
roast on it,
a little bit
of crunch on it,
and now, we're gonna braise it.
-Right.
So, I start off
with maple syrup in the pan.
I'll just place this right
on top of that syrup.
Now, you take the
cinnamon-amon-amon-amon?
-Just throw it on top.
-And your water, Doctor.
Yep.
Three hours,
plastic or foil.
Plastic really
locks down,
and you actually
build steam in this.
If you poked it,
it would pssh!
Sheet of foil.
And then after this is
all covered and sealed up,
it'll go in the oven
right around 560 degrees or so
for about three hours.
After that,
we actually let it cool
in it's braising jus
overnight.
♪
-Then we'll cut it.
-And then they'll get skewered.
-And then what, fried?
-Fried.
So, this is the crispy
pork belly appetizer.
So, you start off with your
cooked beans and apple.
Look at that!
Okay, you think that's
enough pork belly?
You gave me half a pig.
And then the last thing
that we're gonna do --
it's my own interpretation of
a Carolina-style barbecue sauce.
And then, finish off
with a touch of green.
That is the crispy pork belly.
Listen, you say pork belly,
I say thank you.
Look at that pork
just falling apart.
♪
You get that molasses
right off the bat.
Carolina-style sauce.
Man, that vinegar
was right there.
You got sweet and heat,
on meat you can't beat.
[ Laughter ]
Crispy pork belly
and taco.
Have you ever seen a place
at the bottom of a ski run
that has food like this?
-No.
Yourself?
I rest my case, Your Honor.
♪
Up next...
a 90-year-old diner
in Kenosha, Wisconsin...
Out of my way,
that way.
...where the morning
Garbage Plate.
It's really good!
...is bringing in the masses.
Wow, there's a lot of people
in a little place.
♪
I'm here in Kenosha, Wisconsin,
about an hour north of Chicago
and just a few blocks
off of Lake Michigan,
at a place where
their breakfast special
is called the Garbage Plate.
All right, full plate,
three meats.
Someone's hungry today.
How much will you be
able to put down?
I'll try for half, but the
dogs will get the rest.
Have you ever seen
anybody eat a full one?
-No.
-BOTH: This is a half.
He had the full.
FIERI: They're goin'
for the garbage here,
and a ton of other
homemade favorites.
All I need is a sausage!
-Like nonstop omelettes,
-Cheddar.
fluffy scrambles
with a huge slab of ham,
and French toast made
from fresh baked bread.
At Franks Diner...
Wow, there's a lot of people
in a little place.
where they've been
packin' them in...
One piece of American
for my scram, please.
...just about forever.
-This is the best place in town.
-Everybody knows you.
-Out of my way, that way.
FIERI:
The diner's been here
since 1926,
when it was pulled to the site
by a team of horses.
Owner Anthony Franks's kids
have been telling
the story for years.
It was quite a big event
when it came into town.
The street was full
of people
waiting for this strange car
to come to Kenosha.
And over the decades, this place
has become a local landmark.
It's kind of
a family tradition.
My grandparents
used to hang out here,
my parents hang out here,
and now I hang out here.
Six years ago, when the
family decided to sell,
a couple of surprise buyers with
no experience in the food biz
decided to take a chance:
-Tomato, Lynnie.
Chris Schwartz
and Lynn Groleau.
And this, I think,
says "Franks?"
-It says "Franks."
-Why did you keep the name?
-That's part of history.
-That's it?
-Oh, yeah, bottom line.
-Did you come here
before you bought it?
-Oh, yeah. We were regulars.
And then you heard
it was for sale,
and you said?
-"All right.
We'll go look at it."
-GROLEAU: "Let's go look."
And, after
a couple bottles of wine
[Laughter]
and taking a look at the place.
GROLEAU: Couple bottles of wine.
-There you go.
-You believe that story?
-Yeah, that's nice to do
at 7:00 AM.
I like it.
If my dad were around,
he'd be so proud of them.
Schwartz's a master
on the grill.
Yes, yes. Looks like she's been
cooking for 40 years this way.
Woman or not, she's --
Hey, are you saying
I'm 40 years old?
No, I'm just saying you
were born at the grill.
You look like a seasoned line
cook of 30 years.
Putting out dozens
of homecooked orders at time.
Honey on one!
Like pancakes with
peanut butter
and jelly,
cinnamon-roll French toast,
a Reuben omelette with
Thousand Island dressing,
and the famous Garbage Plate.
You think you can
put that all down?
-Yeah.
A hunk of hash browns
with whatever's in the kitchen,
scrambled up with eggs.
So, Garbage Plate's
the number-1 heavy hitter.
Garbage Plate's
number-1 heavy hitter.
-Unquestionably, that's it?
-Make more of those
than anything in a day.
So, every Garbage Plate
starts the same way?
-Every day.
-Onions, the green
-Onions.
-bell peppers, the jalapeño.
-Yep, chorizo.
-Chorizo! That's interesting.
I mean, I'm in California,
and we have a lot of chorizo.
Is chorizo big up here in --
-I mean...
-I mean, in Kenosha?
Right by the water.
-It can be, it can be.
These are all
my Garbage Plates.
Of course, no one can
order them the same way,
so that's why
I have 18 of them
on the grill,
all different.
But we are here
to accommodate,
and to please.
Someone can really eat that
whole thing, or is that like
a family gets those?
Like a family of 10?
There's this one guy
way on the end.
-This is yours?
-That's mine.
-Two meat?
-Yes.
-Garbage Plate?
-Absolutely.
-Have you had this before?
-I have.
-Can you eat this whole thing?
-No.
You have already
subdivided yours.
This is true.
I'm working this way.
It has all the meat.
It's really good.
You know what?
It really is!
And usually,
I don't even like eggs.
I know, this is the most eggs
you've ever seen me eat.
I don't even wanna hear
anything about it.
-[Schwartz laughs]
-It's really good!
I mean, it's regular
breakfast stuff,
but there's something about it.
I think, the chorizo.
Hoo-whee!
Now, you don't have to go
for the garbage.
Lots of folks come here
for the omelettes
or the huge French toast.
This is all for you?!
I thought I'd share some
Oh, my goodness!
with a friend
in the back dining room.
Are you gonna share with me?
-No.
-No? That was no?
-[Laughter]
Can't blame her.
The French toast comes
from homemade bread.
You'd never expect this
from a breakfast joint.
We really wanted
to stay with the tradition
of old diner,
everything homemade,
everything made to order,
and homemade bread
is part of that.
They scratch-bake
everything here.
We hand me the bread.
I had the most arm power,
so I got stuck
doing it.
Lemme see those heaters.
Huh? Look!
[ Laughs ]
-Okay, we're not arm wrestling.
-All right.
Do you know how to braid?
He's got it.
No, I just wanted to redo it.
Make it pretty?
Yeah.
We're gonna serve this.
I don't want you to say,
"Oh hey, Marge, Lloyd,
hey, how ya' doing?
Yeah, Guy from the Food Network
made that jerky one."
[ Laughter ]
Now that -- that's good,
for a first try.
-Hmm?
-Hoh-hoh. I'm impressed.
FIERI:
And as long as we're
in the back room, baking,
get a load of this.
-These are the pasties.
Now, where did you learn
to make pasties?
This is a grandmother
and a mother thing, so.
Are pasties big here in
lower Wisconsin, upper Illinois?
-A little bit,
because a lot of people
have come
from upper Michigan, and
that's where these come from.
FIERI:
It's kind of a Midwest empanada.
Thin as you can
possibly get it.
Stuffed with beef
and all kinds of vegetables.
Put her in the dough,
make your little half-moon,
and you're done.
-That is really good.
I could eat
another six of those.
-It's awesome.
-I'm seeing the light.
-Mmm.
-[Laughs]
-Steak and tots.
-But as killer as the food is,
-Hi, Andy!
-the feel of the place
is as big an attraction.
"Order what you want,
eat what you get!"
I like that.
-You like that?
-Can I get a cup of coffee?
-Go get it yourself.
[ Laughter ]
Does that mean --
just because you like me,
or does everybody
get treated that way?
-Everybody does that.
-Seriously?
And if you're gonna
do your own refill,
you're gonna refill
the entire diner,
not just you.
-No.
-Uh, yeah.
You just pick it up and go?
You have to.
You don't have a choice.
Half a cup?
No, put it all
in there.
Any real rhyme
of who goes where?
Do you have like
sections, or...?
-It's organized chaos, yeah.
-Okay.
-Work okay?
-Want some more coffee?
-Yeah.
-Okay, go get it yourself.
[ Laughter ]
This is one of those places
where everybody knows your name.
FIERI:
And has for eight decades.
We do our best, since
it's 81 years old, okay?
Which makes Franks the oldest
continuously operating
lunch-cart diner in the U.S.,
Oh, yeah.
preserving a tradition:
great food and great times.
To have something like this
is kind of a treasure.
You work six days a week?
-Pretty much, yeah.
-Right like this?
-Right like this. I'm on this.
-Lot of people --
She does the back kitchen, I do
the front kitchen, six days.
I mean, is it
a little strange
that a lot of people
in Kenosha know your backside?
People wanna advertise
back there, though.
-Yeah, I'm telling ya'!
-Sell some space here.
I'm thinking about, lemme get
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Comin' up...
in Salem, Massachusetts...
Get funky with it!
...a seafood spot
tackling tasty turf...
That's totally legit.
...and a lobster with
a straight-up twist.
The whole reason
I rolled into this joint
was I heard about
this lobster martini.
♪
I'm about 30 minutes
north of Boston,
in the famous town
of Salem, Massachusetts.
You know, the witch trials
and everything?
Well, right now I'm in
the historic area
known as Artists' Row,
and what caught my ear
is I hear
there's a little joint
that's makin' a wicked
lobster martini.
This is the Lobster Shanty.
-Two Lobstertinis.
-Enjoy.
It's like a dirty martini,
but not as salty.
Lobster claws!
-I'm a little wary.
-[Laughs]
But I will try it.
Later, after the food.
-Lobster roll.
-The best I've had
in New England.
-Steamers!
-FIERI: Everything you'd expect
in a New England
seafood shack.
-Clam basket.
-And some things you wouldn't.
Margherita pizza.
Mac 'n' cheese!
Oh, so good.
-They're serving comfort food.
-Goin' in.
FIERI: Ever since Diane Wolf --
-Yeah.
-her friends call her Dee Dee --
-Oven's open!
bought the joint three
and a half years ago.
-Got it.
-How did you find the location?
We were actually
regulars here.
Dee Dee is actually
a trained chef.
You're getting really
wonderful recipes.
FIERI:
Like this non-New England
speciality.
-Pulled-pork sandwich!
-This is the bomb.
I mean, it's awesome.
Very nice
barbecue flavor.
Smoking chips?
What do we got?
Two parts hickory,
one part mesquite.
Soak these in coffee and beer.
-Really?!
And I'll let this sit
overnight
and let the wood chips
get nice and soft.
Take that liquid out, put the
wood chips in the smoker,
add some humidity
inside the smoker,
add the flavor,
-She doesn't stop!
keep the meat
from drying out.
So now, we're gonna
make some salt mix.
Coarse ground black pepper,
kosher salt, rosemary,
sage, and parsley
ground together.
Okay. And then, we're
gonna smoke some meat.
Boneless pork butt.
Start with making
some pork rub.
Steak seasoning, brown sugar.
-Some of your super-salt.
Red pepper flakes, cumin.
-Cumino. Cayenne.
Love the smoked
Hungarian paprika,
mild chili powder.
Get that lid on there,
and get funky with it!
[ Surf music plays ]
-Nice.
-Grab the spices out
with one hand,
-Mm-hmm.
-rub it on with the other hand,
so you don't put
the pork hand back in
to contaminate.
-Oh, yeah. Put 'em right into
the smoker, 13 hours.
Ah! Like we're
making a witch's brew.
We gotta be doing
barbecue sauce.
We absolutely are.
A little garlic oil,
our magical salt mix,
diced onions,
just a little bit of garlic.
That's my style.
[cackling]
[laughs] Brown sugar.
Now that that is caramelized.
Boatload of ketchup.
-Throw in.
-Molasses.
Worcestershire sauce,
rice-wine vinegar.
Interesting.
Orange juice,
pineapple juice.
Chopped tomatoes right now.
Chili-garlic paste.
Cayenne pepper,
smoked paprika, cinnamon,
red pepper flakes,
chili powder,
cumin,
-Cumino.
and the deadly
-Hang on.
-ghost chili pepper.
[sniff] Whoa!
-They're really hot.
-See my eyes?
In they go.
Ghost chilies.
Cook this for probably
about an hour.
Little immersion
blender into that.
-And make it smooth.
-Lemme taste the wicked brew.
Is it ready?
Mmm. Whoo!
Ooh, a little kiss
right there at the end!
Yeah, right.
Now, we're gonna take these
pork butts out of the smoker.
-Look at that!
You know it's done when you
can just grab a corner of it
like that and just
shred it off.
Mmm, wow!
Delicious, great rub.
-Pull it apart.
-Right.
We're gonna
sauce 'em in the bowl.
Get it on! [whistles]
-Stir that around.
Let's make that sandwich,
all right?
Lettuce and tomato.
There you go.
-[Whistles]
Mmm. Whoa!
That's totally legit.
The pulled pork is delicious.
Crazy smoke with the beer
and the coffee.
Tender, it's moist,
but what really makes it --
you've got a really nice,
sweet-heat barbecue sauce
going on that complements it
incredibly well.
Mmm. Seriously, great job!
-Rock on.
Pulled-pork sandwich.
Sweet, spicy, and salty.
-The best.
-Enjoy your meals.
-I love it here.
-You're in a little shack.
Big tourist area.
-Mm-hmm.
You could just be serving
corn beef sandwiches
and lobster chowder,
and be done with it.
Where's the love
in that?
You walk in, you get
really great food.
Everything is
freshly prepared.
-All righty.
-That's why people come here.
FIERI:
For everything from clam chowder
to fried mozzarella.
-To die for.
-Even beef.
When I'm at the
Lobster Shanty,
I do go
for the steak tips.
Okay, so what are we
gonna start on first?
I'm gonna trim the flap meat.
Now this is all trimmed off,
I'm gonna cube it up.
Big chunks like that?
Now, the marinade.
-Brown sugar and just a pinch.
-Some of your supersalt.
-Some Worcestershire sauce.
-"Some"?
A little soy sauce.
Okay, a lot of soy sauce.
Some coarse black pepper,
garlic cloves,
red pepper flakes.
-Whoa!
Guinness.
[Spritz]
Love that sound.
-Nice sound.
-Yes.
-I love that sound.
-It's the best sound.
-Boatload of stout beer.
-Yes, but wait, there's more.
-Okay.
-And then, molasses.
-What a wild concoction.
WOLF:
Pour the marinade
over the meat.
So, we let this go
for at least eight hours?
Grill's hot!
Throw it on the grill.
Look how it's started
to break down already
from the marinade --
nice!
We are ready.
Let's plate these up.
All right. Looks good.
Look at that.
Mmm!
Really tasty.
You get all the notes --
the soy at the beginning
and then the morasses,
tiny bit of heat.
The underlying theme
has to be that stout beer.
Don't just think that
we're a lobster shack.
We make steak, too.
Mmm!
Well done.
-Excellent.
Steak tips are delicious,
cut right apart.
-Enjoy.
-It's just good food.
It's not pretentious.
-Surf and turf!
-There's something for everyone.
We had the marinated flap meat
done in the stout beer.
Some real-deal barbecue.
But the whole reason
I rolled into this joint
was I heard about
this lobster martini.
I love martinis.
This is awesome.
Something I've
never had before.
Two Lobstertinis!
You're the one that
invented this, right?
Yeah. Instead of vermouth,
lobster essence,
and you put a claw on it.
-And they like it?
-Yeah, they like it.
It tastes like
the ocean -- lovely.
I wanted to get a drink
and enjoy lobster,
so you have to go with this.
-These are the lobsters.
We're gonna use the bodies
to make the stock --
the essence
for the Lobstertini.
Still a little
funkified by this,
to be very honest
with you.
I mean, I like -- I love
making lobster bisque.
Same start,
different finish.
Do you like dirty martinis?
-I like dirty martinis.
Then, I think this is
gonna be your segue.
-This is gonna do it?
-Like salty, briny,
delicious lobster flavor.
-Lobstery?
It's also a snack.
-All right.
-You're gonna love it.
And of course, we threw some
of our magical salt mix
in the water.
-Of course we did, 'cause we
don't do anything without
the magical salt mix.
-Nothing.
-Let those go for about
10 to 15 minutes?
-'Til they turn red.
Bring 'em out,
let 'em cool down.
crack 'em,
take the meat,
and begin the process
of making the broth
with the lobster shell.
-Yes.
Cold water,
we got the bodies
-Yep.
-and all their goodness.
Black peppercorns,
onion, carrot,
celery.
-A little mirepoix.
Fresh rosemary, fresh
-BOTH: dill.
And a little sage.
-And sage.
Simmer this
for five hours.
How are you gonna keep
the murkiness of it out?
Strain it once through
a regular chinois
-Strainer.
-then I'll run it again through
like a coffee filter to get
all that sediment out of it.
So, this is just
clear lobster broth.
Mm-hmm. Strain it
into a squeeze bottle.
And then, we're gonna
make the lobster martini.
Oh, we're not going to.
I'm gonna hand you off
to Sarah, my bar manager.
-Do you want me to make it?
-Oh, go for it. I mean --
-Are you ready? Vodka.
-Healthy pour.
Yulp.
-Yulp.
-[Laughs]
Lobster essence.
A little bit more than you
would do vermouth in a martini.
But it's not as strong.
Doesn't have
a taste like vermouth.
Then you just shake it.
Anybody feel like
I'm gonna be
having cold,
lobster-bisque cocktail?
Chilled martini glass.
Strain it, lobster claw,
the lemon twist --
there's your Lobstertini.
-Let me prepare myself.
Is there a way to do
this in particular?
Some people put
the lobster in the glass.
Some people just
eat the lobster
and they finish it
with a sip of the martini.
-Mm-hmm.
-Which is what I prefer to do.
When in Rome.
Mmm!
Great lobster flavor.
This is almost like the
ghost-of-lobster martini.
-Yeah.
-You don't get the lobster;
you just get the flavor.
-Exactly.
You just get
the hint of it.
I understand why you serve
the claw with it,
but you know what?
I think the people
that really like martinis
and like 'em dirty,
that's gotta -- it's
absolutely lobster martini.
It's fresh and it's got
some lemon in it.
It's good.
-I'd definitely have it again.
You never see it anywhere else.
-Enjoy.
It's a cool place
to come to.
-The lobster mac 'n' cheese.
-And the food is fabulous.
So, that's it from the
Lobster Shanty
in Salem, Massachusetts.
A lobster cocktail.
I've always told ya:
If it's funky, we'll find it.
See ya' next time, on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
What is that?!
[laughs]
What is that type
of ridiculousness?
Does this go on
all the time?
[ Laughter ]
That's awesome!
-[Electricity buzzing]