I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rollin' out
for a special edition
of "Triple D"
in Barcelona, Spain.
That's right. I've cruised
on over to Europe...
Ha!
...to get a sampling of Spain...
When in Barcelona...
...which means all kinds
of killer cuisine...
Elegant.
...from top-notch tapas...
Cho, cho, cho, cho,
and then [smooches]
...to some crazy
Catalan creations...
A little freaky at first,
but well worth trying.
...and on-point paella...
Mmm.
It's delicious.
...both traditional
and unexpected.
Wow! I've never
heard of that.
So hop on board...
Make you want to dance.
...this first-class flight
to Flavortown.
I don't like it.
I love it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D"
in Barcelona, Spain.
♪
So this area is known
as Barceloneta.
And that means
little Barcelona.
Now, believe it or not,
before 1992,
none of this was here.
I mean, there wasn't
even a beach.
It's a good thing
they built it out,
otherwise you wouldn't
get a chance to check out
this little rockin' tapas
and paella joint.
This is El Pacífico.
This restaurant is, uh,
one of my favorites.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Everything is good here.
It's really tasty.
But not much was
happening around here
before the 1992 Summer Games.
Fieri:
So this wasn't a real area?
You're right. It was an --
a fisherman neighborhood.
No beach, they brought
the sand here.
No hotels,
no big buildings...
No hotels?
So now it's very famous.
Yes.
But back in --
before '92...
Nobody knows.
That's crazy.
Now, tourists, transplants,
and locals
head down to the water
for Chef Ramiro Rodriguez's
Spanish dishes.
Paella, surf and turf?
Man: The Surf and Turf Paella
is one of the famous
and classics about
this restaurant.
What are we gonna make?
The base for our paella.
Here we go.
We put some oil...
Oil.
Garlic, onions, green pepper,
and red peppers.
A few minutes.
This is calamari.
Cuttlefish.
Cuttlefish?
Yes.
I think cuttlefish is more tasty
than calamari.
Okay. Great. Tomatoes?
Tomatoes, salt,
white pepper, paprika.
Paprika.
Smoked, red pepper paste.
Bay leaf.
And how long is
this going to cook?
40 minutes to an hour.
40 minutes to an hour,
okay.
Yes.
Okay. So we got fresh chicken
and rabbit.
I love rabbit.
This is local chicken.
Loco chicken?
Not loco chicken,
local.
Ah, close to here?
Yeah.
Yes. Yes,
it is close to here.
Is rabbit very popular
in Spanish cooking?
It is.
Super lean.
Salt and pepper.
Salt, pepper, oil.
Sear?
And to the oven.
Oh, in the oven.
We're gonna roast it?
Yeah.
Got it.
All right. So we have
our roasted chicken
and our roasted conejo.
Yes.
In the paella pan --
garlic, parsley, and oil.
Okay.
Our base.
So you've got the cuttlefish,
the peppers,
the onions,
the garlic, the spices.
Okay.
Yes.
And what type of rice?
Bomba rice.
Bomba rice, huh?
Yes. We use bomba rice.
Yeah. You know,
you know about this.
Bomba is from Valencia,
close to here.
A region that's close
to here? Okay.
Yeah. And the rice
is very good in Valencia.
Okay. A little of
the beautiful saffron.
Yes. And then...
Stock, chicken and rabbit?
Yes.
We continue
to let it cook here?
Yes, 10 minutes.
Look at these, huh?
Fresh as fresh can be.
We add the seafood.
The shrimp,
the mussels, the clams.
And it goes to the oven.
For another 7, 8 minutes?
Yeah.
Okay.
Paella is ready.
We finish with some
fresh parsley.
Wow. But look at that
bomba rice.
Look at that.
[ Chuckles ]
Can you see the steam
comin' off of that thing?
Mm.
The cuttlefish
is super tender,
I mean, melt-in-your-mouth
tender.
And the shrimp is local?
Yes.
Mmm. It's delicious.
The bomba rice
is perfect.
It's nice.
It's really firm rice,
a real bounty
with the rabbit,
the shrimp, the clams,
the mussels, the chicken.
Made with a lot of care,
not overseasoned,
but it's the creamy,
tender cuttlefish
at the bottom of it
and the depth
of the flavor of the sauce,
it's not just fish stock.
Oh, excellent.
Thank you.
Great paella,
it's all very tender.
And the rice is very moist,
not a dry bite. I love it.
I think it's nice to have
the meat and fish together.
It's absolutely delicious.
Fieri: And served up in
a pretty sweet setting.
It's beautiful.
People are playing volleyball,
the sports club
where all the boats are.
Fieri: Which means the crowds
will be here
no matter what they're servin'.
I thought seaside was,
like, sandwiches
and little poquito tapas.
Not here.
Elegant.
El Pacífico,
with the finger, huh?
With the finger?
Yes, El Pacífico.
[ Both laugh ]
Fieri: Yeah. Here,
they're not taking shortcuts
with their hearty menu.
[foreign]
Arroz negro paella.
Black rice,
it's a typical Spanish food.
My favorite kind of paella,
but it's, like, delicious.
Black rice
with squid ink?
Yes.
Okay.
So a little bit
of the olive oil
with the parsley
and the garlic,
some of the cuttlefish base
that we made with the peppers
and the onions and the garlic
and the tomatoes,
the bomba and black rice
is traditional?
Yes.
Now what?
Squid ink...
The shrimps.
So we add the fish stock.
Yes.
So we let this go
for 10 minutes?
And then the clams.
All right.
Black rice.
Do most people, Chef, when they
would first see this,
they would think
somebody burned it.
[ Chuckles ] Yes.
And what is that?
Aioli.
Yes.
It tastes so much
different.
Yes. The ink.
It's the ink you think?
What do you think?
[ Chuckles ]
It's takin' me to the brink.
Did I just blink?
It's crazy.
You think it's
the ink though, really?
The ink doesn't have
a lot of flavor.
Well, yes, it's so salty.
Maybe it is the salt level
that's --
that's coming up
a little bit on it.
Yes. Yes.
And what do I do with
the aioli?
They put this and mix it.
When in Barcelona...
I've never heard of that,
of taking paella
and stirring in the, uh --
the aioli.
Different.
Way different.
I mean, now the richness
and the creaminess level of it
go through the roof.
Wow!
You allow people that option,
they've got to do that.
Yes.
You're fanta--
This guy, huh?
Man: The first time, when
I looked, I did not like.
But really, when I eat,
I -- I like so much.
Woman:
The flavor is really tasty.
And the seafood
is really fresh.
Very nice place,
tastes real authentic.
It's amazing.
I love it.
This is awesome.
This is what I wanted.
Thank you.
The man, good job, Chef.
Fieri: Up next, we're diggin'
into real-deal home cooking...
Trust me, order
a second plate.
...where their Spanish
specialty...
[ Whistles,
clicks tongue ]
...isn't exactly
what I had in mind.
Once you get over the idea,
the flavor is fantastic.
♪
So I'm here in
the Sant Antoni neighborhood,
which, believe it or not,
is right across the street
from the famous --
and I mean famous,
Sant Antoni market.
You can get fruits
and vegetable,
stuff for the house,
you name it.
So after a long day of shopping,
you're thinking,
"Hmm, what would
I like to have?"
Oh, yeah, how about
a restaurant that serves up
traditional Catalan dishes?
This is Can Vilaró.
This is one of the typical
authentic places in Barcelona.
It's something you can't get
in the United States
so, uh, it's a really
great experience
to come here
and try the different food.
It's something that they have
been doing, like, forever.
Fieri: Or at least
since the '60s.
That's when
Siscu Vilaró's parents
first took over this joint.
Now he works alongside
his daughters,
Alba, Ida, and Anna,
who's running the kitchen.
Three daughters?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
So your grandfather
was a chef.
Now, is your father a chef?
Yes.
But now you take over?
Yes. Exactly.
Fieri: And she stayed true
to the old world,
Catalan cuisine that's native
to this part of Spain.
It's, uh, food that you need
a lot of time to make it.
So slow-cooking process.
-Yeah.
-Mm-hmm.
Food that your grandmother
used to do.
Cap i Pota.
It's the head of the cow.
And it's cooked with the leg.
It's a very traditional
dish here in Catalonia.
Fieri: Cap i Pota,
so a head and leg.
But we don't actually
put the leg in it.
So we're gonna chop up
some head. Awesome.
A country like Spain,
and you gotta think about
how many hundreds of years,
thousands of years...
You had a cow, you had
to use the whole thing.
Well, this is
the perfect example.
You get to the end of it.
You take the cabeza, the head,
slow cook it.
And there you go.
Okay.
The oil.
Onion, peppers...
Five minutes?
Sí.
Mas o menos.
Next?
And sofrito.
Sofrito of the peppers
and the onions?
Cabeza.
La cabeza.
A little paprika?
Sí. And garlic.
Garlic. Okay.
And that's all.
That's it? How long?
Treinta minutos.
30 minutes, okay.
Sí.
It's time to face-a
the cabeza.
Cap i Pota.
Hmm.
[ Whistles,
clicks tongue ]
Where's Andrew Zimmern
when you need him?
Mmm.
Once you get
over the idea,
the flavor is fantastic.
That fat has cooked down
to be nice
and creamy and tender.
I mean,
the sauce is spot-on.
You want to have a --
a cultural experience
that is a real Catalan dish,
this is it, right?
Sí.
A little freaky at first,
but well worth tryin'.
Guapa.
Gracias.
De nada.
It's a fulfilling dish,
very intense flavor.
I love it.
It tastes like heaven.
Were you raised
eating this?
Oh, yeah, of course.
It's hard to find places
like this one.
You can come to Barcelona
and get great food.
But to find the
Catalan style menu...
Nowadays,
it's not so common.
I think it would be really nice
to have more places like this
where you can find
the homemade meatballs.
They're amazing.
Feels like a comfort food.
Now we're gonna
make the meatballs?
Yes.
Pork and...
Cow.
Okay.
Bread with...
Taking the bread with
a little bit of the milk.
[ Whistles ] Oh, hang on,
hang on, hang on.
Look at the color of the eggs.
That's, like, orange.
Do you think about
what they're fed
to create that
beautiful color?
Beautiful.
Mix.
Okay.
In Spanish -- Mézclelo.
Mix -- Mézclelo.
I got the words.
Okay. So in the flour,
in the pan,
and then we fry 'em,
Little oil? Got it.
Okay.
And this is the salsa
for the meatballs?
Sí.
Okay. First...
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Vegetable broth.
Tomato sauce?
Onions.
Some fried onions.
Sí.
Media hora.
So half an hour?
Yeah.
[ Chuckles ] Half an hour.
Got that media hora.
And then the peas.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Mushrooms?
And then the fried meatballs?
Sí.
Nuts and garlic.
No.
Ah, see, I was trying
to help!
I was right in there
for you with the coverage.
Where is it going?
In here?
Yes.
Un poco.
A little bit.
And then let 'em
sit there and simmer
inside of that sauce.
10 minutes.
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
They're as good
as any meatballs you'll find
on the streets in --
in Italy.
The gravy is ridiculous.
I mean, the sauce,
you're just begging for some
bread to sop it up there.
Actually I want
all these meatballs
just on one
big hoagie roll.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Uh-huh.
Catalonia.
Catalan porron.
Fieri: This is actually
called a porron,
or a traditional
Spanish wine pitcher.
Okay.
I'll take this, too.
I'm gonna wear
some of this.
Oh!
Oh, there's
booze in that.
I didn't know there was
gonna be booze.
I thought it was
apple juice.
Fantastic.
-Do you like it?
-I don't like it. I love it.
Tender, lots of flavor,
juicy.
It's interesting 'cause
this Catalan style
doesn't have any
of the flavors
that are reminiscent of what
I think of Spanish food.
No real heavy spice,
fantastic.
Trust me, order
a second plate.
-Meatballs.
-They're super soft.
They melt in your mouth.
I love the flavor.
This is awesome.
All right. So have you guys
been to Barcelona before?
-No.
-No. This is our first time.
And how many kids
do you guys have?
-Four.
Say hi to 'em.
-Hey!
-Hi, Jackie, hi, Michael,
-Antoine and Anthony.
-Antoine, Anthony.
Nothing makes
their kids happier than,
A, their parents going
on vacation without them,
and, B, that they
get on TV.
So would you send
folks here?
Yes, sir.
Absolutely.
I would.
Want to try traditional
Catalonian food,
then this is the place
to visit for sure.
You see a big menu,
I mean, it's great.
This guy
and his daughters.
Fieri: Coming up...
[ Singing in Spanish ]
Fieri: We're headed
to what looks like
just your everyday bar...
Kind of a small kitchen for
the guy with a crazy flame.
But it's hiding atop
this treasure trove.
I'm not kiddin' you. It's
exactly what I was looking for.
Oh! Ah!
Oh! Ooh!
[ Laughs ]
She stole my bit!
[ Laughter ]
So I'm here in an area known
as L'Eixample Gràcia,
which is basically dead center
of Barcelona.
And I know you've heard me
say it a million times
on "Triple D,"
but when you're going through
an intersection like this,
slow down, take a look around,
or you might blow by
this nondescript bar
that just happens to be
hiding a righteous tapas place.
This is Bar Morryssom.
Just what you want
from a tapas place.
Codornices
a la vinagreta.
Woman: This is a good
neighborhood place.
It's been here for
I don't know how many years.
Fieri: We'll just ask owner
Pedro Sausor.
How long has he had
the restaurant here?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
45 years.
Really?
Sí.
He started when he was 20.
Fieri: As the chef
for a previous owner
who met his wife, Alba,
who worked here as well.
And together they took it
over back in the '70s.
And four decades later,
they run it with their sons
plus daughter-in-law,
Carolyn Bradford,
who just adds
to Pedro's family flavor.
Man:
The food is always delicious.
They make a really
wide range of dishes,
Fieri: Which completely
run the gamut.
From Mediterranean
seafood staples
to tapas like classic croquettes
to true Spanish specialties.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Quails with
el vinagreta.
We're in this little bar,
we're gonna have some quails.
Sí. Sí.
Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughs ]
Woman: Really tender,
fall off the bone.
They really just do it
exactly the right way.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Before we start to do
the codorniz,
we have to make
the egg dance.
See, I don't know what
that means. But, you ready?
[ Singing in Spanish ]
I have been cooking
all my life.
I know every dumb kitchen
trick that there is.
That one right there takes
the cake. That was awesome.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Let's start.
I got to have a trick now.
Okay.
The onions.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
In inglés, it's "bay leaf."
I listen to him talk, I mean,
I don't even need a translator.
I just listen to him talk.
Okay. What is this?
The broom that you
sweep the floor?
Es escoba.
[ Laughter ]
-What is it?
-Thyme.
Thyme?
That's some funky thyme.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Pepper.
Cloves?
Now we'll take the quails.
Now we have to kill
any germs with...
And these just came
from the market today.
Sí.
Kinda a small kitchen for
the guy with a crazy flame.
Now we put the quails in.
Peep, peep, peep,
peep.
peep?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
It flew into the pot?
-Yeah.
-I'm gettin' it.
Give me a little
more time here.
[ Laughter ]
It's a little salt,
a little pepper,
a little white wine,
and a little red vinegar.
This was a granny's recipe.
It's, like, 100 years
old he said.
I love it.
Years ago they'd make it
and they'd store it
for two months
and it'd be fine.
Because of all that vinegar --
just preserves it.
Do I have to wait two months,
or are we going to eat it today?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
All right!
Just beautiful.
Fresh quail, never frozen.
♪
Buena.
Make you want to dance.
[ Laughs ]
I mean, this is,
again, a simple dish,
but lights out delicious.
When you take the bite
with the quail
and a little bit
of those onions,
the vinegar and the wine
and pepper,
and just getting into it.
Fresh...
Fresca.
Quality...
Qualidad.
And corazón...
Corazón.
...makes a fantastic dish.
Quail a la vinagreta.
This is fantastic.
I couldn't stop eating it.
Really juicy, tasty,
very rich, beautiful.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
How many different menu
items does he have?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
70.
Where's
the other kitchen?
Crazy.
Fieri: And there's
one more thing about this menu
that makes this place
a real hidden gem.
But it's also not
very expensive.
This kind of food, and they
charge double price in
the rest of the city.
So here's the deal --
I am traveling through
Barcelona
checkin' out
the greatest joints.
What I just experienced
was dynamite.
I can only imagine
what's comin' up next.
See you in a little bit.
♪
So welcome back.
"Triple D" in Barcelona, Spain.
It doesn't get
any better than that.
This is Pedro.
And this is Bar Morryssom.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
I love eating Pedro's food.
It's very authentic,
very fresh, very tasty.
Now, you walk up
to this place,
you're gonna go,
"Ah, it's just a little bar,
you get a couple cocktails,
maybe get a ham sandwich."
Not with this dude
in charge!
Fieri: No. He's rockin'
a huge menu of legit tapas.
It's typical tapas
that you have in the area
but just fantastically made.
You can share. When you find one
you really particularly like...
Bradford:
Chickpeas with prawns.
I absolutely adore
the prawns and chickpeas here.
It's a really good, fresh,
combination of, uh,
ingredients that they have
here at Morryssom.
All right, Chef.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Olive oil?
Okay.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
This is called sofrito,
Sofrito. Olé!
Olé!
[ Laughter ]
Garlic.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Cho, cho, cho, cho, cho, cho.
Okay.
Red peppers,
green peppers.
Put the prawns in.
Did he put them
on the parsley?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
It gives a bit of
the flavor and a smell.
But that's the eye
of a chef.
Now we'll put some salt in.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Put in the brandy.
Okay. Listo?
Hey!
If it wasn't hot enough
in this kitchen,
it got a little bit warmer.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
We put in the chick peas.
From a can or dry?
He picks them himself.
All the difference
in the world.
You can infuse flavor
into it while it cooks.
Oh. That just
by itself...
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Cho, cho, cho, cho.
And then...
Sí?
[ Laughs ]
Ha!
So simple, all the flavor
comin' out of those
peppers and onions.
Mm.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Good wine, good food,
and then sleep.
We like the same things.
♪
When I think of tapas,
this is exactly
how I think of it.
The chickpeas are so tender
and take on the flavor
so well.
But when you put fresh shrimp,
organic vegetables,
and treat it all
with respect,
I mean, it's a very simple dish,
but it is fantastic.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
You have to do it -- you have
to make it with a lot of love.
He treats it like
he's feeding his family.
So just so you know,
I'm part of the family.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Laughter ]
Dynamite.
Chickpeas with prawns.
Prawn's absolutely perfect,
you know, succulent, tasty.
Simple ingredients,
cooked correctly
makes big flavor.
Sí.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
The food in this place is always
consistently excellent.
And that's why the place is busy
all day long every day.
You come to Barcelona,
you want to get tapas,
you got to come here.
I'm not kiddin' you.
It's exactly what
I was looking for.
Fantastic.
You'll love this guy.
That's it for this trip.
But don't you worry,
there's funky joints
all over this world.
And I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
-Right?
-It's clear.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Did you just take over
my show
and look into the camera
and start talking?
I love it.
[ Laughter ]
I like the way he rolls.