Hey there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives.
-This trip...
-Wow.
We're throwing it
into overdrive...
This dude does not stop.
Cooking it up with
some killer kitchen equipment.
That is awesome.
In San Francisco...
Holy breakdown shoulder.
An all-out barbecue joint...
We're gonna have to go
anaconda on my jaw.
Going to town with
some rare city smokers.
These are grandfathered in?
Yes, they are.
FIERI: In Maui...
What a great set-up.
A tricked out pizza trailer...
Buddy, you just
don't make sense.
Putting out pie
from their oven on wheels.
You can't get pizza that good
in most restaurants.
And in Stockton, California...
Night-night.
A blow-your-mind
ravioli machine...
Ravioli train is coming
along to Flavortown.
Chugging along for
over a century.
I've seen really cool kitchen
equipment in my day.
This might be the coolest.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
So I'm here at Stockton,
California,
a city that was founded
back in 1849,
so a ton of history.
And you find a place this old,
you know what you're gonna get?
Probably an old-school
Italian deli somewhere.
And that's exactly
what we have here.
These folks
for three generations
have been scratch-making
the Italian sausage
and making over
4,000 raviolis a week.
This is Gian's Deli.
Pesto pasta.
-Everybody knows about Gian's.
-It is truly
that Italian experience
transplanted here in Stockton.
FIERI: Conjured up
by Gian Bolognini's
cousins generations ago,
and in 1968, 18-year-old Gian
arrived and joined the team.
MAN: Gian came from
a little village
up in the foothills
above Lucca called Corfino.
FIERI: He took over
the biz in '72.
Then in 2008, son Jeff
and his family took the helm
and have stuck
to what's tried and true.
Where did that come from?
Hundred-year-old machine.
Came from another restaurant
that was in business
for about 80 years.
That is awesome.
FIERI: Still cranking out
raviolis by the table load.
How many raviolis
you guys make a week?
About 300 pounds.
A lot of raviolis.
Everybody loves the raviolis.
Can't order enough of 'em.
What type of
raviolis you make?
Beef, cheese, spinach,
Swiss chard combination.
All that together?
Yes, sir.
They are excellent.
All right, brother.
Where we at?
Ravioli filling.
Swiss chard, spinach, onions,
celery, parsley pureed
with spices, eggs.
Gotta have a little binder.
Beef.
Freshly ground Parmesan cheese,
bread crumbs, salt and pepper.
Two to three minutes.
And what happens to it
after this?
We let it sit overnight,
get it to draw
some of that moisture out.
FIERI: And while that rests,
it's go time for dough time,
and lots of it.
Basketball-sized dough balls
are floured and sent
through a sheeter ten times
to get the right thickness.
Then it's laid out
on a pasta table
big enough to make
2,700 raviolis.
Now that we've made
the ravioli filling...
So you just keep scooping it,
keep filling it, smearing it.
Yup.
I get my Zen moment going.
I just come in here
for some therapy.
Now we take down the guard rails
just like that.
Take the top piece.
Okay.
Gently.
This is a two person job.
Absolutely.
It's like making
a big ravioli bed.
Night night.
See you in the morning.
Etched it down just
to seal the ends.
Okay.
And we're gonna pull that off.
Is this gonna come off
the rails and drive down
like a little
ravioli train?
Yes, it is.
Oh, I love it.
Ravioli train is coming
to Flavortown.
Whoo whoo!
Wow.
That's nuts.
I have seen really cool
kitchen equipment in my day.
This might be the coolest.
It's like a mattress
in Flavortown.
Now we cut 'em nine across.
Now what are we into?
Pasta sauce.
Okay.
Olive oil, onions.
So this is a generic,
almost a bolognese sauce.
Yeah.
You take some beef.
We're gonna get all that
nice and brown.
Celery, parsley, carrots.
And these are all recipes
that your dad had.
Or that my grandmother used
and his family used.
And after about 30 minutes
of cooking,
we're gonna add
some tomato paste,
tomato puree,
our browned onions,
beef, and celery concoction,
salt, pepper,
red chili flakes,
some white wine,
chopped up
porcini mushrooms.
Dried porcinis rehydrated.
Water that we used
in the porcinis.
The steeping liquid,
got it.
We're gonna let that simmer
for eight hours.
And so that's gonna
be used on the ravioli,
this is the go-to.
Spaghetti.
That's it right there.
Got it.
Now we got those raviolis
that we made,
two, three minutes.
Float to the top,
they're done.
Now we're gonna add some of
our homemade meat sauce,
give it a good stir.
They soak up
a little bit of sauce.
Freshly grated Parmesan.
And another little stir.
That's what
I'm talking about.
Garnish with a little
extra Parmesan.
Welcome to food coma.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was somewhere else.
So it takes me back
to my childhood.
Tender, nice little texture
to the pasta itself.
A good balance of
the Swiss chard to the meat.
And I love the meat sauce.
It's very simple.
Just little pillows
of perfection.
I literally could eat
about three plates of these.
-Ravioli up.
-Can't beat it.
MAN: The spinach filling
is the perfect bite.
Great flavor.
WOMAN: You can get
the frozen raviolis
and the frozen meat sauce
to take home.
You have a ravioli train.
That is so unfair.
I want a ravioli train.
Or how about
their meat cannon?
It's like the artillery center
in Flavortown.
Oh, yes to that.
And we're firing
this baby up next.
FIERI: Gian's deli
at Stockton, California,
is about as real deal
as it gets.
Old school Italian.
Still got all the big blocks
of cheese
and all the big salumi hair
and they're slicing it to order.
I've often come here
when I need something
last minute
for an Italian dinner.
You know,
whatever you want for lunch,
they'll make it for you.
Sausage pepper sandwich.
WOMAN: The sausage is homemade
and it's
absolutely delicious.
FIERI: Okay, now we're
into making sausage.
Pork butt, pepper,
salt, sugar,
curing salt, allspice.
A lot of it.
Nutmeg, garlic powder,
and a little white wine.
Mix this all up until we get
a nice little bowling ball size
to put in the hopper.
Hopper non-stopper.
Look at the size --
Luke, I am your
Italian sausage.
Think we're ready
to go here.
Oh, it doesn't have
it's own cool little hinge.
It's like the artillery center
in Flavortown.
Hook up the hog casings.
If I had this in the back
of a covered wagon,
I'd be called Josey Wales.
[ Imitating machine gun ]
All right.
We're ready to spin it.
We're a good team here.
All right.
So now we're gonna take it,
tie it off with string.
Poke 'em.
Let a little bit
of the air out.
Let these hang for about two,
three days in the walk-in.
Build all that flavor.
Now we're gonna slice it up.
A browned homemade
Italian sausage
with the homemade focaccia bread
with some teleme cheese.
We'll finish it off
in the oven.
All right.
And fire roasted red bell
pepper, spicy mustard.
Mustard.
Nicely done.
Baked the focaccia yourself?
Every day.
It's really dynamite.
I love the texture of it.
The way that you guys get
your grind done for your pork
is right on.
It does a lot of allspice.
It almost has like a little
Swiss-Italian type
of a flavor to it.
And to think that that sausage
recipe still continues on.
It's good, man.
It is a solid sandwich
every time.
It's got spice
but it's not hot.
From the fresh bread
to the mustard, the sausage,
the red pepper.
I mean, how can you go wrong?
Nothing compares to this.
My dad was a big believer
in treating people right,
serving them
good quality food homemade.
It's a really neat thing
to see how much pride
and how much energy
and how much enthusiasm
that you're carrying on.
You ought to be proud.
Thank you.
Coming up, a southern joint
in San Francisco...
This is kinda barbecue
plus plus.
Where the biscuits
are behemoth...
If you can eat the whole thing
in a day, you win a car?
And the lamb, well, it's...
Lights out.
Awesome.
Excellent job.
I'm here at San Francisco.
I love this city.
I mean, you're talking tons
of history,
awesome sports teams,
and you wanna talk about
big restaurants, right here.
But I gotta be honest,
not too many barbecue joints.
Well, I mean,
you got Gorilla Barbecue,
or you could find yourself
over here
on Folsom in the SoMa district
just a few blocks
up at union square
right here at CatHead's BBQ.
South Carolina chicken.
A block away your mouth
just starts watering.
We have the,
uh, brisket chili.
It reminds me of going
to barbecue joints
back in the South.
It's like fine dining cooking
but with a regular,
down-home experience.
FIERI: 'Cause owners Pam Schafer
and Richard Park
are just a couple
of down-home transplants...
I'm from Tennessee.
She's from Michigan.
Cooking up some
family fixings.
We just bring it
from all around the country,
recipes we grew up with.
Pulled pork on a cat head.
Why is it called cat head?
Cat head is a biscuit
in the South the size
of a cat's head.
If you wanna order it,
you definitely
wanna bring
an appetite with you.
Give me the rundown.
All right.
So we're gonna take
some AP flour.
Okay.
We're gonna put it in a bowl.
Do you put most
of it in the bowl
or do we just get
some of it on us?
We get most of it on us
and then some of it in the bowl.
Okay. There you go.
So we're gonna put some
baking powder and some salt.
We're gonna add the butter
and the Crisco.
Okay.
So you just kinda
get it into pea-size shapes.
There we go.
Making the gravel.
And then we'll add
the buttermilk.
So we're just gonna mix
it around.
So you're just gonPu it out.
Push it out.
So that's the --
that's the ring mold.
What, if you can eat the whole
thing in a day, you win a car?
Look at the size of that!
Pretty much.
So we're going 355
for about 30 minutes.
All right. Next up.
Dry rub.
Brown sugar,
Peruvian paprika.
It's the one I always use.
Garlic powder.
Okay.
Black pepper, cayenne,
chili powder.
A ton of cumin.
Some, uh, onion powder,
salt, allspice,
poultry seasoning, cinnamon,
and, uh, nutmeg.
It's like the United Nations
of seasonings going on.
So what we're going to do now
is we're just gonna
take our, uh, pork butt.
Okay.
Give it a nice
little rub over.
Put a little whiskey on it.
Whiskey bottle.
Take me home.
So this sits in our, uh, fridge
for a couple of days.
How long are we
gonna smoke that?
About 14 hours.
Now we're making our
North Carolina finishing sauce.
You know how North Carolinians
are about their barbecue?
I am all down on
the vinegar side of it.
Well, this one's
a little mixed.
So we're gonna add some ketchup,
some cider vinegar, brown sugar.
Okay.
Some, uh, salt,
black pepper.
You can hear that thing gurgling
in there right now.
Chili flake,
some Worcestershire.
Hot sauce.
Whisk it up,
bring it to a boil.
And, uh, it's done.
Oh, and that's gonna
go with that pulled pork
on that cat head?
Yup.
[ Whistles ]
This has been going
for about 14 hours.
Nicely done.
Give it a little salt.
And this is the finishing sauce
that we made earlier.
We're gonna take
the cat head biscuit.
This is mustard slaw.
Okay.
Put a little
of these pickles on there.
And there you go.
We're gonna have to go
anaconda on my jaw.
Mm.
The pork's got great flavor
to it, nice, tangy vinegar.
Slaw's great.
Carolina sauce is dyno.
And that's a nice big biscuit.
Oh, boy.
You know, we just don't get
enough of this in California.
Well done.
Really good.
Cat head biscuit.
It's a knife and fork
kind of meal.
It's just perfect.
It's delicious.
It's spicy.
It's a little smoky.
FIERI: Folks come in.
It smells like barbecue
right off the bat.
You have these beautiful pits.
These are grandfathered in?
Yes, they are.
We're one of two restaurants
in the city that has them.
e most of it,
These are grandfathered in?
Yes, they are.
smoking up all
the usual suspects...
St. Louis cut ribs.
And even mixed in
a little wild card.
Smoked lamb.
You don't really think of lamb
as, like, a barbecue item.
But this stuff's perfect.
FIERI: Let's get into it.
I'm gonna make a spice rub.
Dry mustard,
cumin, allspice,
chili flake,
cinna-manum-manum-mum-mum.
FIERI: Hey, wait.
That's my line!
Nutmeg, brown sugar,
a lot of salt, paprika,
black pepper and oregano.
And this is just for the lamb.
This is just for the lamb.
We don't do this
for anything else.
Now it's bone-in
lamb shoulder.
Uh, let this also go 48 hours?
Yeah.
We marinate everything
at least 48 hours.
Then how long is this gonna
go in the smoker?
This goes for
about eight to ten hours,
low and slow.
All right.
So what we're gonna do now,
we're making an apple slaw.
Take some red cabbage, some,
uh, Granny Smith apples.
We're gonna just grate those.
We're gonna degrade them?
You're a dumb apple.
We're gonna grate them.
You're so not liked.
Then we're gonna take
just a bulb of fennel.
Okay.
Ah, it's good looking.
I can smell that fennel
right now.
All right. Let's take
some of this dressing.
And that's...
Mayonnaise, cider vinegar,
lemons, sugar, salt,
black pepper,
and allspice.
Got it.
All right, so...
Holy breakdown shoulder.
So we're gonna shred this up,
put this on the plate
with a little bit
of the apple slaw.
So we like to just, uh,
finish her with
just a little bit of salt
and, uh, fennel ketchup
that we made.
And there you go.
Mm. The lamb meat is very lean,
but tons of flavor.
And then the fennel
apple slaw,
super refreshing,
palate cleansing.
The contrast of the cold
with the hot,
the acid of the ketchup,
the sweetness with the richness
and the saltiness of the lamb.
This is kinda barbecue
plus plus.
Ah. I think for anybody
that walks in here and says,
"Ah, I don't like lamb,"
well, then, you gotta try this.
Light's out.
Awesome.
Excellent job.
WOMAN: It's not really
what you would expect
when you think of lamb.
It's tender, juicy.
The apple fennel slaw
is perfection.
This is the place to come
if you love barbecue.
FIERI: I love the smokers.
I love the smell.
Just an awesome,
awesome place.
Up next, we're headed
to the beach in Maui.
Too legit to quit.
To chow down on some
wood-fired pizza...
That is a gorgeous
looking pie, dude.
While soaking up the scenery.
This is my kind of gig.
Now I'm over here in Maui.
Hit it, kid.
To check out a trailer
that the guy made himself
and he's also scratch
making the dough by hand!
This is Outrigger Pizza.
By far the best pizza on Maui.
Pizza in a parking lot.
Who knew it would
taste this good.
MAN: I'dat
watch himit would
throw the pizza.
FIERI: A classic pie move
Philly native Kevin Locke
picked up in college
then perfected
when he hit the road
with this cart in 2009.
I love the rig, man.
Who built the pizza oven?
I did.
Did you really?
Yeah.
What temperature you running?
Seven?
700.
Yeah. What kind of
wood are you using?
Kiawe wood, which is
this tree right here.
So the local native hardwood.
Yup.
It brings out that smokiness
in the dough.
More of a flatbread style.
And a lilikoi pork.
The Lilikoi pizza
tastes like Maui.
MAN: It's got that nice
pulled pork.
It has a nice
little lilikoi glaze.
Lilikoi?
What is lilikoi?
Lilikoi is a passion fruit.
Okay.
First we're gonna make
pizza dough.
Yup.
Hang on a second.
Where's the mixer?
No mixers.
All by hand.
Seriously?
Yeah.
I add my yeast to the water.
Okay.
And my sugar.
Fantastic.
Five pounds...
I don't want you
to take any offenses,
but I'm gonna stand on this side
when you pour the flour.
That's the side
where the wind's gonna go.
Okay.
Fantastic.
I'll be right over here.
Unbleached flour,
bleached flour, semolina.
And now we're gonna take out
four pounds
to add that to
our second phase of the dough.
There you go.
water.
So what'd you do today?
I watched a guy make dough
for his pizza cart
at the park by the water
with some weird contraption.
Danish whisk.
You Danish?
No.
So we're gonna add our activated
yeast and water.
Okay.
Now we'll wait two hours
for this to poof.
Oh. [ Laughs ]
To do what?
Rise.
Good.
Now that we've let
the dough rise,
we're gonna reintroduce
our four pounds of flour.
Hawaiian sea salt.
All right.
So that's together.
Two hours later,
we're gonna knead the dough.
And into our plastic bag
and then refrigeration.
Let it rest for two days.
How many ounces
did you weight this out to?
Four ounces.
Dough is resting.
Now we're going to dry rub
the pork butt.
Coarse black pepper, cumin,
chili powder, garlic,
onion powder, parsley,
and quite a bit of salt.
We're gonna mix this up.
Generously rub this
on the pork?
Yup.
This is awesome.
Okay.
A cup of water.
So a little bit
of braising liquid.
Pop it in the oven.
And how long's it gonna go?
Three and a half hours
at 350.
Pull it out, let it cool,
give it a little shred?
Yup.
Pork's done.
Dough's done.
So put a little bit of flour
on our dough ball.
Then we're gonna press it out
without touching the edges.
So you can build
a little crust.
Boy, that's some loose dough.
Look at that.
Little centrifugal force.
Little semolina
for some ball bearings.
And then we're gonna do
our garlic aioli base,
little bit of garlic,
the pork,
Maui sweet onions,
sweet bell peppers,
mozzarella cheese,
little bit of Romano.
Boy, that oven's hot, buddy.
They only take
about 90 seconds to cook.
What a great setup.
That is a gorgeous
looking pie, dude.
Do some, uh,
fresh Parmesan.
And here's our specialty,
the lilikoi.
Beautiful pizza.
It's dynamite.
The crust is
too legit to quit.
Not too much cheese.
Nothing's overdone.
When you do get the little bite
of pork, you love it.
When you get a little bit
of the pepper,
you're down with it.
Really dynamite pizza.
-A lilikoi pork.
-Sweet, savory.
Dough is crisp, a little
charred on the underside
the way I like it.
MAN: Real tender
piece of pork.
It's got a little bit
of fattiness to it,
which is really good.
And it goes really well
with the lilikoi.
This is my favorite kind
of pizza restaurant,
is sitting out here,
checking out the water.
Italian sausage.
My favorite pizza?
The sausage pizza.
MAN: His homemade pizza sauce,
I haven't tasted
anything like it anywhere else
on the island.
All right, what are we
gonna make next?
Italian sausage.
You guys are making almost
everything from scratch.
Yes. We're gonna make
some red sauce.
Go ahead.
I'm standing over here
because I'm in light blue.
You might get red.
And I can already tell you
that that tomato sauce
is gonna make a mess.
Ground tomatoes,
granulated garlic,
one teaspoon of basil,
one teaspoon of thyme,
oregano,
black pepper, salt,
teaspoon of cinnamon, nutmeg.
And then we're gonna
mix it here.
We made dough by hand
and now you're gonna use
an electric mixer?
Buddy, you just
don't make sense.
One cup of olive oil.
Give it a little bit
of flavor.
And the sauce,
ground sausage,
Maui sweet onions,
mushrooms,
and some green peppers.
Mozzarella,
top with Romano.
Back into the oven.
90 seconds.
This is my kind of gig.
To be outside like this?
The life.
What do you do
during the holidays?
I sell Christmas trees.
This dude does not stop.
There you go.
Fresh Parmesan again.
Little bit of truffle salt.
Hear the crunch?
Mm.
Look how thin that is.
Nice crust, a little char.
What I like is that
you're not heavy-handed
with your ingredients.
It's not supposed to be
the gooey cheese
stretching off
into the sunset.
It's supposed to be a balance
between all the flavors.
You can taste everything.
I'm impressed.
I wanna buy
a Christmas tree now.
Italian sausage.
Italian sausage
is really good.
The peppers on it gives it
that extra little kick.
It really pops with flavor.
It's an incredible experience.
It really is.
We're very lucky.
You can't get pizza that good
at most restaurants.
And I'm doing it
right here on a trailer.
Well done.
Thank you.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on Triple D.
Think we're ready
to go here?
I got him.
Cover my back.
[ Imitating machine gun ]
[ Laughter ]